Hey, guys, welcome back.
In this lesson, we'll start setting up our environment for a local deployment of our own when we see
a local deployment, this could easily be your personal machine.
So in my situation, I'll be deploying it on my personal machine.
But it could also be on a company machine or a server somewhere that this API needs to serve, you know,
across the network.
And they could potentially even be to the Internet, whatever the situation, teaching you or showing
you critical steps towards prepping this machine so that it can host your API.
So our journey starts off here where we have to download the dot net five runtime already of the SDK,
which we've been using for development.
But we want to make sure we have the wrong time and we can just get that hosting bundle for windows.
So when you do that, you launch your installer and then you go ahead and install it, go through security
checkpoints.
And once that is done, you can close that and then, you know, we're going to move on to something
else, our Internet information services.
So what we want to do is add so you can just go to your start menu and see add feature and then you
want to click turn Windows features on or off.
So once that is selected, this little box will pop up and you want to make sure that you select Internet
information services.
Once you do that, you're going to get that square.
That square means that, you know, it's not everything that is ticked, which is fine.
You don't need every single feature.
But I'm going to show you the ones that I have currently installed and then you can just go through
and make sure that those are also on your side.
So I have the management console and then I have these libraries for application development feature.
So you can make sure that you take these off.
Maybe you don't need all of them, but it works for me with these.
So I would recommend that you make sure you have those.
And then for features, you can go ahead and take those.
Health and diagnostics, once that section is actually optional, but I recommend that you get the logging
section and then performance features basic authentication and others.
So once you have those, you can click, OK, and then it may take a while to install.
I already have them, so I don't need to wait for them to install.
But once they finish installing, then you can resume this video.
So once you're sure that you have is or that process is finished to make sure you have so you can just
go to your start menu and type in I guess, and then you'll see it pop up.
And then when you launch, you get this console showing you your server and all of the sites that you
have currently listed under there.
Right.
To make sure that it's working.
You can actually just click on default website and go to browse and then it will show you this page,
which shows you that you're now seeing your server.
Now, another essential part of setting up your local environment will be to make sure that your database
server is installed and running.
So when we talk about the database server, we have a few options.
In an enterprise setting.
You probably already have it or you should have it.
You can check with your system administrator whatever you need to do, but you just go ahead and make
sure you have a server on a personal level.
If you don't already have it, you have two options.
You have either developer or express.
So Express is very free, no licensing required at all.
And but then it has some limitations on a personal level versus fine developer gives you far more features
and it's actually a full poleward.
So it's a much bigger download and a much bigger test to have it installed gives the system many more
features for this deployment.
You probably can get away with Express, but then maybe if you're thinking about longevity, you probably
just want to get developers so you have everything you need so you can go ahead and download that.
Insolation is pretty straightforward and at the end of it you be prompted to install the management
studio.
And just in case you missed that step, you can always just Google SSME, which is short for Server
Management Studio, and once you go through that, you can always just download a management studio
through this medium also, which is also a straightforward installation.
So to launch the management studio after it's installed and to connect to your database server, you
can go ahead and click the icon and you'll see this splash launching screen and to connect to the server
you love to put in the server name.
So I have two servers running on, a few servers running on my machine.
Right now I have a skua express, so I do have an instance of Escalon Express, but I also have an instance
of the developer.
So to get to Scale Express you can see a dot backslash Eskil Express that that really means localhost
also.
Right.
And then if you went to a developer, then you just need localhost so you wouldn't need any special
anything else.
So I'm going to use developer.
So if I say localhost and it will connect and I think of a few databases, not too many.
So we can proceed now before we move to the next step, I just want to encourage you make sure that
you have admin access or even if you don't have administrative access, if you're in an enterprise setting
where you're not in a position to be the administrator, that you at least have enough access are you
are working with somebody who has the access to carry out some of the actions here.
So a lot of the problems that people encounter when doing these kind of deployments outside of probably
missing out the library and not installing something, the next biggest issue is usually permissions
and other authorizations.
Right.
So just make sure that you're working with somebody.
If if that is the case, who has enough permissions to go around any potential roadblocks.
And if you're on your personal machine just or a machine that is yours to manage, just make sure that
you have administrative rights.