Hey, guys, in this video will be creating or Microsoft as your accounts, like I said earlier, we
can get started for free to get to this website.
We go to Azor Dot Microsoft dot com.
And then I guess the road to according to your reason or your language.
But this is what the website looks or should look like.
And you can read through it to see exactly what Asgeir is all about.
It's about being futuristic, allowing more collaboration and operating more seamlessly in a cloud space
where there are all over the world and you usually would just choose the region that is closest to you.
So I'm actually in the Caribbean region, so my closest region is east to us or east us too.
But that's not for this video.
This video.
We're just creating the O'Collins.
We're not setting up anything about regions just yet.
So to get started, we can just well, if you have a live account already, then you can just go ahead
and send in with that live account where you can just click start free.
And here they tell you that you can create a free going to be and you can get started with 12 months
of free services.
So that's a good deal to me.
And if you scroll down, you'll see 12 months of free, popular free services, plus two hundred dollars
credits, which will expire in 30 days.
So they give it 200 dollars so you can create V virtual machines, you can create resources in the cloud
and experiment until that money is up.
And that's really just for one month.
But then there are certain services that you just get for free for the rest of the year and then you
have a few other services that are always free.
So what we're going to do is just go ahead and click, start free.
And then they'll ask us to sign in with our live accounts.
If you have a live account once again, you can go ahead and use that.
If you don't have an account, then you can go ahead and create one.
And this is a very recent option to sign in with GitHub.
So I have a live account that I use, but I'm just going to walk you through the create one first.
No, the Levaquin doesn't necessarily have to be at livor at all.
It doesn't have to be a traditional Hotmail account.
It can be a Gmail account.
So I can actually use maybe the same email address I used for getable or email addresses I use when
I'm signing up for things I can use that, whether it's Yahoo, Gmail, Hotmail or whatever it is,
and just click next.
And here it's it's telling me that I already have a Microsoft icon.
So that's just driving.
My point, though, that once you have an account, an email address, it doesn't have to be a hot meal
or a traditional Levaquin, but they are just creating a Microsoft account for you with that email address
so you can go ahead and sign up.
It's a pretty straightforward process.
The account that they said already existed.
That's an account I was using to sign up for the free account.
So I actually just went ahead and logged in.
And because I really didn't setup much more, I think that your registration process is actually going
to look very similar to this regardless.
So on to get over the hurdle of putting in your email address and proceeding, then you're probably
going to end up on a screen like this where you're going to be asked for your demographic information.
Just for the record, keeping my country and region is Jamaica and I'm putting in my phone number that
I treat next.
And then they say, do you want to verify your identity by phone or do you want to buy a card or someone
to choose?
Takes me by phone and I just got the text.
It didn't take long at all.
So I'm just going to put in the code and then verify.
Now, here's the part that might deter you if you're not prepared for it.
They will want to verify your identity by card so you won't be charged unless you upgrade, meaning
they have different OILCLOTH subscription plans.
So you're signing up for the free subscription plan.
Once that free subscription plan is done, then you won't be able to do much on the platform until you
sign up for a new subscription plan which coincides that upgrade.
So like I said earlier, there is pay as you go and then there's pay as you go test, which is the one
item on which is like half the price of the regular pay as you go.
So I actually provided my card information when I signed up.
And having done that, you can make an agreement.
If you don't have a card or you're not comfortable with providing your card details, then I mean,
you can stop here.
That's fine.
Later on, when we're actually deploying to as you can still see what it will look like and see how
beneficial it is to you.
But if you wish, then you can go ahead and provide your information and then click on the agreement
and accept the agreement terms and then you would be in on the platform.
So I'm just going to sign into my real account, my quote unquote relection, the one that I use, and
show you what a zero looks like.
Well, actually, I just stepped in portable dot as dot com, hoping that you would ask me to log in,
but I did that and they just rewrote me using the same icon that I was just setting up toward Williams
at G.M. dot com.
So this dashboard.
So this is the Azura dashboard.
That's a very basic level.
They have a panel to the side here listing out quite a few services that you can get.
But then because we didn't complete this little boy, because I didn't complete the setup, at least
then when I go to subscriptions, I'm going to see that I have no subscription.
So like I will see in the subscription is how they treat you as a customer, whether Europe as you go
enterprise or whatever.
So if I later on decide that I want to provide my information, I can just come back and click add and
then that will bring me to complete the Senate procedure where I actually add the subscription.
So this is a free trial, one that we're setting up just now.
As you go.
You have developer support as you have quite a few of them.
All right.
So I would probably go with pay as you go, but that that's yeah.
This is all in the in the steps of signing up for Azor, and that is if you wish to proceed with that.
But then for this detour, really and truly, I just wanted you to get as far as the dashboard so that
you can see that this is what a zero looks like.
This is really workload management, portelli against against your virtual machines.
But for this course, we'll be looking at up services.