Welcome back, guys, in this lesson, we'll be dealing with the post method or verb that allows us
to create resources or new records in our database, though we've worked with Post previously when we're
setting up our login functionality in our account controller.
We did kind of experiment with the post and we explore the fact that we can actually passing data in
the form of the body or an adjacent object that will get these serialized into whatever object we have
set up for it and that we know sensitive information needs to go across.
You know, you are in a visible manner.
So what we're going to be doing is setting up the post functionality for our hotel so that when we are
creating a hotel, we we can ask the user to send over all the details for a hotel in the form of a
JSON object, and then we pass it on to the database.
So I've already prepared the methods that we have over HDTV post and we will be returning Statler's
400 status to one as well as status.
Five hundred, no notice.
This is two one and not two hundred because to no one means created.
So we'll be indicating to the calling application or the client that's whatever you requested to be
created has been created.
So let's us get started.
And now the first thing that I would want to do before I go ahead and create anything or bring over
any data into my database is to check if the dates of coming over is valid.
So what I'm going to do is put in a new statement here to see if not model state is valid.
So we did something like that.
I believe when we're doing the log in where we said, is the model state valid?
Meaning everything that I said is required, is it there?
If not, we return the budget request.
So we're just going to do the same thing, replicate that step here.
But I'm saying if it is not valid, then we're going to log the era and say that there was an invalid
postal attempt in that method.
Right.
And we return the budget request.
Otherwise we want to try an operation.
So we have our track catch.
And, you know, the uniformity of our code is such that we can actually take these.
So you start seeing that we're kind of repeating certain things because all these things, what if we
wanted to change the message and we would have to change it here, change it in this method, change
it here.
And then as we expand, we have to have more touch points.
So later on with Seattle, we can kind of abstract out all of this repetition.
But right now, I just want to make sure that we understand the concepts at hand.
So we will just go ahead and modify the error message.
I know you can try our operation now.
What are we going to try?
The first thing that I would want to do is to take this deal.
And if we just review this detail, ETAs name, address rating and it's expects that country ID and
then we have hotel detail which has ID and country.
So once again, the reason we're not using hotel detail is that we don't need the ID value coming across
with the create attempt.
So that is why we only have the fields that we absolutely need values for outlined inside to create
version of this detail.
Now, once I have the detail, what I want to do is Muppet's someone to say A, our hotel is equal to
mopper the map into an object of type hotel, which is the data object.
And I'm mapping the content of the hotel DETI all.
Next up, we're going to call on our unit of work.
So I'm going to see underscore units of four dot hotels DOT and then I have insert whatever, inserting
my object of type POTO because by the time it gets here, whatever validations you need to put in,
you can put in.
So here I'm just validating the model.
If you had other things that you needed to make sure are in place before it gets as far as trying to
insert it, you make sure you do all of those checks and balances and return the budget request or whatever
aerostat goes to the client before you actually start to insert.
And even when doing the insert, if there's an exception, we're still going to return something, except
it will be a five hundred since the area is probably on our side.
So after we call the insert, the next thing we need to do is call the save.
So notice when we were just retrieving, we could just do Oades that get there's no save.
However, on this occasion we're altering the the database, so we have to commit the change that we're
making afterwards.
So that's.
Why we have to call the save.
Now, after all of that, we need to return something nice.
So what am I returning this?
I'm going to say Creer to now I've created and I've created at action right there, actually, and created
that route also.
So they all return the two or one.
It's just that when you say created, it's just a tool one.
That's it.
However, you can see it created at root and have it called the endpoint get hotel with the idea required.
So it actually returns the created object to the client, which I think is useful.
So I'm going to go with Creator that route, then I have to specify the name of the route.
So in this case, I did say I wanted to go to get a hotel and then after that I have to specify what
parameter values this endpoint might need.
So if I look back, I get hotel.
It needs an ID self to specify a new object.
And it's going to have a field called ID and it's going to be equal to a hotel that's already noticed,
hotel not totally to your hotel, still does not have a 90 value.
However, after this operation, this object will get updated with its ID and then that is what we will
pass along.
So let us take this one for a spin.
But just before we do that, before I get ahead of myself, we need to let this rule know that it has
this name right.
So even though it has the name, we need to let you know that it is a gift operation that goes by that
name, not necessarily ruled, but by that name.
Right.
So I can just append here and say name is equal.
So this is like a little internal nickname, though, to say this is your name.
Whenever somebody, your sibling, sibling being another action calls.
So let us try that again.
All right.
So we're going to test this one in postwoman.
And I already have an object here.
So I actually copied this object from a previous guest test.
So we already established that the ID is not required.
However, just going over to slugger, just to show you what slugger is going to care about, when we
look at the post for hotel, it's showing us that this is all this going to care about.
Even if we send over extra information, it will be ignored.
All right.
So that is what our object needs to look like in order to go into our post.
So using Posman, I'm actually going to test it with the ID and let's see what happens.
So I'm going to click through and make sure that this the action is on post.
We have our end point and then click send and we're getting this airable system invalid operation,
nor much is supplied values.
So that means we need to restructure the code, our own uncreated.
So going back to the code, let me just see what overlord's are there.
And we have the string name with object value.
I believe I'm missing the actual object.
There we go.
So Cummo and hotels or passing over the idea and the actual object to be displayed.
So let's try that again.
So the same test that just given error, I'm going to try it again.
And there we go.
So look at the difference between the two payloads, we're getting back to our hotel object with the
idea value of six.
All right.
Even the five is 5.0 here.
It's five here.
So just to show you that this didn't count for anything, thanks to us not allowing them to submit that
data.
So that's another reason it's a good idea to use details to kind of sanitize what can come into your
API.
Now, in addition to displaying the newly created record, another advantage just using created out
Rutan pointing to the endpoint would be that in the headers we actually return the location where they
can go and fetch this record.
So you see, it did have a certain purpose.
If I just, you know, the client, if they look in the headers and just get location after I have returned
the data that they can actually just use that and do a get operation and retrieve their record.
But of course, I'm not authorized.
So, you know, that whole shebang already that have to go through and do all of that.
No, on the point of being authorized, I don't think it's harmful to allow somebody to retrieve a hotel
by ID.
Right.
So we did authorize it initially because we were testing.
However, in practicality, I don't think we need to authorize get told if we allow them to get the
list, they should be able to get one.
However, I do think that it would be good to authorize who can create.
All right.
So it's up to you.
It's business rules and your needs will determine where you put the authorized and how much security
you enforce around your endpoints and operations.
So in this situation, I'm going to authorize create hotels.
So you have to be authorized.
And to make matters worse, if you are not in the role of admin, then you shouldn't be able to do this.
So to enforce rules based authorization, I can see rules equals and then list out as many rules as
I want to support.
So if I say authorized rules equals administrative, that means if you are authorized, you get to talk.
And what you are a user, not an administrator, then you cannot carry out anything.
You're still not authorized.
However, if you're an administrator, then you can go right ahead.
So that's it.
So once again, you can go about enforcing one.
What endpoint do you expose to John Public versus an author?
Authenticate that user and then by extension, how do you extend these functionalities to which authorized
group of users you can authorize based on policies, rules and quite a few options available to you?
If you just come, you'll see that you have the authentication scheme.
You could make one JWT, another one password off, et cetera, et cetera.
You can enforce a policy and you can limit it by rules.
So there are quite a few options for that.
So right now, I'm going to challenge you once again what we just did with create.
I encourage you to try and do it with the country, make sure that you test it and that you get back
your country successfully.
And we'll compare notes.
And we're back.
I hope you paused and attempted it, if not, then go ahead and pause.
No, but I'm going to walk you through what I did and really and truly, you'll notice that the court
is almost identical, one where in the country controller we have the same authorization measures.
Once again, your context may be different from mine, but we want to just make sure that we secure
the endpoints accordingly.
We are doing it post.
We have similar alternatives to what we did with the hotel except for the action.
I'm going to call it create controller passing the appropriate DTL.
We validate the model states firstly and then we go ahead and add just in the same fashion.
And then we created that route, get country parcel of the object and we made sure to add that name
here.
So you see, once you get the hang of this, unless you have some extreme circumstance where you have
to do extra computations on calculations, and even then it would just be a matter of mapping over or
you wouldn't probably wouldn't get the calculated values through the details.
So you Muppet to the object type and then you do all your calculations and then you insert and save.
So there's really not that much to creating resources in your API.