Hey, guys, welcome back.
So the first thing that we need to do, having set up our environment and everything, is to create
our projects.
So what we're going to do is launch Visual Studio and then we are going to go to create a new project.
From here.
You can choose the template that you want if you have HSP, not Natcore Web application at the top.
Go ahead and select it.
If you don't, then you can just type in web in this filter and it will filter down.
We're going to be using C sharp, so make sure that C Sharp is selected and you don't have to change
much else but to select the desired templates and go ahead and click next.
No will be building a hotel listing API.
So I'm going to call my project hotel listing right now that we have that we don't have to change much
else we can go ahead and create.
If you want to select a specific location, you may go ahead and do that.
Otherwise, proceed with create next step has a selecting the stock that we intend to use.
No, you would have already installed the dot net five SDK and Visual Studio twenty nineteen.
So you should have gotten it core 5.0 as a as an option.
If you don't have this then you should have three point one.
Either way you can just double back, go ahead and install the SDK, review that video if you need to
make sure you have everything installed and then you can go ahead and select 5.0 and we will be building
and speed on that core Web API.
No, to the right, we have the option of adding authentication and configuring some other things.
So we'll leave everything as is.
We won't be configuring the authentication here because the options that are given to us are not really
what we want.
So we'll be manually configuring that later on.
And that would be a good exercise.
At least I hope you understand how identity card gets integrated into your API, but we can leave it
as no authentication right now and then we can go ahead and click create.
So now that's our project has been created the just 2.0.
Before I move much further, the layout of my visual studio may look different from yours because I
tend to use the solution explorer on my left hand side.
By default, it should be on the right or it would be on the right.
So that's probably what yours looks like.
Either way, you can always drag it and put it wherever you want.
I like to have it to the left.
So that's where I'll be using my No.
The solution explorer is giving us a list of files and I'm just going through this and this is the first
time creating a project.
If it's not, then I'll just go over this anyway, because, you know, repetition, Beaton's impression
and maybe I'll point out something that you didn't know before.
But hey, so the first thing that we want to look at is our properties folder.
So let me start over.
So we have what we call the solution, which is like a manifest for the list of projects that are in
this solution that we're building.
The project is hotel listing.
I notice when I click it, it's really just an example file with a bunch of configurations and listings
and other things needed for the project to know what its identity is.
So because it is that net 5.0, you see that's the target framework.
If we choose three point one, we would see something different there on the properties or other dependencies.
We see analysers, frameworks, packages as we go along.
You see this list growing.
So don't get too much into what's happening there.
We look at properties, we see the line settings.
So here it's like just configurations to tell the application how it should behave when we are in the
bug mode.
So what's very important here, though, is that we did allow it to configure SSL or TPS when we're
creating a project.
As a result, we have this SSL port.
So when we're doing our application, testing and so on will be at HTP s colon slash slash localhost
colon.
And then because ETPs, we're using the SSA report, otherwise this would be the less secure HTP endpoint.
So that's just a little thing that I'm pointing out.
Otherwise, the other configurations we'll get into as we go along, we have our controllers folder,
which really Hoess, our well controllers and these do exactly what the name suggests.
They control the application flow, the logic or everything goes, you know, when we receive our request
for information, how we interpret it, and all of those behaviors would get defined inside of our controllers.
These are the first line of defense once it hits a.
API endpoint, you're actually coming to controller and then it would say, okay, which endpoint was
hit?
What should I do?
And then it will return accordingly.
Once again, as we go on, you'll see that come to life.
All right, I'm going to skip ahead to our upsetting thought, Jason, which doesn't talk much, we'll
be modifying that as we go along, though.
But let me go on to the program that Sears, which is the starting point for our application.
So here you see it runs its main functions.
If you don't know the language or developed in a C sharp console applications, you notice that you
always start with mean least C++, C Sharp Java, all of those languages at least have a mean method.
Right.
So once we're running, our API is going to hit the mean and in many is going to basically do like a
building.
So what it does is it aggregates all of the middleware on functionality and puts into the application.
So it goes this method, which is really defined right below, and it does its initialization based
on what is in our Start-Up File.
So if I go to startup, here's where you see where all the middle words are added and the configurations
are called at the get go.
So here we see where you want to use comptrollers to add whatever leverage we need to add so that we
can use our comptrollers setup swagger.
So traditionally, Swagga would have been you would have to implement that manually since this version
of Dunnett API, it comes out of the box.
So we don't have to do too much work.
But we'll be exploring what Swiger is later on in case you're not quite sure what it is we.
So that's configurations for your services.
So we have configure, which allows us to set up some other functionality.
So without getting too much into them, some of them are self-explanatory.
Some of them are for security reasons, and some of them are really nice to haves.
And we are going to be adding more and more as we put more features into our API.
So don't worry too much about it.
And the final file in this solution would just be this model.
So this model just basically represents data or a strongly typed unit of data, and we'll be defining
lots of models and data transfer objects later on.
But for now, we have created our project.
We should have a fair understanding of what we're looking at inside of this solution.
And when we come back, we will start configuring our first added service in the form of login.