Welcome back.
In this lesson, we're going to start setting up our data classes and by extension our data base, that
we'll be using an intuitive framework, which is Microsoft or course flagship object, relational mapper
or for short.
And they allow us to actually model our database classes or database tables, rather, as C sharp classes
and then engineer our database based on our class definitions.
So what we're going to be doing to get things started is creating a new folder in our project.
So just right click, go to add and click new folder and I will just call this data now inside data.
We're going to start putting in our classes so our hotel listing or API will really just for educational
purposes, only have two classes or two tables, one for the country and one for the hotel.
So basically, when we look for our country, we should be able to see all the hotels that are associated
with said country.
That's basically the idea that we're going for.
All right.
So I'm just going to go ahead and click data, click, add, and our first class will be country.
So notice I'm going to name it in a singular fashion country.
The next one would be hotel.
So this each class represents one unit, country and a hotel before we start defining the fields for
either.
I just want to get all the files in place and then we can just work our way back and see how everything
ties in.
So after we have defined our classes, at least these two, I want to just go ahead and create what
we call our DB context class.
So I'm going to call it data base context and go ahead and add that.
And then this class is really going to represent our bridge between our defined classes or entity classes
and the actual database.
So country that's an entity that's going to be formed, engineered into a table or whatever we define
as feels, will soon double back and do that.
But whatever field we put in country will be fills in a table called whatever we call it.
So we're going to call the table countries because the table is effectively a collection of records
of type country.
The same goes for hotel and the same will go for as many other entities slash tables as you may have
to define.
So this is what we call code first engineering, where we actually write all the code for how we think
our tables should look and then forward engineer or make adjustments to the table accordingly.
So after creating this database context, we need to kind of outfitted with things that it needs to
know that it is the bridge to the database.
So the first thing that it needs to know is that it inherits from DB context.
Now, this is going to give an error because I need to go and fetch some tools.
But then when I control of not you, you'll see Visual Studio suggesting that you installed the missing
package, which is Microsoft thought entity framework core.
If you're not seeing this prompt, no problem.
You can always just go right.
Click the project, go to management you get and then you can search for the same package.
Just go to Brose and type in the package name and you would see it listed there.
So either one works.
But while I'm here, I'm just going to get all of the the libraries from here that's I know I'm going
to need.
So I'm definitely going to need this library.
So I just don't load that one.
And once again, I know I'm definitely going to need the driver for Eskil server because we'll be using
SQL Server databases.
That being said, there are other ones for other database engines.
So you can use to see what light you have.
I've seen post, Griss, I'm not seeing it listed here, at least not immediately.
But they're all here.
So we'll be using SQL Server.
So I'll go ahead and get that one.
And the final one that we're getting, at least for this period, is the set of tools because we need
the tools to be able to run some commands in the future.
So I just go ahead and install that one also.
All right, so now that we're done in, you get if you don't want to check over and installed, if you
clear the filter, you'll see everything that you have installed, that's fine.
So I'm going to go back to my DB context and then I'm going to control that again.
And then the prompt no changes to include the using statement because we already have the library at
this point, though, inside of our repository.
Well, sorry, our database context.
What we need to do is define a constructor, someone to see a public database context.
Or I could have just done Setar tab tab.
There we go.
And then I'm going to take the parameter DB context options.
So this will be passed on from the start up.
But we haven't defined all of that yet, so we're just auditing it right now.
And then what I need to do is also initialize the base controller constructor for the context to take
the same options for no, we don't need to put anything else inside of the constructor so we can just
leave that blank and move on.
So I did say that this represents the bridge between our application and our database.
So it is here that we actually list out what the database should know about when it is being generated.
So in short, our terms are more practical terms.
I want to say a public DB set, give this DB set a data type, which in this case could be called entry.
And then I'm going to give the property a name, which would be countries, so the name that you give
it here is the name that the database will use.
So the data type, as far as Sharp is concerned this country.
But then the database is going to define a table called countries, and whenever we're accessing it,
access it those countries.
So that is a minor thing.
I mean, everybody has their own naming convention and some people use a common letter for their table
names.
I don't like to do that.
I like to keep my table names, plural and the data type singular because this is one country.
But and this is a collection of countries.
After all, this is a set.
It's a set of countries.
It no matter how you want to justify it, that's that's my justification.
Once again, context rules, everything.
So I'll do the same for hotel and hotels.
So there we go.
After doing all of this, we need to let our upset things know about the connection string.
So the connection string is basically just as good as the name suggests, a string that outlines how
to get to the database that the application needs to connect to.
So what I'm going to do here is create a new section and it's automatically giving me connection strings.
Right.
And inside there, I'm just going to call this let's call it a secure connection.
And Eskil Connection is going to have server equals and we have a local DB that is kind of built into
visual studio.
So at this point, you may have your own database that you want to use.
If if not, and you're a beginner and you're just following along, then you may use this one that's
defaulted off to do much more any more installation.
Actually, it's already included with your visual studio installation.
However, at this point, if you have like an obscure server, you know, whether it's localhost or,
you know, the IP address, that's what you would put in as a server value instead of what I have here.
All right.
But continuing, we also define a database names.
So the database that we should look for slash create, I'm going to call it hotel listings for listing
on the scoreboard.
So that's the name of the database that's I would like to interact with on that server.
And then just one more very important or relatively important option, which is integrated security
and that agency equals.
Sure.
So that's what our connection string looks like.
So everything will come together after a while.
We're just doing it bit by bit and building up to when everything is integrated.
So our next step is to go over to our start.
So.
I did say that when we define the context is getting into options from the start.
So the startup needs to know that when the application starts, it should be loading its database configuration
from here and using this file as the bridge.
All right.
So what we're going to do is add a new section.
Actually, let me just riada this a bit.
So I like to add controllers as last or near to the last thing I do in configure services.
I like to do everything else before I add controller so you can just go ahead and move that line.
So services that add DB context.
And so I call the database context.
The code, the function is it's looking for a DB context and then what it expects is something off type
DB context.
So this is of type DB context.
This is my context that I'm creating.
So I'm going to pass that in as that data type is looking for, of course, including any missing references.
There we go.
And then here's the part options.
Right?
So we have that little lambda initialized that we're used to by now or it's not foreign to us by now.
So four options.
I'm going to say use.
Escudo.
Server, all right, and remember that when when when you get just not included that ESKIL server library,
say, if I just control Duchesse here, it's being include that using statement.
All right.
So use a secure server and then it's going to want to know, OK, so where am I getting the configuration
from?
So I went to see a configuration that get your connection string.
Get connections.
There we go.
And then this is automatically upsetting.
So it says good connection string, because it's already knows that there might be a section for connection
strings.
And I'm saying get the connection string with that name so you can actually find multiple connections,
strings here.
You just need to separate them and each one of its unique name.
And at that point, you could actually configure different database contexts for different databases
in the same application, which could come in handy if your API needed to span multiple databases.
So there are a number of benefits to having an API because it's not limited to one database on one set
of interactions.
Right.
So get connected on string.
I'll go ahead and pass in that name, closing all the bridges that need to be closed.
And now I believe that we have everything later on, we'll come back and modify this one, we need some
other functionality added.
But for now, OK, add an extra semicolon.
So there we go.
So far, no, we have all we need.
Before I move any further, I'm just going to double back and we are going to complete our class definitions.
So we have a hotel and we have country.
So country.
And I'm just going to say Tabatabai Tab is going to have an ID.
So Entity Framework's is if you create a field called, I automatically assume that this is the primary
key.
All right.
So you have two options.
You can see it or you can see the entity name ID.
You will automatically say, OK, well, I'll just use this as a primary key.
And so I'd be right there.
That one is the key.
And let's see, a country also has a name, so country name and one more.
So just use control D to duplicate that line and we see maybe area or Schadt, maybe that's just the
start.
So in my case, the first country that I would put in is Jamaica and the short name would be GM.
And then based on the country, of course the short name is different.
Right.
So that those are the fields that I expect the country to be able to have when the database is generated.
So I'm going to save that one and I'm going to look at Hotel No.
So to start off, we can take it in name because I mean, we have to have the primary key.
Every hotel has a name, but then I have some other fields here, including address, which is string
the rating, which is a double and then a foreign key reference to our country.
So let me explain this.
So if you know about databases, you know that the primary keys, the unique identifier for any given
table, the foreign key represents unique reference.
Art may not be unique, but it is a strong reference to another record in another table.
In other words, any hotel has to be in a country.
So we have the hotel, we give it the name and address.
It's rating, but then we let it know.
We we give an I.D. here that corresponds with a country ID.
All right.
So we have to define two fields.
We have data annotation here.
So square, various foreign key and you give it the name that you want.
So you could actually give this foreign key feel a different name if you wanted to.
You could manually put in your name or in this case, I'm just going to give you the same name as the
class that it's referencing.
So name off whatever class.
Right?
Then we have two properties.
We have country as an object and then we have it as an integer.
So it is the hard reference.
That's the ID value, the one, the two of the three, etc. However, country represents the actual
object.
So we can include all the details here.
When we look at a hotel, if we wanted to know the name of the country, all we have natively instead
of hotel is the clincher ID.
But then we can fill this object with all the details so we can see in hotel dot, country dot, whatever
properties that we wish to include in our data.
So this is a nice and easy way to one create a foreign key reference to another table and to make sure
that when we pull a query for a table that has foreign keys all over the place, we can include all
the details right here without getting too many messy joins and having to jump through hoops to get
into the.
So now that we have all of these details defined, let me just do a quick run through just to make sure
we're all on the same page.
We have our folder called Data in which we're going to be storing all of our domain or database related
objects and code.
All of that will be stored inside of this folder called data.
Later on, we can look at maybe putting it in its own project, but for now, it's just three files
or a few number files.
So we don't need to do all of that.
So data has a file called Country, which is defining our countries table and one called hotel, which
is defining the hotels table.
We also have the database context, which is inheriting from DB context, courtesy of Entity Framework
Core, which is once again acting as our bridge between our data classes and the actual database.
All right.
How does it get to the database?
Well, one, we have the connection string that defines where to look, what to look for and yes, look
for security.
Right.
So that is our connection string.
Otherwise, at Stato, we want to add the deed context or add that bridge to the database courtesy of
this file.
And this file should be using this connection string.
OK, sorry, I just had one extra brace, I just removed it.
All right, so let us do a quick build before we proceed to engineer or database.
And to do a build, you can to hold on control, shift and press be or you can go to build here and
build solution, but we have a successful bill.
So let's go over to the package manager console.
If you're not seeing it there, you can always go to and new get package manager and package manager
console.
All right.
So here is where that entity Framework for Tools Library comes in handy because it allows us to run
certain commands here to facilitate the scaffolding.
And that's what it's called, scaffolded in the database, the creation of the database.
We have to run certain commands.
So what we have to do is first add to what we call a migration's Adarsh migration.
If you start typing apress, it will kind of autocomplete and then I'll see creation.
That's a database created.
All right.
So we had the migration database created.
So this is basically going to generate like a manifest or a preliminary file to see that it is generating
and see I'm getting an error.
So this is good.
It's good when we see these errors and we work through them, because sometimes when we go through perfectly,
we don't know what might happen.
All right.
So this arrow has to do with the country property in the hotel class, and I believe that uses the Arden's.
So what I've done is to reorder it.
So I had the ID underneath the property.
That's what it looks like initially.
So I'm just going to reorder by taking the property, the integer property and putting it directly underneath
the annotation for a foreign key and moving that down.
So as you can see, it can be sensitive Artomatic with some things.
So let's see if this works.
I'm just going to rerun this command at migration.
And we are getting a completely different vibe where it is seeing Bill started, succeeded and is letting
us know that if we want to undo, we can run this, which means it has been done right.
So here we have our migration file and then we see that we've got a new folder called Migration's.
And what it does is take snapshots of each instance of the database.
So at this point, we're defining our table countries with these column attributes and these properties.
And if you look if you look at it closely, I don't want us to analyze it too much because, you know,
it can be overwhelming.
But if you look at it as somebody who is familiar with the C sharp language, you realize that it's
not seeing anything out of the ordinary, seeing we have a table or we're creating a table, write the
name of it is countries based on what we define in the DB context, countries that the columns in the
table should be idy, which is column of type in it.
And we're defining it as identity to increment by one.
Right.
That's all it's really doing.
Name is string, which should be defined as inva char because in in a secure server, a strong Israel
inva char and short name and char right there were there could be controls that could put our own maybe
the size and if it's moldable.
Right.
But then those are things that we can look at later on.
Ultimately, though, we see here that we have our migration and it looks good.
So the next step would be to actually create the database.
All right.
So what we do is go back to our package manager, console and roon, update the database and give that
a few.
And then when it is done, it will let us know with a simple done.
So how do we check?
How do we verify?
So you can go over to the Eskil server object explorer.
I have it open here if you don't have it.
There you go to view and you choose a secure server object explorer.
So in the server Object Explorer, we go to the very server that I did see was built into Visio studio,
which is Loka DB slash Ms Escarole logo, DB or so.
You can expand that, go to databases and then you will see the database listed there.
So hotel listing DB and when we drilldown and drilldown we'll see our countries.
You'll also see that they're tracking all of the migrations happening.
So each time you make a change to the cross that said, somebody came and said, oh, we need to extend
control, we need to put on dialling code or area code, whatever it is, then you add a new field,
you create a new migration, you update the database, you will create one more file like this to say
this is the change should be made and then of the database will go ahead and make those changes on your
behalf.
That's good.
In a development environment.
In a production environment, not so much.
There will be far more controls.
Our own hold updates to the database are handled.
But for now, when we're building from scratch, it's good to understand how to do so efficient.
So that's it for now.
What we did today was we defined our data classes, our domain classes.
We set up our DB context.
We did all of this from scratch.
All right.
And that's good.
It's good to understand how everything connects.
So we have the database context.
The classes are the DB sets and the respective names.
I remember whatever you call the properties here, that's what the table will get called.
If you need to undo the migration, it becomes a bit tricky because if you just to remove migration,
you will get an arrow where it will tell you that the migration has already been applied.
So you would have to revert this change to the database on a hole which since it's in the young stages,
you might as well just you could actually just go and delete the database, make your changes, create
a new migration and do an update database.
Right.
So if you do need the database, then into the framework won't be won't be telling you that something
has been applied to a database that's not there.
It would allow you to remove migration.
You make changes to whatever classes, then you do everything again at migration update and then it
would scaffolded database with your changes.
Otherwise, if it is not as serious as removing moving migration, you just wanted to add or remove
something.
You go ahead, make your changes to your domain classes accordingly.
Then you add migration of the database and it will take a snapshot once again at each point.
So when we come back, we will look at how we can see data into the tables, meaning when the when the
migration happens, we just put data in before we even get into the API because it's nice to have test
data there before we start putting in data through our actual testing of the API.