Hey, guys, today we're going to get started with installing Visual Studio, Community Edition and
DOT at five.
Now our journey begins here on the Visual Studio website, which you can get to see through a simple
Google search.
Or you can try to reproduce this URL, which is Visual Studio, dot Microsoft, dot com slash, VSS
slash community.
Now there are different editions of Visual Studio and community is the one that is free for individual
use and that's the one that we will use.
So you can go ahead and download Visual Studio, which will give you the visual studio installer.
And once that is completed, you can go ahead and run that file, go through in the security check points
that you might have, but you may proceed to allow the installer to begin.
Now, this is where you actually define what Visual Studio will be capable of.
So these are called workload's.
And each workload will expose a different feature set to do so for Web development.
You want to get the speed on it and web development workload for desktop development.
You want to get the desktop development workload.
And for any other SDK or type of project that you may want to develop, you can go ahead and get the
workload associated with it.
For this exercise.
You want to prepare our visual studio with the necessary resources for web development.
Once again, you can go ahead and take as many of these workflows.
Each one will come with its own size and it tells you how much space is required based on the ones that
you select.
But at minimum, for Web development, you want to make sure you have speed on that and web development.
You can go ahead and take the other development tools if you wish.
But I'm not going to do that because these are all dot net framework six and four and four point eight
four point sixty four point seven and four point eight.
But we're going to be installing dot net five in a few minutes so you can go ahead and do this and let
Visual Studio install.
This will take a while so you can grab a cup of coffee and come back.
No ones that don't load and installation is completed.
You have two options.
You can go ahead and sign in and sign in, meaning you sign in with your life account if you have one.
If not, then you go ahead and create one.
It's free and it makes life easier if you just create one and actually sign in.
But I'll just go ahead with the not no maybe later option and then you choose your general settings.
So I like the dark theme and you can choose who they want web development settings or general, I'll
just leave mine on General even though we are doing web development.
But they basically just optimized certain keyboard shortcuts and the layout based on your selection
of Lieberman in general.
And I'll start with Visual Studio.
All right.
So once that is done, you're going to be prompted with this, though.
If you don't get this, then that's fine.
But here is why I would have suggested that you sign in with your life accounts because you you have
a 30 day trial period.
And if you don't have the account, then they'll basically just tell you to exit.
So you can actually just go ahead and sign in.
So I'm just going to sign in with my own.
And once you have signed it and then you'll see that it is not licensed to you and it just looks a bit
more inviting.
So now, instead of exiting Visual Studio, I can close.
And this is Visual Studio at the very basic level.
Now we have Visual Studio.
What we also need is Daughton at five so you can get to the dot net five download page through a simple
Google search once again.
Or you try to reproduce this.
You are whichever one you find easier to do at this point.
You want to download the SDK and the runtime.
So let me start by closing Visual Studio because it need to install extensions for it and the installer
is always available for you.
So if you fail to add a workload, just so you know, you can actually just click modify and then it
will relaunch that page with all the workload.
So if later on you wanted to do something new, you just need to modify, get that workload and then
you will get those project templates accordingly.
I'm going to close with the studio, however, so we can continue with our installation, so we'll get
the dominant five.
No, you can see that the SDK is available based on your OS.
I have Windows 64 bit OS working with right now, so I'll go ahead and download that and why that one
is downloading.
I'm just going to hit the mark button and go over to the runtime, which is absolutely necessary for
hosting to see the ICE runtime support.
So if you're going to be hosting the net five application on a local server, then you definitely need
the runtime so you can just get this hosting bundle that they have there available for download.
So you can just download both and when they're both finished.
So when the SDK is finished, you can go ahead and install that one first.
It shouldn't take too long.
And OK, so it's successful after we've installed the SDK, then we want to just make sure that we have
the runtime also agree to anything and go ahead and ruin your installation and it will let you know
when it is successfully completed now that we have the SDK is completely installed.
I just want to launch Visual Studio and show you what you get with those SDK.
So if I go ahead and create a brand new project.
Because of the workload's that I have available to me, I will see different project templates, so
I own the tool is the Web workload, so I have the ability to do a regular console up.
I have the speed on it core.
As a matter of fact, I think that this one comes because of the desktop work load.
But at this point I'm not trying to figure out which workload belongs to which.
I just know that if you are going to be doing a Web project, you have the option to choose your Web
application, a blazer application, and you can choose them with a core or dot net framework, someone
to choose a core Web application.
This is not the actual application that we're building.
I'm just showing you your options when we go ahead, put the project name to create.
Then from the dropdown list here, you can choose whether you want to core two point one or three point
one or the latest dot Natcore five point or and with that, you will be able to choose the different
templates and proceed.
So when we come back, we'll actually create a project and do a tour of the folder structures.