Hey, guys, I want to take this time out to welcome you to this new course, ultimate SB at five Web
API Development Guide No.
Its title is a mouthful, but I can assure you the contents sort of lives up to the billing.
In this course, you'll learn how to create and maintain maintainable Web API using air speed net five,
which is the latest and greatest in the Microsoft Development Stock Entity framework.
And we will explore many enterprise level design patterns and considerations when it comes to designing
an API.
I am your instructor for this course.
My name is Trevor Williams, I am a software engineer and part time lectures.
Now, let's explore what's an API is the letters app and I are short for application programming interface,
pretty much an API is a software interface that acts as an intermediary between two applications.
So let's say you can access Facebook like functionalities from an app that is not a Facebook app.
So this app has to talk to Facebook and allow you to do Facebook like things, whether that is communicating
with Facebook through an API.
So in this course, you will learn how to build that kind of interface to allow persons to access an
underlying data store that we will be building using functionality that we will be building or using
clients that they will need to build, whether it's from mobile or web or any other type of device.
So APIs or at least the type of API that we will be building are based on the rest principles.
So we will learn, rest and rest assured for representational state transfer.
It is a very popular Web API standard and it is across many platforms.
So though we will be building the API using the net or the API can be consumed by clients from many
other developments.
That's in addition to this will be learning how to use that.
Natcore five will be looking at how to understand the services and how the whole application still works.
And we'll also be looking at using enterprise level pattern.
So, you know, best practices that we can put into the code such that when we are ready to expand,
whether through our own self discovery or in an enterprise setting, we won't have to pull up too much
of our application to do that.
But we can just take on components as we go along.
So in a nutshell, you're going to learn Espie dominated by an entity framework for we're going to be
using code first database development and exploring once again key encoding patterns, looking at API
authentication, using JSON Web tokens or JWT for short, how we can protect and harden our endpoints
and protect them from unauthorized or unwanted access.
We look at understanding the darknet poor service pipeline and how we can extend them and put in our
own middleware.
We're looking at API testing and logging, so we'll be using Horstmann and Cerillo for our API testing
and logging purposes respectfully.
And we'll also be looking at how Swiger can play a part in documenting our API and also helping with
our testing source control.
We will be using GitHub so that we can securely store our code and be able to roll back should we need
to.
And then we look at after building all of these wonderful things, how exactly we allow our API to be
accessed, whether in a company setting or by the world know this course has quite a bitterness.
It's about 10 hours long and you will be learning a lot of things.
So buckle up, get ready for this journey.
And I'm very excited to have you along.