Welcome back, guys, at this point.
We have basically completed at least the bulk of our configurations as we go along, we may see the
need to include all those things.
But right now we want to start actually making our API work because outside of hitting F5 and seeing
Swiger and seeing the logs, nothing works.
We don't have an API just yet.
So what we want to do is actually start configuring our get end points.
And I'm going to explain exactly what the get endpoints mean.
So to start us off, we're going to just look at this weather forecast control that came with our project,
but it is actually just some sample code that kind of provides some context as to what we need to do
to get our get in point up and running.
So our controller, like I said before, actually controls what happens when a user requests information
and hits the controller.
The endpoints are usually determined by our what we call actions, which are these functions that are
going to be defined inside of the controller.
And what it responds with are when the controller, the action is hit, rather, it does its computation
and then responds in a manner that the calling application or the client application that is trying
to access the API will know that this was a successful call maybe.
And generally speaking, whenever somebody calls, I get commodities in order to retrieve information.
Hence the word gets they're getting something or they expect to get something.
So within the context of this sample controller, we see that we when we call this end point, it is
going to return data.
So we are getting data granted.
It is very random data.
It's nothing to zero.
But the reality is that it is doing the simple command, which is getting so we have what we call this
HTP attribute.
Right.
And it is seeing it is defining the behavior of the function.
So when we actually test results and we can do that right here in Swiger, we just go ahead and pull
this down and they shows all of the examples of what we might get.
We can click, try it out and click execute.
And then it's going to show that this was the request that was sent.
So notice, there is no real indicator here to say or this slash get.
There is no indicator to see what the endpoint was.
We know the server based on the fact that when we run the application, that's our server address.
And then we know the controller that we're interacting with weather forecasts.
Right.
That's the name of our controller.
Weather forecast controller is a static keyword.
Ever control necessar naming convention.
But then I don't know which action it hit.
So what really happened is that I'm just going to set a break point here so we can see that when we
click execute, it actually hits that breakpoints.
It's calling this method and it's called a get.
And when I have five, it just returns with all the information that was being retrieved from that.
So what's really happening here is that based on the protocol and certain definitions that we're going
to be making here on each option, the way we formulate our requests, it will the controller will automatically
know which one we should hit.
And the context for this, the background behind this is that you don't want to get too granular with
your names for your actions.
So you don't want to say, get off, get one, get one by.
I'd get one by name.
You can call.
Well, you can actually call the action.
Basically, anything you want to say can give it its own name.
Of course there are standards surrounding that, but the reality is that if you have multiple gets,
you can name all of them the same get.
But you, based on the data that is required to retrieve the information you can stipulate which get
should get called.
So all of that once again, this is just the introduction.
So in the next video, we're going to create our own controller.
We're going to start off with the hotels, sorry, with the countries, and we'll see exactly how it
goes.
And we want to retrieve the countries, the listing of countries from the database through an API called.