It goes so we'll be starting a new section of our API development and really actually this is just about
value added features.
We've done quite a bit of work.
We already have a functioning API with a nice, clean architecture that can be easily extended.
However, there are certain things that we want to take advantage of when it comes to core.
And these features are these allowances will enable us to reduce some of the repeated code that we have
throughout our application.
So let's say, for instance, one we keep on repeating track catch.
Every time we do an operation, we have the track.
So we'll be looking at putting in code to reduce that and handle errors in a global fashion.
Since we really do the same thing almost every time, all the things we'll be looking at will be to
reduce our need for checking certain doing certain checks before we complete certain operations or putting
in action filters.
We'll also be putting in mechanisms to help speed up the retrieval and processing of data like caching
paging.
So we'll be looking at all of these things and we'll start off with implementing paging.
So stay tuned.