All right, so now we'll be constructing our first controller and our first get operation, so I'm going
to actually controllers go to and click controller and then we're just going to do an API empty controller.
So just choose the EPA to the left and a controller that's empty.
And we're going to click at no, just for some clarity.
We have gone ahead and obstructed a lot of the data base operations into our units of work so that we're
not directly interacting with our data base through our controllers.
Right.
If we did API controller with actions using entity framework, then it would actually generate a controller
which has an active object of the DB context, which is the data base connection.
And we would be able to do all of our entity framework work right here.
The danger of that, however, is a danger.
In the long run, it may become less maintainable as the requirements grow because then you're going
to end up repeating a lot of it, which is why I went all the way over to our AI unit of work abstractedly.
All of that made it very generic so that we have one code base that we're just making more dynamic calls
to.
So far, no, I'm just going to deal with the empty one because we really don't need to go ahead and
scaffold this one out.
But as we build on the application, you will see the practicality of all that we have done.
So API controller, that's empty.
Go ahead and click.
Add and then the name.
You generally want, once again, the name to reflect the endpoint, because just like with weather
forecast, we know that when we hit you earth slash weather forecast, we expect to deal with weather
forecasts or if I expect to be with the hotels, sorry, I'm starting with countries.
I keep on seeing autos.
So we will have Country Hour.
We could see countries controller.
Right.
I want to say country, our country controller, and then we get our blank controller know a little
background behind what you're looking at in this controller, the route.
So we have two rooting mechanisms that we can use in API development, at least NBC API development.
One is the convention base rooting our team, right.
That one is where we actually have to go to the startup and we would configure in use endpoints.
We would kind of configure our route so I could and endpoints that map controller controller route.
There we go, and then I would kind of define the naming convention so I could see a name Kolon and
I'll just say default and then the convention for the routine would be the pattern.
What should I look like?
And I'm just showing you, this is not the one that we're going to use, but I'm just making sure you
understand exactly all the options that's out there.
So we'll have comptroller and then the sample will be equals home.
Right.
Slash action.
And, for example, index.
And then slash any parameters that would be required are not in the form of the IED.
All right.
So this should be encouraged versus also.
So this would be our way of defining convention based routine schema so that we any time a request comes
in, that request needs to specifically state that we're looking for this controller by that name in,
for example, weather forecast controller or that's the endpoint we hope to look for.
But we want this specific action.
So I didn't mention that we don't want to get too specific with our actions.
We don't want to say get countries, get country, get country by name, get to country by you know,
we just list them or we have 50 actions.
And then you the calling client application us to remember the action to be used with each call.
So that is what this would kind of force us to do so far.
And that's that's probably more useful for a Web application, you know, irregular NVC application.
But when it comes to the rest API standards, what they want is for the verb to determine what it is
that you are going to be doing.
So then we are going to be using what we call attributes routing.
Right, which is basically just going to say, look for the controller and some FAA wanted to modify
the frequency API slash controller.
So whatever you put here is what is going to come after that server name, server, name being localhost
Kolan, whatever power to slash whatever route is here.
Right.
So if you look back at weather forecast or the weather forecast, that's what's there.
So it was that slash the controller being weather forecast.
If we look at our new one, we see that we have slash API slash controller.
So then the links will look slightly different.
So when we generate a Saugatuck, you'll see that coming to light.
But right now, what we're going to be using is the attribute.
Base throating.
All right, so it allows us to map directly to our controller and directly to the actions without being
too specific about which exact one, but then the verb is going to determine what endpoint should be
called based on the request.
And so now that we've gotten all of that background, let's actually wire up our first and get.
So before we can do anything else, we have to include our private read only a unit of work so that
we can take advantage of the database access.
Right.
And I'm just going to call this one on the score unit of work.
So this is my naming convention where I use an underscore and you would see it at other places to use
an underscore for private variables and well, you'll see as we go along.
So we need that.
And I'm just going to put on the logger so I lugger.
After that, we need to go and set up our injections, so I'm just going to quickly copy and paste these.
So that I don't have to monitor, retyping to do.
So once again, dependency injection means that once we have registered and on that note, we need to
go to the start up and complete a configuration, but once you have registered something in the start
up as a service in the bootstrappers, it becomes available to four in injection in any way in most
cases.
Right.
So far, control, we can just inject an instance of the units of work and we'll just make like a copy
of it to Four Loko use.
So that's what this is for.
And we'll do the same for the longer.
All right, so we have our local copies of those.
No, the thing that we need to do in the start up is to actually register the units of work.
So we created it, but we didn't register it in the bootstrappers.
So I went to leave it.
And I'm going to show you the error that you would get and then we can resolve it together.
All right.
So moving on, after doing those preliminary things to configure my constructor, I'm going to define
that.
I want an HTP and you can see all of the potential verbs being listed there.
So HTP get operation.
And to complete this operation, I'm going to be using public and I'm just going to go Issing.
So public async.
Task after action results.
All right, so if you if you had generated the controller with the ESP, with the entity framework already
added to it, all of them would have been a task of our action result.
So you just get it out of the box.
So it's good to just start using it from the from the get go.
Right now I can name on get country.
All right.
And that's fine.
I mean, well, in this case, I want all countries so get countries because I'm getting multiple.
Right.
Once again, based on our routine, we don't need to specify that.
Well, you'll see that later on.
And then our task now is going to do a try catch.
Right.
So we're going to try an operation and handle any error that we might get.
And I'll extend this with the X so that we are actually catching the exception object.
And then here I'm going to see var countries is equal to.
Our units off work to call the countries and then I can say get all.
All right, looking good.
Now, remember, with our our method, we could put in an expression here if we wanted to add a filter,
you know, get companies where this that that that we could do quite a few things from this method alone.
But right now, we just need.
All right.
And then I'm going to return.
So the return types are very important.
Right.
You want to return key when everything went all right.
That's why it's called Occy, right.
Or two hundred.
So the status number is 200 and we can return to OK with the data.
All right, so that looks good so far.
We're going to be modifying it a bit in a few, but that's what we're going to try and do.
And then if everything goes OK, will return, OK?
And it's going to send back to the calling client whatever data came back from this call.
Now, in our touch, at this point, our lugger becomes very important.
So logger log error and then I can see something like that.
A sign something went wrong.
And I can see I can put in more details in the eye and someone to use my interpellation, that's a dollar
sign there in case you're not familiar with it, thylacine's.
True, it allows me to superimpose any variable at this point.
So I'm just going to kind of specify the name of the method where whatever went wrong.
Right.
So name of get countries.
All right, and then I'm going to.
Passing the exhibition object.
Actually, I have that backwards.
The exception should come first in apology.
So it's exhibition come then something went wrong or exhibition, then our message.
So Syria, along with actually just fleshlight, our print of the entire structure is so you can see
all the details of the arrow from the exhibition that has been through.
You know, if there's an error, I don't want to just throw what I want to do is alert the client that
something went wrong.
So, yes, the logger sees it.
That's for our internal purpose.
But then I want to return something to the user to see, you know, this is what happened.
So Stuto scored five hundred is the universal code to see there was a server issue issue.
All right.
So this is telling the user that this something went wrong on our part.
It's not you.
It's me.
All right, so then the status code five hundred means internal server error.
And as I say, please try again later.
All right.
So that's what our client or the client consuming the API will see when there's an error.
Otherwise they should get the list of countries.
So let us test this out.
All right.
So the first thing you'll notice is that, no, our new endpoint has been added to the saga.
The second thing you'll notice is the difference between how the links look.
So weather forecast versus API country, once again, that has to do with the route that we have defined
up here with its API slash controller, or it is just the controller name.
Right.
So it's it's dynamic.
So at any point we can go and remove the API if it's too much of a bother, but we'll leave it for a..
So let us see it.
Try it out and then execute.
And what do we get.
So first, that's the request, Yoro.
So the server.
All right, slash API slash country, and we're getting this error.
All right, so it's actually spitting ode to our sluggard, the entire response to see unable to resolve
service that that activating this, that, and you see that it's getting a five hundred error rate.
So we totally return a five hundred whenever something bad happens.
Another thing to notice, though, is that I'm not specifying the name of the function being called.
So before we fix that error, notice I'm not seeing API slash controller slash get countries.
It is only calling slash API slash country.
You, the user doesn't know the name of the method being called and being, you know, sending the response.
So that's another thing that when we talk about the routine convention, because we specify that it's
I get it automatically formed to be, I get commands.
So we're going to fix the error and then I'm going to test it again using postmen, which should provide
a little more context as to what we mean by git versus post, et cetera, et cetera.
So to fix this error, we need to register our service, like I said before, in our startup, not see
us.
So in the startup, we need to see something like services dot and add transient.
Our units of work, units of work, so you would see the different scope options are transient at scoped
and at Singleton?
Yes, sometimes I forget, right.
So add the things we've done a ton before.
No, we haven't.
All right.
So I translated means that every time it is needed, a new instance would be created at school.
It means that a new instance is created for a period or for the lifetime of a certain set of requests.
And Ad Singleton means that only one instance will exist for the entire duration of the application.
So based on your needs, you might end up doing different ones.
So add transient.
Here means that whenever somebody hits my control, I'm going to always create art.
This is always going to provide a fresh copy of the IOU and the tough words.
Let me just go ahead and include the missing references.
And then let's try that request again, so this time I'm going to use postmen to handle this request,
so I'm still going to try it out only to show that, OK, so we're getting an error for the logger and.
OK, let's fix that.
So these are it's good to see these areas.
You can tell why we can't we can try and show those chutes, why we're getting those.
So I think the issue with the logger is that it has to be injected with the context of the class it's
being injected into.
So in this case, it will be the troller.
So I just swap this also I lugger within the context of just genes where we see whether to control controller.
All right, and then let's try that once again.
All right, so we're going to try it with Postman this time.
So I'm just going to enter the request URL, which once again is just the is the localhost call on the
port number that you have and then slash Appia slash country.
Now, when we talk about get versus post versus put with Bowsman, we can actually try to change the
type.
So it's remember that we built it to be a get.
That's what it is designed to be, which means that if I attempt to call this same endpoint with a post,
it's going to give me I could not get a response.
And OK, I'm getting something because of the SSL, so you can just go ahead and disable SSL verification
if you're getting that issue.
All right.
There we go.
So method Matalote, method Matalote means that it sent some request and the verb that was requested
does not exist.
All right, so if I try get and then send again notes, I'm getting five hundred and I'm getting another
arrow.
All right.
Oh, we're getting some good arrows, have this concept of good arrows where it's good to see these
arrows and understand how to fix them.
Right.
So this one is saying that system that takes Jason is giving an exception because a potential cycle
is detected.
So the background to this is that because of the dependency on hotel, hotel has a dependency on country
and country has that dependency back to hotel.
So what it is saying is that, well, I'm getting hotel, which is country and country as a hotel.
So I'm seeing a lot of data going from side to side.
So I'm let's fix this one.
I've encountered this one before, so let's just go ahead and fix this.
To do that, we need a library managed to get packages and we're going to be getting the new soft Dorjee
Sun, but not that one we want.
The Microsoft is beyond that.
Let me just type in Newton soft.
That's not the one we want.
We want this one, the one that is optimized for our purpose, right.
So I'm just going to go ahead and install that one.
All right, and once it has been installed, what we need to do is go to our startup and we're going
to honor our controllers, we're going to add new htun soft Jason.
There we go.
And define some options.
So all lammed R.O..
I mean, you can call it option if you want any token is fine lambda arrow and then define that all
p dot serialize zero, those serializer settings dot reference loop handling is equal to and I'll just
break the line so don't get too far off screen.
So the serializer settings, the reference loop handling is equal to Newton's soft on the reference
loop handling and then that's an item so on to say ignore.
So where do you see that.
We're basically seeing where you missed the reference loop happening.
I don't know, make a big deal out of it, just ignore it, turn a blind eye and let the program run.
All right.
So another thing and I'm just going through and correcting any little mistakes that I made here.
We're calling it.
What I didn't do was we to Cardinal, whenever we're calling on asynchronous function or something,
that's a task.
Make sure we all wait.
All right.
So let's try this again.
So going back to Posman, we're going to try and send one more.
And this looks a little bit better.
There we go.
Status 200, OK.
All right.
So once again, our status 200 is a universal sign that everything is OK.
And instead of us having to see Stuto code, they just give us some method for it.
Unfortunately, they don't have a method for the 500, or at least I haven't seen one as yet.
So that is why this one looks that way and we can see OK with the data to be returned and it will automatically
be serialized into.
There we go.
All right, so notice that we have each property coming back and hotels that's empty for no right,
because we didn't include the hotels, what we can do that later on.
So that is how we handle it now.
We have one more modification to make, and that is to do the mapping.
So remember that we don't want to return the actual domain object.
So it is right.
No gets all these returning country and country is the database object.
What we want to return is the old.
So we want to return contra deal and then well later on we'll see how we can extend the deal to be a
bit more ah make it make sense as to why I'm going to go through all of this trouble, because clearly
the data model, the domain model as a return type worked, but then we still want that segregation.
So I'm going to just see country or we're going to map to it.
So we need our autom upper in order to do that and to get out of mopper.
I have to define a private read only called off type.
I'm upir, so I just go ahead and include that and then do the injection.
Right.
So we after we inject it, then we are going to separate the subnet.
So we're going to see var countries is equal to that call and then I'm going to have another variable
on that and call it Vasilis is equal to mopper dot map that I'm going to specify the data type.
I want to map it too, so I want to map it to a list of type country deal.
But which have to include a missing reference.
All right, and just close up the brackets and what I'm hoping is countries, which is already coming
back as a list.
All right.
So whatever data type it is that you're you're you're getting back, you have to make sure you map to
that appropriate data type and then all of that.
So it's just going to take all of the domain objects and convert them into country detail objects and
stored there.
So if I didn't specify a list, I would get an error because this is a list and I'm trying to.
Well, it would it would give an error regardless.
It may not be a syntax error, but you can see that the data type is not quite what I'm expecting because
I need a list.
Right.
So just be very explicit inside of this map section.
That's your mapping a list of this or you're getting that.
I hope to to at of that data type.
And then instead of returning the country's will return results, which is of type country deal.
So at this point, if it is that we wanted to leave out some details or include more details, we could
have defined those additional features in here, doing whatever calculations we wanted to do in here.
And then they would never really see what's in what's coming directly from the database.
What we would have sanitized it, transformed it, embellished it as much as we want before we return
the data.
So let's just go ahead and test and make sure that this one works and then we're done with this task.
So back to Posman, we're going to see Sind, so it's going to hit the same method and right now let's
bring it up.
So here's proof that is bringing about something different because remember, hotels was at the bottom
of the list initially.
No idea.
Hotels named in short names.
So you know that the data is restructured only because it feels encouraged to are in a different order
than they are in the domain object.
Either way, we can see that it's still working and this is how it really should be.
So when we come back, we're going to look at how we can get a specific country based on maybe the idea.
Let's start with the idea.