Welcome back, guys.
So in this instance, we're going to be setting up our Lowgar utilities, so our weapon of choice for
this one will be Cerillo.
That being said, there are quite a few potential tools that are there.
Safe Cerillo of analog log fortunate.
At least those are three that I have used.
And I'm sure that there are others.
No, I am using Cerillo because it is touted as the fastest one out there and it is very popular in
the developer community.
But be very objective when choosing your tool and went to walk you through the configuration for serial
log and configuring.
The others may have some variations, but ultimately they are all geared towards doing the same thing,
which is logging your application activity.
No, let me explain what I mean by logging application activity.
There are times when unexpected events occur and if it occurs.
No, and you hear about it five minutes later or even the instant after it happens, sometimes it's
difficult to track, especially in this context where it's an API.
There is no real UI, no real feedback, except an error that has occurred.
So using this logging utility will be able to kind of make notes as to what action triggered, what
response that would have turned out to be an error response.
And even then, we can see the details offset error response.
So let's get started with setting up or logging.
So we need to get the libraries associated with Cerillo.
So I'm just going to.
Right.
Click on the project, go to manage to get packages, and then we're going to look in the Burrow's section.
So these are what we have installed.
Your versions may be different from mine, and if you are prompted to update, be careful that you should
be able to update the Microsoft and safely enough.
But just be careful and doing updates.
Be ready to roll back in case anything breaks.
So far, no will brose and we look for serial log dot is Venette course, so you'll see this one.
But that's not the one that we want.
We want dot is being that core.
This one has a library, is dedicated to our project type so we can go ahead and install that once again.
If the version is different, it shouldn't be a major problem.
And for all the problems that you're getting, just go ahead and answer in the affirmative.
And then once that is done, we're just going to head over to our program, DOT, see it and begin our
configuration.
So what we need to do is let the application know that we're going to be using Siri log instead of the
default logger that came with our project.
Because if you look in upsetting to see that there is some semblance of a logger there giving you some
configurations, but then this is not as robust as what we want.
Right.
So Cerillo kind of builds on top of that and it allows us to override.
So I'm going to go down to the eyeholes builder and the first thing I'm going to do is make a new line
under that on their line twenty and not use Andred Ceri log.
All right.
So once I do, that is going to let me know that I need to include a library, so use your logoff to
include that using statement, but then that's not all.
That's not something in the beginning zone that we have this library here we can go back and configure.
So I'm just doing getting this part out of the way because in the past, admittedly, I've forgotten
to put that in.
So let's just get that out of the way and proceed to modify our main application, which is going to
initialize our lugger when the application starts up.
And we're just going to put in some test log scenarios right here in the mean as our test case.
So what I want to do is configure a longer object, someone to see a log.
Dr. Lugger is equal to a new lugger configuration.
All right, so this is going to allow us to do is set up some defaults and expected behaviors for longer.
So I'm just going to be breaking line with each configuration that there are someone to see DOT.
And the first configuration I want is right to then dot again.
And then you see here they have different options.
So fired on the console coming out of the box.
But then they talk about sinks so you can download specific libraries so that you can log to a database,
you can log to other various files or file types based on how you need it.
But right now, I'm only interested in file later on when they setup our database and so on, we can
double back and add database logging to our suite of tools.
So right now I just see right to file and then this takes some parameters.
So I'm going to just name the parameters as I type them because I'm not necessarily going to type in
the specific order that they are required here in the constructors or in the overlord's or other.
Right.
So the first one that I'm going to write is POF Path means where should this file get created when it
needs to be created and path needs to be a stream.
So I don't want to set a set path and I'm just going to spend some time and explained here once again,
context rules.
One, you may want to have a central logging path because once you have deployed your API on a server,
you don't want to be spelling and guessing.
Where did the log go, where the log might be?
You might not want it in the actual project.
Right, because I had a log file here that had just deleted, admittedly.
Right.
But you may not want it in a project because somebody debugging the application may not necessarily
you don't necessarily want them to go into the project files on the server to be able to access the
logs.
So you can define somewhere on the network.
You can define on another drive.
You can just put in a path here where, you know, you want your log files to go.
So I'm going to see something like C colon slash slash and I'm going to say hotel.
So I know exactly which application I'm dealing with when I see the folder.
Water listings, slash slash logs.
All right, that's my path that I'm defining, so I'm not saying you must define this path if it's the
daedra for you, if you don't want to put in the logs, that's up to you.
Right.
But I'm just recommending that you make it easily accessible or accessible enough that you can find
it when you need to.
All right.
So see hotel listings, logs, and then I'm just going to give my love log dash not so I'm going to
explain that seemingly random dash in a few.
So that's my file path so far.
Lots of errors.
But let's just carry on and see what I'm just breaking lines so that we can see everything.
All right, this breaking line and making sure it didn't work, so that's it for the POF, the next
configuration I'm going to put in is the old template.
How do I want each line to look?
Right.
So I'm already prepared.
I'll put templates.
I'm just going to sit there and walk you through it.
So once again, named parameter or template kolon undivided.
I want would be timestamp something and put in a timestamp with that level of detail.
You can add or subtract.
You may not need all of these.
So that's your mom's the then our minute, second, minute, millisecond and whatever Z is.
Right.
So I've seen this, I've used this.
It's very detailed.
It gives you the exact time stamp.
Something happens.
You may not need that level of detail that's up to you.
And then the level what level warning is it is it's an information warning.
I'll go through that later on.
What is the message?
And then new line or an exception, if there's an exception included in Brooklyn, shall be exception.
So that's basically what that is doing.
The next parameter that I have is rolling intervals.
So that means what interval should that create?
A new file.
So that brings me back to that random dash that I have there, because what's going to happen here is
when I say rolling interval, that day means I'm going to plug dash and the date associated with each
day.
So this is good for segmenting.
You're a lot faster.
If somebody said something happened last Thursday, you can easily go and find the log file for Thursday
of last week and review it.
Otherwise, you're just going to end up with one big file that keeps on growing and growing and growing.
And then you're going to have years of logs in one file, which is to me that's inefficient.
At least when you have multiple files, you can manage the older ones, you can delete them safely or
move them to an archive safely and still keep that segregation.
So that's why I'm setting that rolling interview.
But you have different options.
You could do it by the day, by the hour, by the minute, by the year.
It's up to you.
All right.
The next one would be the restricted minimum level.
So I want to restrict to a minimum of log even level that information.
Right.
Meaning I don't need to see every little thing.
There are certain debug points like, oh, you know, this is starting initializing this and revving
up that.
I don't need to see all of that.
So the whole verbose here logs are depends on how much you log as well as what you set as the minimum.
So here I'm seeing only log at a minimum of information.
I need to include this library control, not enter.
And we include that library.
And then I'm missing this semicolon.
But before I put on the semicolon, let's just take a look here again, just so we're sure I'm not missing
a comma here.
So that's a good thing.
I took to review that.
And then the final thing here to get rid of all these errors would be to after this file, open and
close, as we see not longer.
So it's going to see a longer configuration.
All of this create the longer object.
No.
All right.
So now that we have it created, we can actually start using it.
So what I'm going to do here is wrap up or start process or I mean, the main lining, the main function
inside of a track.
And if you're not so familiar with that track catch, it means he's going to try to do something.
And if there is an exception, it will catch it and handle it accordingly.
So that's what we call a Sipson handy.
Right.
So what we're going to do is to try and run this line.
But before that, I'm going to log to the information or log a bit of information to say, hey, application
is starting so we can see exactly what time and all the details are required to know that the application
started at that point.
All right.
If we catch an exception.
And here I'm just qualifying exhibition with the objects that actually holds the exhibition, then I'm
going to see Lolled Feet Tall so you can log area, you can log information, you can log warning here.
It's fatal if the application stops working.
So I'm seeing log not fatal and I'm seeing this is the exception that caused the fetal log to be written.
And this is Mrs. Cissie application for the field to start.
So I'm seeing so that when somebody is reviewing the log, this is the result of or this is what happened
as a result of this exception, the logger will formatted it needs to format it and spit it out into
the file according to this.
All right.
And then after all of that, I'm just going to see finally finally means after you've handled with the
attrite operation and got it done, everything is done.
What do I want to do here?
I'm seeing I just want to flush and close my log object.
So that's what's going to happen when we start our application.
So right now, I'm going to go ahead and press this play button up here, which is going to start up
our application that we can go to the log file and see what happens.
All right.
So now that the application is loaded and just so you can see, the browser will come up with Swagga,
we'll go through Swagga later on or too much about this.
It looks nice, but our focus here is on our log.
So we see our log here.
Application is starting and we see the log level and it's kind of formatted.
We thought it would be right.
So other things are actually writing to the log.
See, their application started so log that it was started.
So this is a starting this once you started writing again, see the exact timestamps, for what that's
worth.
Right.
We know the environment.
So you see logs provide certain details for us that we can't see when we're just looking at the browser
like this.
You never know that all of this happened in the background just by looking at this.
So that's it for us.
Setting up the logger, at least for now, literally set up our database and so on.
We can come back and add the function that we can log to the database also.