Welcome back, guys.
We're continuing our API development journey and we'll be exploring the put verb at this time.
Now, put is similar to the post, except it is mainly used to either create if it doesn't exist or
update if it does exist.
So let's get started and when we tested you, that will make a bit more sense to you.
So the first thing that I would want to do is to replicate the kind of restriction as to who can access
the to me.
If you can't create, then you shouldn't be able to update it.
Once again, context rules.
But I'm just going to authorize and I'm just going to authorize.
I'm not even going to make it rule based.
Right.
So the administrator can create.
But then once you're authorized, you can go ahead and create.
You can go ahead and update.
Sorry, regardless of your role.
All right.
So the next one would be HTP put.
That is our new verb.
And more or less, we're going to have the same return codes except be doing something differently for
this one.
So let me just comment this one out and when we get there, then we'll adjust it.
So we have our method stub and I'm just going to copy so I can move quickly with prepping this method
stub.
Right.
And this one will be update hotel.
No, in terms of the detail that will be used for hotel.
Well, firstly, we need the parameter for the ID.
You know, there are two schools of thought or maybe three schools of thought on this matter.
Let's say two school of thought.
Number one is that I need to have the ID in the euro, just like we had with the get right.
So I need to need you to pass and ID with the euro.
But then one school of thought would say that the DTL also needs to have the ID.
So that means the client needs to pass in the idea with the euro and depositing the body of data to
be updated.
Now that is one potential validation point where you would check if the idea that wasn't in your matches,
the ID sent over in the payload or the to and if there's a mismatch, then you return maybe.
But request.
All right.
So that is one method of doing it.
And I'm just talking you through it before I actually do it.
The other one would be that the DTA doesn't need to have the ID because the it is going to be in the
euro.
So I expect you to pass over the euro with the idea of the record you wish to update, and then you
just pass me the updated information and I apply it accordingly.
Now, that is also an acceptable train of thought.
They're both acceptable once again, context rules.
So some people feel more comfortable with the doublecheck having to ID the euro and the body and then
you check and then if they don't match, then you reject that.
And some people don't mind having it one place and just going along with the operation.
So we're going to take the approach where we have it one place and not in the deal.
Now, because of that, I could use that creates a lot of detail.
But then to me, that would kind of violate the single responsibility rule that I've been kind of promoting.
Because when you say create a hotel deal, it doesn't anybody reading the code that this is for creation,
why is it in the update now you have two options.
Again, you could either rename this to maybe something like absurd, where this detail serves the purpose
of creating and updating or inserting and updating.
Hence the portmanteau.
Absurd, right.
But then once again, still single responsibility depends on how strict do want to be.
You could also realize that you might have varying fields in the two details because what you would
accept for creation, you might not expose all of that for potential update.
So you want to consider all those things.
So what I would do is actually create a second detail.
So I created another one, I call it, of the total detail.
In this context, everything that is here for the creation is fair game for update.
All right.
So I'm not going to go ahead and create another one at all.
I did was just inherit.
So I'm just doing this because of the single responsibility concept that I have in mind.
I also want to make sure that when you see updated to detail, you know what it's for.
However, otherwise, what you probably want to do is just be more particular with the fields that you
expose in detail.
And we've seen where that can help with some control already.
So I'm just going to go ahead with that level of inheritance once again.
That's up to you.
We just want to write clean code and make sure it's readable at the end of the day.
Right.
So I'm taking the idea in the parameter and then I'm taking the fields for the update in the body of
the request.
So I'm going to start off with my validation.
Check someone to see if not model state dot is valid, if it is not valid or if the idea value sent
over is less than one, because I mean, it should be at least one right.
To be zero or negative.
So in either situation, I just want to log and return, but request that something is wrong with your
attempt.
Right.
And then we can move on to our try and catch.
And then we know that for the cat section, we're going to be logging the error as well as.
Turning the status, five hundred, right, so let us see what we're going to try.
No, in order to try, I need the original record that needs to be updated.
So what I have to do is actually see VAR Hotel is equal to a weight unit of work, not hotels that get
me the report cards put in my filter where the idea is equivalent to the idea coming in through the
parameter.
All right.
Then I can do another check, I can see if a hotel is equivalent to no.
So I could have done a search, maybe they passed into the ID 10.
I would left six hotels and a pass in 10 with something to update.
I'm going to try and find it, but I need to make sure that I actually found it right.
So then I would probably it's a bad request.
So let's say I do the same thing here, but in the buttocks section, I'm going to see submitted data
is invalid.
All right.
So there's no modesty there.
It's just a matter of those the record with that idea exists or not.
And you could actually even just extend the unit of work to do the exists.
But what I'm doing is just getting it one time.
If it if it's not, then we end it.
However, if it is not null, then we can go ahead and try to do our bit.
Now, a quick way to kind of equate the two would be to use the mopper.
Dot map.
And then I can see at this point what is the source, so the source series hotel and then I'm going
to see I want it to be no, I'm sorry.
The source would be the detail.
My apologies.
So hotel detail is the new source because hotel detail has the latest information.
And then I'm going to say hotel to the right.
So if we look at this mumper overload, it takes two things the source and the destination.
And then what it's going to do is just map what's in the source to the existing destination.
So effectively, we just said whatever is in this, put it in that if there are two things that are
not equal, then please update this one with the feeds coming from the detail.
Right.
And then we can all see unit of where the problem is that we did not do any tracking.
So if we were doing tracking, we could have just said save.
But we are not trucking stuff to c update and then pass in hotel.
Right.
And then we.
You know, it's all work.
So this one extra line of code, not too bad.
So the thing is that I remember I was explaining that with the update method, what we did was to see
please pay attention to whatever entities here.
I touch it and change it state to modify it.
So know that it's modified.
So when we save, it will be kind of in the register to be saved or updated.
Right.
If we had not or if we had made the tracting optional, then we wouldn't have had to take that extra
step of seeing updates.
We could have just done the change and see of the because trucking is actually by default.
So I'm just explaining that a little bit to because I didn't mention it.
So let us after we save, we can return the content.
So no content seems like a bad reply, but it's really a tool for which is anything in the 200 range
is good.
Right.
So that's a good because I don't have anything to tell you.
Like, OK, you sent an update.
OK, there is nothing more to do.
You're good to go.
Right.
So that's what the content is really for.
So coming back to the one that we commented, it's not just status two or four.
So let us test that, so just to bring attention to what Strugar is doing, you'll see that each type
is nice, the color coded.
So if the word wasn't enough, then you see the color code put is nicely stated there.
And there's already teal with the feels and it's expecting an ID value in the parameters.
All right.
So let's use Postnet and I'm going to go right back to the last hotel that we created.
So this was our successful post attempt and we got it back.
So the ID value is six.
So I'm going to say put is my verb and I'm passing in six, says the ID value, and then I'm going to
put a comma.
This was misspelled.
It's a tiny, tiny change here.
But let's us see.
The comma underrating isn't really five, but it's four point eight for MoonPies Jamaica Grand Resort
and of the countries, Jamaica.
So let's leave that.
So let's go ahead and send and see what happens.
All right.
Method not slow and oh, I think I know why we didn't put on the parameter alone here on the put.
So the same way that we have this on the HTP get out to specify on the put that it should take that
parameter.
So apologies.
Let's just add that and let's try this again.
So buckin Posman.
I think I should get the for one this time.
All right.
That's better.
So the four or five I'm not allowed means that either you have something wrong with the request or your
endpoint needs to be fixed to match.
Holder should look.
So just know that's what we ran into.
We had the request properly, but then the endpoint was lacking.
All right.
So it's good to see these little things along the way so that when they happen, you can take control
of the situation.
So what we need to do is get a token and I believe I still have my user request over here.
So it's really cool with Bowsman.
You can always go back and get previous requests.
So let me just grab my token, come back over here, add it to the authorization header and then try
this again.
And it's hitting my and since our break point there.
All right.
So let's continue.
And there it is, tool for no content.
So it has successfully processed the request, but is not returning any content with no content.
But once again, a tool for it is a good return type.
So let us know.
Go over to our previous get and see what happens.
And I have a token.
So let me just go ahead and put this token here and do the get and then we will see.
All right.
There's our Cummo and there is a rating change to four point eight.
So as far as are concerned, the put works.
No, just building on what the put does and doesn't do.
You see, if you miss of something, let's see.
You have some features that are not required.
All right.
Right.
No, it's hard to test, but I'm going to go ahead and modify this detail.
So let me go over to create D2 and I'm going to see that the address field is not required.
All right.
I want to restart.
So why this restart?
Let me just explain what we're about to do.
The put is always going to replace the data.
The only thing it doesn't replace is the idea pretty much.
Right.
So any time you're going to do a put, you have to be mindful that whatever data is there, it is going
to use it to replace.
If I don't provide an address, let's address all of this.
It's no longer required.
I don't provide an address.
What I'm doing the put.
I'm doing the update.
Right.
Same hotel and I'm doing the update and I send.
All right, so I'm getting a tool for no content, but look at what happens to my data.
So notice we had an address volume.
No.
Address is no.
So you have to be careful whenever you're using these kinds of updates or at least to put because it's
always going to replace it with the data that it got.
So it is on you to make sure that your validations represent the data quality that you really want from
your client application, whether you are building the client or it's a third party who is building
the client.
The app is yours and you have to set that standard because it not being required load and all of it
to be there know once again that could be good or bad based on your situation, but that is how the
pot will work.
So I'm going to encourage you right now to pause, replicate the put endpoint for the country's controller.
And then we're going to look at something else as it relates to the port and how we can enter a bit
more data than where I am right now.
All right.
So we're back.
And I hope you paused and attempted it yourself, but I already did the update country, and I'll just
walk you through it quickly.
There's nothing here that's out of the ordinary compared to the hotels.
Everything is fairly standard.
You have to create contra detail, which I did.
There we go.
It's a good thing I'm doing this review.
All right.
So it did contribute to contribute to and everything else just looks the same way.
No.
One thing that I want to point out with the update contra detail is that I have included this property,
which is a list of hotels.
All right.
So, yes, arguably I could put it here and then remove it from this one and then let the country need
to inherit from the update contra details since it does all of these on the list.
So this would get everything.
Yes, you could do that.
But then this is just driving home my point that you really want to kind of keep your details as unique
as possible, because then, you know, you may have shared feels sure, but then you may have unique
files also along the way.
Know, the relevance of this list of hotels is that I can actually use my port to update a company and
also insert new hotels are related hotels because remember that hotels.
This means that one country has a list of hotels or one country as many hotels, which is why we can
reference them by list here.
All right.
So let's explore what that would look like.
So if I go over to my swagga documentation and then look at the potential pillared you see here where
they're showing me that I can put in the name, the short name and then an array of hotels, and then
I can put in details for the hotel.
And of course, the hotel has potential details for the country.
And then this is what they really meant when they said it could become sightly because it's just one
big thing after another, after another.
However, we're going to try this and we're going to insert a new hotel we're sorry, a new country
with a new hotel.
So I'm going to just duplicate this port so I can certainly say duplicate tab since I already have it
there.
Before I do that, let me see all of the countries that I have.
So I don't really have any tests with country.
So let me get all my countries so I can see my options.
So I have Jamaica, Bahamas and Cayman Islands and see if we need to update Cayman Islands because of
Cayman Island.
It should be islands of cosmetics.
But let's just go ahead and update that.
So I'm going to take let me just get my bearings.
So I'm going to take the payload from the sample right.
From our Soga and then the country's.
Sorry, the countries I had that I want to update, I'm just trying to find where that was the countryside's
three, so the name will be Cayman Islands.
The come the end point would be country slash three.
All right, the short name still S.I.
So once again, you have to provide the value that you expect to have there afterwards.
All right.
And then I'm going to go inside of the hotel section, remove anything that I really don't want.
Right.
As a matter of fact, let me go back over to the detail.
I just noticed that I'm listing out hotel detail here.
So I did say we could consolidate.
But here's a good reason I'm not consolidating.
I said hotel detail, hotel detail then puts in the ID.
But if I'm doing an insert, I'm updating Cayman Islands while I want to insert a new hotel automatically,
which means I don't need the added value.
So this DTA is actually incorrect.
What I should have here is create a hotel DTL, which is a better representation of the data I wish
to collect and that would also get rid of the excess feels like the country and the extended list of
hotels.
So let's try that again.
All right.
So now when I look in Swiger and I look at the the schema, that looks much better.
So you see details are very important.
What do you require from your user?
Make sure you expose only that.
So I'm going to take this corrected payload, go back to Boston, and this will be far less confusing
for me.
Right.
So let's try this again.
This is going to be Cayman Islands with a capital I write.
The name is still S.I.
I have to provide that.
And then in the hotels section, I can actually list all the hotels or objects of hotels.
So this square market means area.
Then the current embrace encapsulates all the object properties and I can see come up and list so I
can through comma and continuing to put them in.
Right.
So here I'm going to put in the Ritz Carlton and its address is Grand Cayman.
It has everything on five and another one, the local hotel.
So these are actually hotels in Grand Cayman.
You can look them up if you want to verify that.
However, I'm not going to specify the countryside.
All right.
So I'm actually going to remove your ID, but then I do have it as required.
So I'm going to remove it in the payload.
And what I'll do is make the change in the code itself for the DTL.
Let's just go over there and make it not required, at least just for this experiment and let us try
that.
So change made.
We have the list of hotels.
They're not referencing any country at the moment.
However, they are underneath the country's payload.
We have the country ideastream.
So let us send.
And I'm getting a tool for no content, so let me go and check.
So let me get the list of hotels and see what came back.
All right, here we go.
So we have the local hotel coming back with an idea seven and the Ritz Carlton coming back with an idea
of eight, and both of them are part of country three or keep in mind.
So you see, that is how you can actually use the put.
So the put will see, does this thing exist?
If not, I will create it.
And the only way it knows it exists is if the ID value is provided.
So when there's no ID value is going to say, well, this doesn't have an I.D. so I will go ahead and
create it.
However, because of our constraints that we put on our end point, we are not allowing people to just
use the port to create because we do verify that ID value must be present or have, you know, a sensible
added value must be present before we move on.
So those are the constraints they can use to make sure that the port operates.
So you want it to.
However, its global operation is very versatile.