You guys will come back, so we already settle for Azura cones and all we want to actually deploy.
So before I do that, though, I want to make a slight configuration change to where our files will
be going, because in Asgeir, there is no CGI, there's no local draft.
So what I wanted to do is let Cerillo create a folder within the whole folder structure for the project,
and that's where the logs will be written so that when we go to Azor, we don't have to worry about
any file path or get to fancy.
So let's go over and publish now, that being said, I'm just doing this locally for simplicity.
There are tons of more outlets that I see a robust logging mechanisms that we can take advantage of.
I'm just doing this because I want to find the most cost effectively, because the other ones cost money
as you add on.
Or so, let's just go to publish and we're going to set up a new publisher.
So I already have a published profile for local deployment, which is a Holeproof.
Right.
So I can actually just rename this one so I know exactly what it is for its profile safe.
All right.
Well, then I want a new one.
And this one is going to be the Azira profile.
So what I want to do is deploy to one Azura up service, know if you if you don't know that much about
Osram cloud, what happens is that you can deploy an application as us on an application, as a service
kind of constraint, meaning you don't have to worry about the server or anything, just like a nice
container for you and put your code there and then they will host it.
And that's where you get like a SAS, right.
Or rather, that would be the services platform as a service.
So they're providing the platform as a service for you to just put your app on it and it will just run.
So that's what they mean by the service.
And then what they want to buy a Windows or Linux, we'll use Windows.
Otherwise you can do it a container or to a container industry or to a virtual machine.
So basically the same kind of considerations that would have made with its deployment to either your
machine or a network machine.
You would have to do those kind of considerations against a VM in Azure because it's the same thing
as just a virtual machine CRM server and a whole will to choose the platform as a service, the service
and then click next.
And then this will, though it may prompt you to get connected, so you'll have to sign in order to
send in.
So it just for me, it shows you the subscription resource group and I don't have any of those.
So I'm just going to go ahead and press this plus sign to start building up services.
They ask for the name, I'm not going to change the name.
And then I have a few resource groups here from past projects, but I'm going to create a brand new
one.
I'm going to call it Hotel Listing API.
So that's the name of that resource group and then the hosting plan here, I can leave it on the default,
but then they do have a free hosting plan.
And based on where I am in the world, e US two is my best bet and I choose free.
So you might be somewhere else in the world.
You choose the region that's closest to you.
But based on where I am, EastWest is my region of choice.
Now choose the free deployment.
Click okay.
And then create.
And then after that process is done we can go ahead and click next and then we can refresh.
No apologies, this management, so I don't want any management, I just skip this step and then we
click.
So the next screen you're showing us what our side you are is going to be.
So whatever the OP name is that we sit there that Dot Azera websites dot net because it's free, they
give us a subdomain and we can always go ahead and buy our own domain if we want, but we won't get
that far ahead.
But because we do have a service dependency on a database, they're seeing what they need to configure
your database for connectivity purposes.
Right.
So I need to go and configure and then they'll ask us, do we want an on premises secure server database
or will it be easier?
So once again, we'll go with the POS option where they are just giving us a service in the cloud and
we just need to connect.
So we have to go ahead and create a brand new instance of a database service hosting Nemoto Service
Stevic kind of fill out some things.
I'm going to put it in the same resource group as the Hotel Listing API.
There we go.
And then database server.
I have to create a new one.
So it will kind of fill out some things, but I'm going to have to put in my administrative details.
So and the password part of it is relatively strict.
So just make sure you have a special card and a capital letter and a number and you should be fine once
you exceed seven characters.
So once you put in all of those details, you can go ahead and call it autofill, what it needs to fill,
but then it does need to, one, create the database server and then you would have access to connect
to it.
Right.
And that is completed.
So let's just go click next.
And then what it will do is say, OK, this is the database connection string name.
What is the user name?
So we have to put back the user name that we just use to create the database stuff and the password.
And then it will keep it in the Azor upsetting section.
We can choose the Kevo, but I'll just leave that as the default settings there.
And then if we want, we can actually view the connection string value so I can actually show you guys
that.
So the datasource this is the connection to the actual database in Azura, right.
So if I just copy that just for my own purposes, then it shows the initial catalog.
That's the database name.
The user I.D. will be travois at that, that whatever that domain and the password.
I use a simple password, of course.
And I realized that you use a more secure password so that we can just go ahead and click next and we
don't have to touch anything here and just say finish.
All right.
And now we can click publish.
And this might take a while because it has to create a few resources.
And this is seeing your publishing the application without bundling the runtime, checking the runtime
compatibility so we can give that to the end result of that check.
However, is it launching the browser and sending me this five hundred error or so at least we know
that it is responding.
So the API is there, but we still have a few things that we need to do.
So let's start off by going to our portal.
So only just manage in a zero portal.
We get navigates into this page showing us the application running as your art.
So we know it's definitely not Adelita, it's there.
We click brose.
It's going to show us the Yurok are protected by GPS and we're getting by that five hundred.
So we're not we're not any better off than we were before, but at least we can confirm a few things.
No, if we go down to configuration it will kind of show us some of the things like our connection string.
Right.
Or remember that connection string and that hidden value, at least from this connection string.
I can see the server for the database, so I'm just going to copy that.
Remember I showed you earlier, so I'm just going to copy that.
And then in the management studio, I'm going to try and connect to it's just going to click that plug.
If he already had it open, that's fine.
If not, then you launch a management studio and then you put in the server name and whatever credentials
were there and click connect.
And it will just promptly to.
And so what happens is that the firewall is seeing I'm not allowing access to the database from any
other source that's outside of us.
You're so right.
Know, what I want to do is just sign in and then it will add an exception for the IP address that I
am using.
So that's an important security feature.
So I will be behind this IP address.
Somebody from their own home with a different IP address won't be able to get to the database unless
they sign in and verified, just like I'm doing now.
So I'll just go ahead and click, OK?
Of course there are ways to allow access from everywhere, but we don't need to do that right now.
And then when I look in the list of databases, we see our database.
I'm just confirming that our database is.
But look at this.
There are no tables.
And what I'm going to do is edit the profile and go to settings.
And we actually skipped this step.
I guess we're too eager, right?
So we did not do the migration steps, apply this migration on publish and we already use their own
the connection stream with the new Tostin database at runtime.
So that's not really necessary to take again.
But that's fine.
And I'll see even that.
I just click publish again.
And if we just look at the log, you see adding database and then you see here, it gives us the some
indication of some scripting happening.
So let's double check.
And what happens this time around is that because we said apply the migration's it's actually went ahead
and filled all the tables for us.
Right.
So that's the real important part of it.
So we didn't have to manually the script.
But once again, it would be prudent of you in our real production life scenario to control this process
a bit more than we can do on our personal projects and in our personal time.
All right.
So you can check them out, of course, on deploying on controlling production in the environments.
But for this, we're just we just want to get our API open running and understand all the systems work
together.
So this is our database currently functioning on our as your server.
So let's go back to our consulate instead of Koutou, go to the side of the road and then remember that
we said put the love at the same root as a filesystem.
So that's why we have access to our loved folder right here, which will show us our log since we've
been doing this deployment.
So if I just go ahead and download, it will open it up in a new browser session.
And I just want to see why it through the most recent error.
So it says something went wrong with the argument, not the exception, some strong reference error
and some encoding that is supposed to be happening in service extensions, line forty six.
So if we just go and look at the code and see what exactly is happening on that line, it is where we're
configuring our JWT and you see that we're doing all of this and this is where it says the encoding
failed and it failed because we're looking for key and key is really an environment variable called
key.
So remember that we just had to set.
That'll be nice.
We have to do the same thing as you're right.
So what I'm going to do is go back to our management dashboard, go down to configuration, and then
from here I can see a new application sitting.
So I'm going to see a new application.
Setting is key along with the values.
So, I mean, I can continue to use that same value.
I'm going to probably just use a simpler value.
But then for consistency between the environments, you probably want the same thing.
So it's, you know, one or the other.
They use a simpler one in dev bodies, a complicated one in production, or you use one part environment.
So for, you know, security and separation of roles, situations, a developer might not be able to
just go into production and manipulate anything because he probably doesn't know.
But for simplicity, I'm just going to keep the same key across.
And I click, OK, go ahead and save that continue.
And it will it will say it will restart the application.
That's fine.
Go ahead and restart.
And once that is restarted, I'm going to go to over if you go to Brose.
All right.
So we know that we can't brose anywhere.
We're getting this.
So at least we're not getting a five hundred.
This is the same error that we've got.
If you went through the highest deployment, that's what we got when we went to the root.
So if I say slash Swagga, then it will lead me to the Swagga doc being hosted on our as your website.
Then I'm just going to go ahead and do a quick test.
So I'm going to try to get the countries execute.
And then I have successfully retrieved all of the countries currently in the database.
So that means if I tried to use post one, I'm just going to copy this URL, go over to Postman and
I'm just going to create a new workspace because sometimes you can overcrowd one.
So I'm just going to create a new workspace.
Called it as your.
And then what I'm going to do over here is just do all my azure related requests.
So country I want to get there's no authorisation tag.
But then as you can see, you can get all the countries right off the bat through this.
Let's try one of those registration items and then to to do something that is secure.
So I'm just going to be flipping between the original workspace where I had the requests already and
this new one.
So I'll just go over to the post.
I just copy this and instead of bothering you with creating it, I just did it.
So the new endpoint would be whatever the website name is, Slash and then API.
So that's why I didn't remove it since the Iast deployment.
I left it because it makes more sense here.
Write a column, slash log in and then we can send and I got an error because I had the login payload
instead of the register payload.
So I apologise.
So we're doing our register and we have the cart payload with the email password and this is the same
one that we tested with from when we're on our local.
So I just want to verify that everything still works as it works and we get our tool to accept it.
So that's good.
We're on the right track.
So what I can do is repeat the login request.
So I just click that, bring about the login request and then we can send get our token.
Excellent.
And then what we'll do is attempt the delete our creation or something that we know.
We had said that one of those authorized and of course I'm not bothering you with forming the link,
but you know that you have to form the link properly.
The endpoint is API slash photo with the ID.
It's the delete.
I thought and then we add our authorization, betoken and the token that we just got about from the
log in and then when we clicks we retrieve our tool for no content response.
So if I go to the database just to verify once again our Azor database, we can verify that we no longer
have a photo with the ID three.
So we know that we can register user to our No publicly deployed API.
So if I made this link any more, any easier to remember than you could actually browse through it.
Granted, by the time you're doing this, listen, this probably no longer exists.
But the point is that this is all you can publish your API to the world.
And using slogger, you made it easy for anybody to be able to come by and say, oh, that is how this
endpoint works and these are all of those.
And you see that we retained our country V two for, you know, and we're talking about versioning,
our APIs.
We retain the weather forecast default API.
But of course, no, we can clean up all of those things.
And some cleanup's that I would suggest would be like with country and hotel, really and truly, I
should have called it the endpoints, countries and hotels.
So the controllers really should have been countries controller and hotels controller.
But that's semantics.
That's just a matter of presentation.
At this point.
We can confirm that our functionality is up and running.