Or Guess will start looking at teaching in this lesson, know a little background as to what aging is
and why we need it, paging talks about segmenting the data that is being returned.
So right now, what we're doing is we're doing one big keyword, getting all of the values in a certain
table all at once.
And while it may look fine because we only have, what, three countries and five hotels, when you
deploy this API for international usage and you're actually storing hotels in 200 countries across the
world, you will realize that your data is going to grow exponentially.
And then you will definitely need to, one, protect yourself and your system from too many requests
and the burden of serving up that much data all at once to potentially many clients, as well as protecting
the clients from having to develop ways internally to segment the data because they're getting back
too much all at once.
So paging is a nice, effective and efficient way to segment the data allowing the client to see I would
like this many records and then we just return according to what they asked for.
So I started off with Posman on the screen because what we want from our client is that when they're
making that service call, they would pass in parameters to say something like the page size that they
would want.
So page size would mean how many records?
So let's say they say 10 and then they would say and I would like the page number.
So that's a page number.
So I can either type in the link or just put it on here in the Palms section to page number would be
equal to something like one or two.
So we need to know implement code to see that if they ask for a page size of ten, that means they want
ten records.
But then to ask for page three or something, that's not page one.
That means they would like the required 30 upon to record 40 or something like that.
So that way, if they're displaying 10 hotels at that time on their pages, when when they go to the
next page, on the next page, they would just increment this and they know they would get 40 to 50,
then 50 to 60, etc..
So if we have five hundred hotels, at no point would anybody be getting all five hundred.
They would only be getting chunks of fifty or whatever it is that they are asking for.
Of course we can limit the maximum.
So what we need to do is start off by creating a new model.
So I'm going to call this model, request firearms.
So just a class and it will just be a model outlining the constraints or, you know, the parameter
names that there are a lot of passing.
Right.
So before I do anything, I want to initiate or declare a maximum size of fifty so nobody can request
more than 50 records at the time.
Of course, this is mine or yours.
So if you want to limit it to ten, you want to it to 100.
That's entirely up to you.
Do what's best for your system.
So we're sitting that 250 right now and then we have another property that we're going to call page
number and another one.
This one is private that we're going to call bid size.
All right.
So the these are just defaults.
So I'm seeing that the default page number, in case none was specified, the default page number will
be one and the default size will be 10.
Right.
But then I'm going to make the page size a public version of the page size where I'm going to manually
see get and here I'm going to return on the score page size.
But then we can also set the value for page size to be equal to.
And I want to see value being greater than Mark Spitz size.
So this is a question I would just use a Turner upwards to see if it is greater than the maximum size.
Then we send the data.
So that's why we did that.
Right.
So if they requested more than ten more than 50 records.
So the default is 10, right?
If they're requested more than 50, then we just send back 50.
Otherwise we send volume.
So value here is a keyword, as you see highlighted in blue, just like it is for return.
So value would be whatever value we're sitting here.
All right.
So here we just have a default getset our initializing it to one.
So it.
There are no real constraints here on this because we don't know what age they're at, however, or
this one we're seeing always return the size.
So when you get to return what that is, however, when sitting it if the requested size is greater
than 50 or whatever value you put there, then we return that maximum.
Otherwise then we can go ahead and return that value.
Now, the next thing I want to do is to modify the controller, so at this point I'm going to just modify
I get confused because like I said, I don't want at any point somebody being able to just get all the
records out once that that would be problematic for my system.
So what I'll do is modify, get countries.
So this endpoint is no longer just gets all countries, but now we're going to see from query.
So you see in from body being put here, I believe when we were doing the post you see from Buddy.
So that request would have the data in the body.
Right.
So we would have done that.
Let me see if I can find any of those with the body.
There we go.
So that's the from body that it takes from that.
However, from query will look inside of the query string.
That is being possible for the Paramount, so that's why I called it to request Parramore parameters,
right.
So from programs, we're looking for fields that match the names as outlined in our request model.
So it's the same kind of concept as the deal request pirogues.
So I'm just going to call these requests firearms used the word Perm's as a keyword.
So, no, we're looking for our query.
Query string, sorry, that will have in fields for bid size and the page number.
So now the next development will be involving passing that information down to or get all commands.
Remember that in our units of work or all this saying, oh, just give back everything anyway.
Right?
So what I'm going to do is pass the word power down to the get all.
And of course, that is going to require an override.
All right.
I don't want to get rid of the original guitar.
It may serve some purpose otherwise.
So I'm just going to create another one.
Right.
So let's go back over to our unit of four units over the generic repository.
And we have get all as it is.
So what I'm going to do is create a brand new declaration.
I notice of this new data type here eyepatch list.
You'll see more about that in a few.
So I have tasks get all and I'm just getting the includes as well as the request parameters.
So I'm not even going to allow them to do the filtering and all of that stuff because we're not really
interested in that, right?
No, we're getting all.
But we want to facilitate the page.
So let me just go ahead and include what I can include, where we clear this data type deposit so we
can leave that alone.
And since that is knowing in the interface, I need to go and update the generic repository so that
we can implement it.
All right.
So now that it is there, what code do I put in?
So really and truly I'm doing everything that I'm doing here?
Well, maybe not every single thing because I have no autobio, but I'm just going to take that code,
based it down here and then return.
All right.
So I'm just going kind of slowly so we can see exactly what's happening.
So there's no expression.
I can take all the expression.
We do have facilities for the include, but we don't have any autobio.
So I'll take that one note.
Now, what I need to add is.
A facility to actually, well, filter our peek exactly what I want from court, because this is still
just returning everything.
So at this point, I'm just going to go ahead and take care of this error, which is the list.
And if you look at the suggestions of the library, I want is not there.
So I'm going to go over to new get and get it manually.
So management to get packages to browse.
And then I'm going to look for eggs, not paged lists.
So this is a very prominent library that helps with paging.
So we'll just see expanded list and make sure.
Go ahead and install that.
I know that it's installed we can go back and try and take care of those errors.
So this is a positive.
You know, I can say using Eckstut page lists, so go ahead and do that.
So making the page list itself is very possible.
But then why do all of that when there's a library?
Right.
So go to the generic and let's include all the missing references.
All right.
And then the cool thing, though, is that I don't it's complaining because we have a page list as a
return type doing two list here.
So it gives us an extension function that allows us to see a two page list async and then the two page
list will take two parameters.
It wants a page number and the page says, where are we going to get that from our request parameters?
All right.
So actually, I want to even take the null off this and frankly, I'm going to take off the interludes.
So let me just throw a little refactor, because I'm thinking about it when we're getting like in pages,
when they're paging the data, they probably don't need to include anything about the country or anything
else.
Right.
Because they're just listing it.
When when you get the details of something, then you probably want to include.
So, I mean, that's that's up to you.
Maybe I'll leave.
That includes because I could see value in its value.
That includes bullets or, of course, firearms.
We definitely want that to be mandatory for this version.
So let me put this at the front.
I think that's why that red line is there, because any time you have the apartment is listed, you
have to have the nullable wants to that end.
So they will also request sperm's so back to the task on query as not tracking the two page list and
then were passing for programs that which one to settle on first the page number.
So it's important to always look at all the requirements to make sure you're putting the cart value
and then they want the page size.
And yes, I do have somewhere you can get that from.
All right.
And then I think this area is there because we need to be seen.
There we go.
So, no, we can get a page list of anything that we have in our database.
And I need to go and correct my repository where I made this.
Not nullable, and of course, I need to move it to the front.
All right, so you see, as you build on your API, tiny changes are made along the way.
They're actually required.
But, you know, once you know what you're doing or you get on top of it, so you just build and make
sure that you haven't messed up anything else I see here.
All right.
So they're saying that get all.
There is none.
OK, so this is because I'm still using the phones on guitars, right?
No, we have to get our functions to distinguish between the two of them.
What I love to do is pass in exactly the parameters that the one I know I want needs.
Right.
So.
Well, actually, that's not working because the other one still takes more than one, so it's still
confused as to which one it is am dealing with.
So what I'm going to do, I probably should have done this from the start.
I just changed the name and do a new one right.
Someday to try to be generic and it backfired.
So let me just call this get paged list that I think that's clear enough.
So in the generic repository, we do that in the generic repository.
We made that change as soon as I find it.
There we go and there we go.
So let us take this for a spin.
So we only done this the countries.
And the fact is that we've done it one place and it's that easy to go over to any other controller and
meet that change because the hard work was already done.
Right.
So that's one of the advantages of having a clean architecture.
And I have an error here and that URL is just my about, so I just fix that part.
So let's try that again.
And when we get to this point, no, let us try to bring back country with bits 50 and page number five.
I'm actually going to set a breakpoint here so that we can see the Parramatta's coming in.
Or maybe let me just put it in 39.
All Let's try that.
So send.
All right, so it's hitting the breakpoints, so that means the request was recognized.
Let's see if we're getting the request palms there.
We get five and 15.
All right.
And that will continue.
And we know that we're going to get back all our countries.
The request is for a size and a page number that doesn't exist.
Only have two hotels so.
Well, two countries, sorry.
So that not one is the first indication that this is working.
So let's try this again.
I want page number one with page size two.
I only have two countries, remember, deleted one.
Right.
Let's try that.
So when we send we only get the two right.
If I requested page one with only one that I'm only getting back one, if I requested page ten, which
means skip to the tenth record.
So what our library page did was it automatically modified the query with a tick and a skip.
Let me just jump over there.
So in link or entity, framework or other, you can actually say something like query dot and you can
do a tick.
So you take this number right.
Return to specify a number of contiguous elements and then you can say skip where where it says bypass
a number.
So that's really what it is doing.
So when we send the page size or let's say a page number 10, it means skip 10, skip 10 records.
Right.
Or skip 10 times this number of records and then bring back this many something like that.
So all of that it sounded confusing is really not that difficult to write.
I'm probably making it so more difficult than it really is.
But the reality is that we didn't even have to do all of that because of our library doing that for
us, which is two pages does that automatically.
And that is why it takes those three parameters.
Maybe I can't go into that the class behind it.
So that's fine.
So, yeah, so that is how we implement pages.
So obviously you're probably not seeing the full part of it because I only have very few records.
However, if we see that maybe 50 hotels into this database and we said we want page five and only ten
records, then it would say, give me that.
Well, I think my math is off there, but I hope you get the gist.
So right now we have paging enabled in our API.
And once again, this is built to protect both yourself and the requesting application.
And if these parameters were not provided, then by default, we have told the request per class that
the value should be fall to page number one and a maximum of 50.