All right, guys.
So after setting up your environment and I'm sure you visited that everything works, know, what we
want to do is actually publish the site to or I know before we do that, we have a few steps that we
have to complete.
And one code change in particular that I want to do is regarding the Swagga USA in the startup page
where we have used Swagga UI.
I want to kind of change this endpoint is generated and the reason is that I have witnessed that once
it is published, the POV rules kind of change.
So what we want to do is make it look something more like this.
We're using our UI or see Lambda talk and then we have the current embraces making it an object and
we're just going to kind of qualify the base path a bit to see string that is no longer whitespace,
see that root prefix and then we're going to see dot org.
So what happens is that when the root prefix changes relative to if it's in development like it is now
or if it's published, the the path needs to look a little bit different.
So what we're doing is just seeing either put one or two dots and then we're just going to prepend that
to our existing path, which was there before, and hotel listing API.
All right.
So you can go ahead and make that quick change and just to double-Check that it still works.
We can run it and we're still seeing our Soga API documentation.
And you'd also notice that the URL has not part when we look at we get this.
So when we go to air, is that the that link might look slightly differently, which is why we went
through all of what we just did.
All right.
So now that we've confirmed that is working, another very important thing that we want to do is create
the database.
So in our database server.
So whether you're using a skill express or you're using developer, you can just go to that particular
instance that you hope to host the APIs, what database on, and then you just want to create a new
database.
So you want the database to be present for when we do our migrations.
Right.
So because I don't want any typos undertaking to DoubleClick the database name from the from the hosts
from the opposite thing.
Sorry.
And then just go ahead and use that name to create the database and then you can just go ahead and confirm
that the database is there.
It's empty right now.
No, don't worry too much about it.
But this is the initial deployment.
Right.
So what we want to do is publish so we can go ahead.
Click our project.
We see publish that and then we can choose our target.
So we have quite a few options here.
You can publish to Azura, which we can look at later on to Docker a folder, F.T. This would come in
handy if you're hosting like on a, you know, GoDaddy or one of those or you have to FTP to the server
that it will be hosted on or you can go directly to ISIS.
Or if you have other profiles, you can just import a profile of someone to do folder.
And I'm going to explain why I do a photo, because I'm doing a local deployment.
I can do it locally to the machine and then move the files to where I want them to go.
This also applies when you're going and this is my based on my experience.
So in my experience, I have done folder deployments where I chose the folder directly on the server.
It was going to because of a typo I put in the wrong path.
And, you know, I tried it and tried it and tried it and nothing was updating.
It turns out I was doing it to the wrong path.
I didn't notice until I chose an option that said delete everything in the file folder.
And then I ended up removing some other critical files just to get my little website.
So my cautious nature know that I've learned through experience.
Promise me to always do a deployment to my machine and then the files and move them to the target machine.
That's how I do it.
So that's what I'm going to demonstrate to you based on the experience you can choose whether or not
you will do it my way or you just go straight to the target machine.
But there is no right or wrong way.
It's just a matter of experience teaching me wisdom.
All right.
So I'm going to choose A for the deployment.
So it's going to go to the Benfold release starting at five publish.
All right.
We can click, finish and then we can edit.
So there's certain things that we want to do so we can at this point change the target location if you
wish.
But then when we go to settings, we can choose other little configurations.
I want to file publish options.
So this is the option I was talking about.
Delete all existing files prior.
So what it does is why the folder and and the new files.
And if you don't choose, that's what it will do, is probably just override what's there or what's
in common anyway.
So this can be risky because if it's the wrong folder, like I said, it will remove critical files.
We can choose the databases, no databases, use this connection string at runtime.
And I'm going to take this and I'm going to change is going to Chuncheon because I don't want it to
use local DB, muscularly local DB.
I wanted to use my local host or local school express whatever the server name is.
You put that there.
I will retain the same database name and any other option and then ask about the migration.
So I'm going to say apply this migration and what this will do is generate a script.
Based on the current situation of the database and the migration's and everything, right, so we can
just go ahead and do that, click save and then click publish.
So here you have the target location.
This is where it's going to go on my machine published.
And once that publishes completed, they'll show you if it was successful or not, which it was in my
case.
And the generation of the scripts was completed successfully.
So moving on from it, just being the initial deployment, this generation step is very important because
when you're going to be, you know, deploying like an update, it's already in production and you're
updating something.
Amy, database changes, new migrations, etc. You will want to provide that script to the database
administrator or the senior developer.
I mean, if you're the senior developer, then fine.
Well, you'll want this script in order to more have more control over the database changes.
You don't want anybody to just see or migrating data.
And I'm just going to do a migration on the database because in development we have fewer concerns about
the actual data and integrity than in production.
So you want to be careful of that and let's move forward so I can just control click and go directly
to the system where this was published and I can take those files.
And what I'm going to do is in I asked them to just bring up, as we already have, the default web.
We know this.
We're going to right click.
And then I'm just going to go to explore.
So this is not bringing me to the iron folder where I would folder where all the web ups.
No, let's just say that this is a server that has multiple Web applications running.
So all of them are running from the server name slash the Web.
I mean, so what we're going to do is create the API as a Web app so we get the server name or the machine
name, slash the APIs endpoints.
All right.
So I'm going to create a folder.
I'm just going to call it Hotel on the score API.
And then inside this field, I'm going to place all the facts, and if you're coming across a network,
I would recommend that you archive them so, you know, it's easier to copy across, but since it's
just from Florida to hold on to see a machine here.
It was an easy operation then I want to run the Eskild script, so I'm just going to go into the F Sorehead
Kennedy that quickly AIFS good scripts, open that script file and then here you'll see that everything
that was in the migration's is right here in nice, understandable escudo.
All right.
So even the migration's that we did databased created all of those things, seeding data.
So the default data that we put in all of those migrations are here in Eskil scripts.
So that's why I'm saying that when we're going to be changing the database, each time the script is
generated, we can actually extract the new stuff and have more control over what we're doing to the
database.
All right.
So here and well, either way, this script kind of protection, because they say if the.
So that's why I have the migration history table, because it takes the snapshots of each migration.
So it's as if this migration doesn't exist, then carry this action.
So it kind of will see if it's done already.
I don't need to do it again.
All right.
So we can just execute this.
And let me just go back to the top.
So with Escudo, if you're if you're, you know, not so familiar with Eskild, in order to make sure
that your script is able to run against the database, you can either at the top C use an input in the
database names in this case or the hotel listing, or you just make sure that the database is selected
from the top here and the list of available databases.
So that's how you can ensure that you're able to run its own database.
When I click execute the scripts runs successfully.
So no, I have the tables.
If I just refresh, they're all they're all the ones for the users and the hotels and countries are
the ones we created manually.
They're all there.
So now that the database is primed and ready, what I'm going to do is continue with setting up the
API Web app itself.
So back in I guess I'm just going to refresh this list because what it will do is list every folder
that is in the route automatically.
See that?
And then what I'm going to do is right, click it and convert to an application before I do that, I'm
sorry.
I'm sorry.
Before we convert this to application, let's go to the application pool.
So our application pool is like a container within which Web application are web applications can run
over.
A single responsibility principle would suggest that you do upwell per upright because if Apple goes
along with multiple apps, then all those apps stop working.
So, you know, for isolation you can have multiple someone to name its hotel API pool, not do nothing
to funds are complicated.
That dominates your version.
I want to say no manage code because are using course.
So this is very, very important.
And then we can click, OK, so that's fine.
Now, the relevance of that is that when I'm coming back to the previous step, no, when I right.
Click and C convert to application, he's going to ask me which application pool I want to select so
I can go here and select from this dropdown list.
Hotel API pool.
That's the one that I wish for this app to run in and then I can go ahead and click.
Okay.
And then you notice that it no longer looks like a fool, I know it looks like a little Web globe with
the well.
No, it looks like a nut.
All right.
So let's take this for a spin.
I'm going to just browse to put it.
And we land on this page that is seeing four or four address, not phones.
All right.
But what we would have expected is more that is swagga documentation's.
Let me see if maybe when I promptitude will.
And there we go.
So now at least we know that we're looking at it from localhost.
So notice this is not localhost.
Call on the ports, localhost call on the ports, the port.
No, let me just show you just so we're very clear.
Localhost Cole on the port no represents the dev environment in my situation, localhost by itself represents
IRS.
If you have multiple Web Web servers, maybe you have Wampus or Apache or other Web servers running
that you may need to change the ports, because right now I have a but it runs on localhost port eighty
eight.
Right.
What it is the default on is, is my default.
So localhost is what you see when the web app name and then the first page.
So at least we know that we're serving up activity from the IRS.
All right.
So let us use Posman and do a fresh request.
So I'm just going to request all the hotels from the API and notice the link.
I hope it's not too small right now.
I have to see localhost slash hotel, underscore API, slash API slash photo.
All right, so it's Lokos slash the web app meme, slash the path that we would have settled in our
control as it is the jumbuck over and I'm just doing this so I have a complete understanding of all
these little variables and hold it up.
Right.
So the route that we settle was API slash controller Bitsie.
We could change it now we probably will know that we're deploying.
Right.
But the point is that because its API slash, that means whatever is preceding it will always go that
way.
So if it is that we didn't use our up call the total up, it could have been localhost slash API, especially
if it was the main route, if it was a location of the application server.
So in this case, it is not I'm not going to go into any renaming just because because your situation
might be different from mine.
I'm just explaining all the dynamics behind why my ending may look this way and yours may not, because
you went on a different path.
So if you deploy directly and I once again have no problem showing if you deployed your your API directly
to the root of this and it pulled right off w w w sorry you didn't make us all pull away and put it
right here at the root that localhost slash Swagga would actually serve you of this very page that we
were just looking at in coming from localhost.
But because of this webapp we have to go into the web to get to the actual stuff.
All right.
So let's us test this request.
And when I click send, I am getting a five hundred error and all the cool thing about all of what we
did was that we sent up.
Right.
So I can always just go over to my logs folder and take a look at why I'm getting these errors.
All right.
So this log file is showing me that something went wrong in the data client.
There was a log in there for the user and then it's showing me the name of the user.
So in the previous video, I did see permissions to play a very important part in what you're doing.
Right.
So.
For our up pool that we just created in order for the user underneath the pool to be able to interact
with the database, we need to make sure that we give it permission to the database.
So what I'm going to do is go over to a secure server, go back to the database, and then we're going
to do two things are going to create a login for that Upwood user.
And then we're going to add that log in to the security for the database.
So firstly, you log in or will let me let me just see if I can do it directly as a user.
So under the database itself, I go to users security, then users, the new user, and then I choose
Windows user.
All right, and then to put in that user name is Apple, that's its domain, and the basically the name
of the pool is the user name right now.
We can click.
Okay.
And then if we look in the list, then we will see that that Apple users not added.
No, let me try this request again.
Still getting up 500, let me tweet this a bit.
So what I will need to do is give it more permissions.
All right.
So we added it to the database, but we didn't give it any membership.
So I'm just going to say, does DBI owner know you will want to probably be a bit more granular than
I am being ranked?
No.
When setting permissions because the user that may access the database might not you might not want
to give them ownership because ownership means they can drop the database and other potentially malicious
things as much as it's a system user.
You want to be very security conscious when giving permissions rights.
So you may just want to give them better either data.
Right, or which means they can read and write to the database, but they can't do any other critical
operation that might compromise the data.
Or in my situation, it's my machine.
They're my users.
I'm going to be the owner.
So I'm going to say membership DB owner and own schemas DB owner.
And if you look back, I generally notice that the default schema is the and that you don't have to
worry about that.
That's more database level stuff.
We just want to get our application up and running so we can click OK, and then we can try again.
And then we see here that we're getting better, so we're getting data from our appeared to be not just
to let you know that some of the security features are not safe features or configurations that I might
have just put in might not necessarily work just like that for you.
There are other factors, are you that many streets are doing these things?
Do you have enough permission to give users permissions?
And all of those things do play a role in whether or not you can successfully complete all the activities
like you just saw me do it.
Ultimately, however, these are the very basic steps towards getting your application up and running
and the configurations needed on the database.
And so as not going back to I guess there are a few things that we want to make sure we get in place.
If you remember when we were setting up our JWT, we added a secret key that we added as an environment
variable.
You know, if you added it to the settings file, then you don't have to go through this step.
If, however, you did what I did and I did it as a system variable, then we need our API to store
that key.
Right, so that it can handle that operation by itself, wherever it is on whatever machine.
So everyone in is over to the configuration editor and from the dropdown list to the left, we want
to make sure that we have a system, that Web server, and then we're going to choose S.B in that court.
All right.
So go ahead, click S..
We're going to system the web server is Natcore.
And then from the drop down to the right, we're going down to application host dot config.
Now, when we do those two changes, we can see environment variables can't equals zero, so we're just
going to click that and then we're going to add our environment variable.
No, the same thing that you are added as the environment key.
So I just went and retrieved mine and my name was the word key and my value was this good.
Now, however complicated, however simple it was, the point is that we want it in a secure location
and that is what this mechanism is affording us.
All right.
So you can just go ahead and put in your name and the key that you selected and then we can go ahead
and close this so that it's added to the is No.
One, we can apply to apply the changes and then restart our pool.
So I remember I did mention that when multiple jobs are in the pool, if you if anything happens to
the pool and all of those apps go down.
So we just want to restart our pool.
We can just do a recycle.
And then what we want to do now is test our login and talk and retrieval and then secured access.
So let me just double check that they still work.
All right.
So our API still works.
That's good.
Let me attempt to login.
So I'm just going to go back to one of my older, older requests.
Right.
And well, actually, I kind of use this older request yet because if I attempted so I'm just going
to duplicate this and I'm going to remove the poor number.
And I'm also not using it as ICBM's.
That's a whole other level of configuration.
We're not going to get too much into that in this in this lesson.
We just want to get our deployment up and running.
So localhost slash hotel, underscore API, then slash API, slash Lucky and I'll in special year.
So when I send getting off for one.
Right, I'm not authorized because this user does not exist.
So because we didn't see the user.
So if you, if you see that the user you probably don't have that program.
So I'm just going to close some of these older.
Requests are so let's try and register the same user or same user, so just change the path and when
we send the request, we see that we get a tool to accept it.
So this users created let's go to the database and verify and we can see that user here, terremoto
example, dot com and the password.
So know that we have the user created.
Let us try our logging operation again to try and get the talking.
So the same request that we just tried let send.
And here is our token.
All right.
So if we just go to JWT and take a look at our token, we're seeing things that we're used to seeing.
Right.
It's going to see invalided signature because once again, it doesn't know the key was signed with,
which is what we just set up in the environment variable.
But we see that the token does have the information that we expect.
So that's no, I'm going to try one of the delete operations.
So let me try it with the Horter so we know that we have three hotels that we seeded.
Right.
I want to delete hotel with three from the database so we know that we need our token.
And we have the link.
Let me just change this, the hotel, so we're deleting the water, so we just want to verify that our
token works.
And when we do that, we're getting back a tool for so that means if I go to the database and look in
the hotel's table that started off with three, we're on the scene, too.
So you see our token worked our all our end points, at least what we've tested so far work.
And so far, we have successfully deployed our API to our local you know, our local ICE deployment
with our local database supports.
So following these guidelines, you could successfully deploy your API within your company, setting
out for your personal use or whatever the situation might be.