Hey, guys, welcome back.
So our first line of security will be for authentication and to implement the authentication features
in our API.
We're going to be taking advantage of the built in libraries of the corp.
So we're going to be making a few modifications to our database context, our startup and other little
things here and there.
So let's start off with our database context where we have to change it from being DB context to know
being identity DB context.
So this is just another class that allows us to take advantage of that identity services.
And when I do control what you see here, that you have the option to install a package dot net identity
if or entity framework or so, you just go ahead and find and install the latest version.
And then once that is done, we need to make one more modifications or on model creating where I need
to see base dot on model creating.
All right.
So I have to call the same function in the base class, which is our new base class.
I will just pass along the same builder object that we're using in the current context.
Now, that's step one done, we'll go over to the start file and then start making our modifications
here, know what we need to do is configure our identity services to know which class is going to be
used to infer the tables that will be generated.
So before I move on, let me just backtrack a bit and explain what's going to happen.
We're telling our application from the get go that we want to use our identity services.
That's what we're able to do know.
The identity services will be based on a database connection to a connection to a database that has
tables to facilitate identity related things.
User storage, Barole storage claims a number of things.
So what we need to do now is configure identity services to know which class is going to inform how
the user's tables should look and if potentially there is another one for how the rules will look,
et cetera.
So already built in is a user called our class called identity user.
And let me just go ahead and include say it's a legitimate class that's already built in that can be
used.
But if we look at the details of identity user, you'd see that it has fields for Lacourt and you don't
have to come here.
But if you want to get to that point, you can just control click and then continue to control click
until they get to that part.
All right.
So we have these default fields that will come up in the database, as you can see, if I use the name
email and password or password hash.
So those are common fields that any user table needs to have its dealing with the harshing automatically.
It's always going to have all of that built in.
No problem.
However, there may be times when we need a bit more information from our users than just email, password
and username potentially.
So they allow us to extend the identity user class and put in other fields like we made it necessary.
So I've already kind of started that process in data.
I created this class API user.
You can go ahead, click your photo, go to add, create the new class API user and then an API user.
What I have done is inherit from identity user so no one's inheritance happens.
We did that with our deals earlier, so we're doing it now with identity.
Users are going to automatically inherit all of these files as well as any other field that I see I
need.
So in this case, I just need first name, last name.
You could one date of birth equal to one country of birth, area code, other things, whatever it is
you want, you can just extend this class and add them, but you will always have these fields by default.
So once you have that class created, you can make two changes.
Before we go back to start up, I want to add that class as a context for the need context.
So I'm just using my uncle brackets and seeing the context here relative to API use, because by default
it's going to use identity user.
So if you don't have that requirement or you need more fields, then you don't have to take that extra
step.
However, it would be good to do that extra step because later on, if you need to extend it, you can
do so without much headache or hassle.
All right.
So that's one more change that we maintain our DB context.
No, we need to configure the identity services.
So I could do that from here.
But I'm going to kind of bring along another journey, you know, where we don't want to some sometimes
you don't want to keep on putting in and putting in and, you know, the start of the stacks is swell
and then you have to scroll through mountains of code to find one configuration.
So what we're going to do is go over to our project, create a new class.
If you want to put it in a folder, that's fine, but I'll just leave it at this level.
So I'm going to call service extensions and then instead of service extensions, I'm going to have public
static void and I want to call this one configure identity.
So this class is going to be like, well, it is the service extension is a better configuration.
I wouldn't want to burden in this Start-Up File with we can abstract it to this and just call the methods
are part of it, but you'll see that.
So I'm going to say this as a parameter, this and then I service.
Collection.
And call it services, all right, including the missing references.
There we go.
And then this is not going to say that I need to have this as a static class.
All right.
So.
Inside of this method, I'm going to have a variable, I'm going to call it builder.
So basically builders are going to be like amalgamation of us building up the same services that we
would have added here.
So the same we would have said services, Dot and Addison, that we can obstruct that over to this class
and then we just call it on the other side.
So you see in in due time.
So we're going to be adding our add identity core.
And then we're passing in the user class, so once again, we're using the custom user class, API user,
so API user, right.
And then open and close brace.
And I just need to include any missing reference.
There we go, and then I'm going to have my LAMDA talk where I can customize certain things about how
it handles the user interactions.
I can set my password policies right here.
I can see that all passwords must require digits or have a minimum length use unique characters.
All of those things are right there out of the box.
However, I'm more interested in just making sure that my user so user and require unique email is true,
right?
That's the only one I'm really interested in enforcing right now.
However, you can experiment and you can add the others that you feel are necessary.
So that is the first line.
And then I'm going to say builder is equal to new identity.
So more services will come with like a special builder to set on all of that.
So I'm just going to say identity builder and include the missing reference.
There we go.
So new identity builder.
Give me the builder.
Right.
So that's a builder object that we just started, that user type.
So whatever type was specified, that's what I was passing in there and then type off because I want
to use rules.
So the same way that there's a built in identity user, there is a built in identity roll.
So roll means are you admin or are you user?
Whatever it is, that's what the rule means.
Right.
And then after specifying that the rules should be there, then I'm putting in the collection services
object in the form of services.
After all of that, I'm not going to say builder DOT and we need to tell it where it should be storing
or which database it needs to interact with for the identity services to happen.
So I'm going to see deed to this context.
Right.
So the DB context that we're using as our database, we're passing the matching object for that and
one more line to our default token provider.
So I did say we'll be using tokens, but later on with official the token bits, I'm just putting all
of that there.
So just for context, once again, this builder object is really just seeing I'm building up the everything
that needs to be built up to add to the services.
That's pretty much what we've been doing all this time.
So here we said services DOT and then we had all of these lines and options on going down the same thing
with the core policy and so on.
So now that we've extracted all of these lines to this method or to this class and this method, I can
know in Start-Up C Services DOT and authentication, because that's the first thing I need to add authentication.
Right.
There's authentication core also, but I'm using at authentication.
I haven't had any problems with that one so far, so I just deal with it and then I'll see services
configure identity.
All right.
Nice and simple.
So services that configure identity is basically what we just did here.
So you can start looking at the it this way any time.
We have to add in something to the startup.
If it's not a one liner like this, maybe we can start looking to extract these things to that file
and have the builders just send over the object whenever it is called.
Right.
It's not the end of the world, but different people like to see different things.
So some people, myself included, don't like to see bloated startup files.
And at least when you have that much code, you have to be scrolling through any scroll of configuration
five times before you realize it was there.
Those little things can get annoying when your application grows.
So I'm just showing you the way that you can obstruct too many lines of code from your configuration
section and have it in a very confined space.
So now that we've done all of that and we've done all of that set up, what we want to do is do our
migration nowhere with add the tables for the identity search.
So what we'll do is add dash migration.
We know this part C added user or added identity, let's just put it that way, added identity.
And once we do that, we get our migration file.
So now when you look through, you see the different table names.
We have the experience rules stable.
We.
Is net users stable and if you look very closely to see that in addition to all the default fees that
we saw earlier, we also have the custom ones that were added to the cross.
All right.
First name, last name.
So it's going to scaffolder still is going to put in our custom fields, right.
Just the same way we could have overridden the rules.
And if we wanted more information on rules than this, we could have added a custom clause extended
and it would have been the same.
So let's just go ahead and update our database.
And with all of that done, we have finished our configuration for our identity services so you can
give yourself a pat on the back.
However, most of what we've done is in the background.
If you want tangible evidence of something being done, you can always check your database and you'll
see the tables that have been generated accordingly.
But our next step is to actually set up the endpoints such that the users can possible information and
get registered as users of our API and also for them to log in.
And then after that, we'll talk about how we continue to verify that this user should have access after
they have login.