Hey, guys, in this video will be creating or GitHub Balcones, and this is a really simplistic getup,
makes it very easy for us to sign up.
You just need to go to get tubed up.
Come, that's g i t to B dot seal and get tubed up and you will land on this bridge from here.
If you already have an account then you can sign in and you can pretty much stop watching the video
here.
If you don't however, then the Senate form is right here.
You can do a little reading just to get an appreciation of what GitHub is for.
And it's all about they do have pricing, so they do offer enterprise plans and education plans and
different plans for different situations.
But for the solar developer or for very small teams, that may not be enterprise level, then they do
give you a lot for free.
So to sign up, you need only put in a user name and an email address and a password.
And once you have provided all those things and provided that your user name is unique and of course,
then you sign up for GitHub and you should be in.
So I already have an account, so I'm really just going to sign in.
You saw my brothers are going crazy trying to provide information, so I'm just going to sign in with
my existing account.
So that's my what?
You can use your username or email address to sign in and the password.
And here I am.
This is my landing page.
So they actually give you like a sense of community.
It's almost like a Facebook for developers.
To some extent you can follow people and once they're following people, you see their activities on
the landing page, you can jump to your repository.
So obviously, if you're new to GitHub, then you wouldn't have anything listed to the site here.
But I'm not new, so I've been quite busy putting content on GitHub.
Almost any little pet project.
That's a start.
I have a GitHub repository, actually.
I need to go through and clean this up.
And also I've had students add me to their reports in the past so that we could collaborate.
Maybe they were having a problem and I could just verify their code through the repository.
All of those things are, you know, possible through this very powerful tool.
But once you have created your account and you're signed in and, well, you obviously wouldn't see
what I'm seeing once again, but then that would complete the sign of active.