Hey, guys, welcome back.
So in this lesson, we're going to be going through a process called seating.
So seating is where we provide some initial data to the database.
And what we're actually going to do is just hardcoded some records that when we perform a migration
afterwards, the migration will have instructions to create these records of the database with these
records, and it won't necessarily rely on user input.
So at least that will provide a nice basis for our testing when we start developing the API endpoints.
So what we want to do is go to our database context and where we're going to override a protected method
that is really inside of the DB context.
So protected override void on model creating and we are passing in the parameter model builder and I'm
just calling it builder.
And then what we'll see is something like a builder dot entity and then I have to specify which entity
I'm dealing with.
So we have control of hotel countries have to exist for hotels to exist.
And that's really because of how we define our records, right?
We said country and hotel as a foreign key, so we have to have the country before we can put in that
foreign key.
So would just say entity country that has data.
Oh, I'm sorry.
I'm missing a record period there.
Right.
So into the country.
And then open and close race has data data so open and close race.
And then inside of this, we're going to define some countries so we can define as many because it takes
an artist or has data really takes an array of type country so we can define a few records here.
So I'm just going to define three.
All right.
So new country record with ID equals one.
And once again, we are putting in the data, so we have to manually provide all of these values.
And this is the first country that I'm putting.
And the short name is Jim.
All right, and I'm just going to copy this and paste it cannot reduce the typing, so this would be
too and this would be three.
And the next one, let's see, Bahamas.
And the short name for Bahama, if I'm not mistaken, is the S and then the next one would be Cayman
Islands.
So I'm just choosing some destination, some popular tourist destinations where you'd probably want
to know what hotels are there.
Right.
So the short name for Cayman Islands would be.
All right, if I'm not all that accurate, then later on we can to it.
But for now, once again, these are example records, right?
So I did that for country.
I would just repeat that feat for the hotels.
Right.
So I'm just I just copied and pasted most of the code.
I noticed that at the hotel it is going to change the expected parameters to type hotel or whether it's
seeing objects because it's not getting hotels here.
So that's fine.
We'll just resort to hotel.
All right, I mean, what else did we have for the hotel address?
So let me get this.
So this is Sondos Resort and Spa, so I'm actually familiar with some of them.
Address.
Let's just keep it short and see the grill.
We already know the country, the country is Jamaica, so your idea would be one, right?
And then the rating is the last I heard it was, I'm going to say four point five.
But I know it's a five star kind of resort, so I'm just going to copy these details down.
All right, so we have a hotel for Jamaica.
I mean, just put a hotel per country just to make sure that we're spread right across and I'm just
going to make up something for Sunday for Bahamas.
So Bahamas, let's see.
They have grand.
Grand Paladium, so I know for sure Grand Paladium is a hotel in Jamaica, but for example sake we're
putting it there or puts it at their own place.
I'm sorry.
So this would be contrary to let's just do that.
And that's a four star.
Once again, this is not factual, we're just making up data, right, so far, cavemen, they have
comfort seats.
And dress that, said George.
On the contrary, these three, four cavemen and they're eating is four point three.
All right.
So that's also feeding some data into the database so this can get a bit crowded.
You could just collapse it like that so it doesn't take up too much space.
Or what I tend to do also is actually move it to underneath the DB definitions so that when I come to
make modifications to the device, it's always just stack them on top.
I don't have to scroll all the way past that.
There are ways to extract this and put them in other files and call the configurations also.
But then this is just a quick, quick, quick, quickly to see the data into the database.
So now that we have defined a few test records, the next thing that we want to do is add on migration.
So I'm going to add migration.
And this one, we're going to call the seeding data or so notice that each time the migration I try
to be descriptive enough with the name such that you can tell, oh, that's what happened at that point.
So it's almost like source control for the data.
Right.
And if you look at this, this migration file, you'll actually see here where it is insert data into
this table.
And these are the columns and those are the data volumes.
Right.
So it will go ahead and do all of that, right?
I don't know.
I turned my four point three to four point two, nine, nine and eight.
Not sure why, but that's just how it is going to reformat it so that they can do the insertions.
So the next thing that we want to do is update their database so that it can effectively carry out the
commands in the migration.
So it did see it done.
What I want to do is go back to my object explorer and then I'm going to right.
Click and view data on the country's table.
And there we go.
We have data in our database.
So we have successfully created our three countries and we can look at the matching.
Hotels.
All right, so that is how you can put initial data into your dominant core applications using entity,
framework core and the DB context.