Welcome back, guys, in this lesson, we'll be exploring how we delete data through our API, so I've
already actually created this action, if you want to, can pause and activate it.
So I'm giving you a sneak preview as to what it needs to look like, at least initially.
The verb is http delete.
We need to let you know that it should expect some parameter in the form of ideas.
An integer, we authorize it.
This is another one that you probably want to enforce a rule for administrator because we're deleting.
Otherwise you can just leave it as authorized.
And we know that the response codes here would be four hundred to four and five hundred.
So you can pause and attempt it and then we can compare notes.
So what I have in this delete hotel action is a validation to make sure that the ID value makes sense.
That's number one.
So we do that and then we rejected as a buddy request.
If it doesn't make sense, then I go on to try.
We know that our catch is already logging and returning US status codes are five hundred.
But then when it tries operation, what it does is it retrieves the hotel with the ID that was passed
and we check if that hotel exists.
Otherwise we once again see buddy request and log.
The error, otherwise, we go on to delete the photo and see more changes, then return or contents,
you see there wasn't really much to deleting the hotel.
So the same holds true for the country.
It's pretty much the same method.
We have the delete country with the same statuses.
If you want to extend the same permissions accordingly and we go through, we get the ID, we verify
that the volume makes sense and then we try the operation, getting the country validating that it is
not fake number and then going ahead and deleting it.
If it gets this far, we return and the content of two or four.
So what we want to do is test deleting a hotel versus testing, deleting a country.
And then you're going to see why I'm placing emphasis on those two tests.
So with the introduction of the delete endpoint, saga gets a bit more colorful.
You see delete being promoted here.
And what we're going to do is use postmen and attempt to delete.
So you have the endpoint.
You know, we need the ID value in the euro.
We're going to choose our verb as delete.
All right, and what I'm going to do is choose a hotel that I really don't want to hurt.
So I think this one this one was just a random test.
You see, it's still seeing string string, just like the default values that are in the payload example.
So I'm going to delete hotel with the I.D. number five.
So in my delete request, I put in the euro, slash five and then send.
Of course, I need to authorize.
So let me backtrack a bit and try and get a token there would go.
All right, here's a token, grab the talk and jump over authorization.
We're talking there we go then and we get to know content.
So if I look back at the list, I shouldn't see the auto side five.
There it is.
It goes further than six.
So five is gone.
No, that is how we would delete a hotel.
No, the thing with the country is that the country has hotels, so it's a bit riskier when we delete
a country that we're actually going to have to remove the hotels also.
So let's see what that looks like.
Someone to say country.
And looking back, I see that we have two in Cayman and we have that.
So we have one in Bahamas.
So let's try and delete the country of Bahamas.
It only has one or two soldiers bite the bullet and make the sacrifice of that one.
And we can always add it back later on.
So what I'm going to do is see a country with these three and go over here.
Put that there, all right, I need three and then send.
And we see we're getting a new content, so if I look at the list of countries that we look at, the
list of countries I shouldn't see.
Oh, I deleted.
Come on, that's fine.
So I need Keyman, so, you know, we only have two countries, one and two.
I thought I was deleting Bahamas apologies.
So that means none of the hotels that have I'd value three should be there.
So let me send.
And there it is.
So we have control with the one country with 80 to control, 31 one, et cetera.
So no country with ID three remains.
And that's because in our migration when we created the database so you can go to the first migration
file, I call the database created, you'll see in the configuration that the constraint on the foreign
key was that it said are differential action, not Kaskade.
So Cascade means that if you make any change to the parent meaning country, so you have country being
the parent and hotels are in a country.
So there the children are cards.
If you make any change to the country record, it would reflect on the hotels.
So in this case, the change we're making is that we're deleting the parent record.
So it's in undelete.
I want to Kaskade, meaning whatever you do to the parent, replicate that action across the child so
this can actually be changed.
But then you'd have to make the modification in the context file and then run another migration for
it to know that you want no action or to restrict meaning.
And I usually do.
I restrict because if there are children records, I don't want to delete the parent.
So that means once there are hotels associated with this country, you cannot believe the country has
what to do.
However, write notes on Kaskade and like you see when you delete that parent record, it's going to
cascade across all the hotels.
So you have to be careful with that.
Make sure that if that configuration obtains in your API, it is deliberate.
That is how you want it to work.
But this is something that can cause massive data loss if it is, if it goes untethered.