All right, so previously we configured our get to method, and this is really the get all method,
but it's not all the time that our client application wants to get everything.
Sometimes they want to get specific data.
All right.
So we want to at least provide them an endpoint where they can get one country based on a particular
unique identifier.
In this case, the ID.
Right.
And just for context, since we're building the API with the context of the actual client.
If you saw a list of countries and you wanted to see the details of one of these countries and you click
The View, then what would happen is that it would go back to the database and get that specific country
to display the specific information or details of that particular country.
All right.
So that's the same thing that we want to provide an endpoint for so that when on their side, when the
user clicks the country, they're in the background.
We'll see which country was tricked here, which IDs there.
Here's the ID API, please.
May I have the details?
And then we say, OK, we'll do the look up the details for that particular country.
So without any further delay, let's get to it.
So I'm actually just going to copy that original get.
All right.
And we're just going to make some minor modifications.
So the first modification would be to the attributes.
So, yes, they're both targets.
Right.
But this get in particular needs to know that it can take a parameter.
And this is really it has a lot to do with documentation purposes.
And it's good so that when people see it, they can infer at the same time what how it differs as it
goes along.
So you can define the gate, but then you open and close Breece.
And then inside of that you define the template for the gate.
So I can see here that I'm expecting some parameter called ID and it should be off of it.
So if you wanted to get by name, we could do something like name of type street.
All right.
So so you would know that this gate is going to take this parameter name and the names are very important
and that data type, which is also very important.
Next, we are going to have to rename this.
I mean, get countries.
This isn't getting countries.
This is getting a country and it is taking a parameter ID.
So like with any other method anywhere else in C sharp ones, they're calling them.
If that has now you have to pass a perimeter in, you have to define department that that's expecting.
I notice that the name here matches the name that is in the attributes.
All right.
So get country ID.
No, we have to see him try to catch, but then we're going to change the quarry and the mopping up.
So one, we're not getting countries, we're getting in country and we're all in the same elite units
of four countries, what we're calling the get method.
All right.
And our get method notice the red line, the get method requires the expression or the stipulation behind
what exactly it should be getting.
So we have to define in this the expressions.
I remember I said that the expression is really going to be a lambda expressions.
I'm going to pass in that same kind of lambda expression, which is a token lambda arrow, and then
what am I looking for to Dot?
And then I have all the fields off the table.
So this was designed for countries, right?
So what field in the countries tables should I be looking for?
I'm looking for the ID and my my condition is that the ID in the country is stable much as the ID coming
in through the parameter.
All right, and then in the same way, I can include because I'm just thinking about it, if you ask
me for the country within the context of this some other country, I figure that maybe you will want
to see all the hotels for that particular country.
So while looking at the list of countries, you only want to see maybe the list of countries.
However, when you look at one country, you probably want to see the hotel.
So are hotels.
So I want to say a new list somewhere to passing a new list of timestream.
And I'm going to add to it, so this is what we initialize our list and we can say that I want to include
your toes.
So once again, this is not going to go over to our units of work, is going to hit the living, find
the method, which is in the generic repository, and it's going to hit the gate.
So this is the expression, this is the includes.
So it gets all the records.
Then it says if there is and includes, go ahead and include whatever you need to include, include
the hotel's right.
And then we're going to look at Macquarie, take off the tracking and return the first our default record
that matches and default means just return if we can't find anything.
But the first record that matches this expression.
So the expression would be where you got it is equal to the added value.
It will do all of that computation and just return the one record to country with all of the hotels
that are available.
So I'm just going to double check with my domain just to make sure that the thing is called hotels,
because this has to match just the same way in the detail.
It has to be hotels.
All right.
So now that we've done that wiring up, I'm just going to change up my mapping.
So I'm getting back one country object, one object.
So I'm not going to come up to our list.
I'm just mapping to contribute to you.
So that's a one to one mapping.
And I'm just taking off the S's and fixing the plurals under the singular just so that the code is self-explanatory.
We shouldn't be calling these countries when we're only getting one.
Correct.
So I'm just trying to make sure it's readable.
All right.
And then we're just going to see something went wrong in the name of get country.
So let us take this one for a spin.
So you see the gets really straightforward, right?
We did one there and we just took the quarter with a few modifications where potentially done with it.
So let's see what.
So the first thing I want to bring attention to is the documentation.
So you see API slash country and see API slash country slash IDE.
So that idea being displayed there is courtesy of our annotation here.
All right.
And then if we drilldown into it, you'll see that they're actually seeing that ID parameter is required.
No two ways about it.
It's required.
Right.
And if we say try it out, we can put in that.
But I'm going to put I'm going to use postmen to test this one.
All right.
So when I say get.
Right, with Bowsman and the same end point and says, and I'm getting the original get, which is getting
the list, no, when I modify this end point and I say slash one.
All right, and then click send look out what I get back, so I'm getting back only one result and this
is the idea and it's the list of hotels, which there's only one hotel associated with hotel number
one.
So country number one, there's only one hotel.
But this is unary.
So if there are more than all of them will be listed on that property or attributes.
And then the name is Jumia kind of short name is Jim.
So you see our second guest is working.
So let me just put our break point and show you exactly what is happening when we meet that request.
So putting our break point there and then clicking send again, Bridgepoint is activated.
If we look in the parameter listing, we see our value one coming over.
All right.
And then we can go ahead and.
I'm going to use Epton, so if it doesn't go into all of the method, cause what if I look at the country
object coming back, you see hotels and that's the list with only one idea, the name, the short name,
and then we do the mapping.
So no result has all of the data that was just in country.
And then it's going to return to Occy with results.
So it's automatically going to be serialized into serialized into JSON layouts.
All right.
And right there, we're done with our second get.
So now we know to get all I know, we know how to get by based on a particular requirements.