Welcome back, guys.
So today we want to just have a quick run through of Swagga, how it ties into our API development and
what its purpose is.
So Swagga really is there to help simplify API development for users, teams and enterprises.
It's an open source tool set and it basically helps us to design and document our database with much
less effort than it would really take to have this level of detail.
So it's a really good tool.
It helps us to automate a lot of things.
And the best parts of it all is that it is already included with our API.
So in previous versions we would have to go and install it.
Granted, it wasn't a very difficult process, but now that Microsoft has seen that it is kind of a
standard that everybody with an API wants to put in structure because it's so cool, so efficient,
that's everything it's doing, then what they've done is they've actually just started packaging it
in our API for us.
So the main libraries that allows slogger to be integrated, well, one comes from this new get Puckett's.
If I go to managing to get package, we'll see that we have the package already installed for swashbucklers.
Not is the Internet's core.
Right.
Gives us the slogger tools then in our startup.
So remember that program that CSS calls the startup.
So startup is not where we define all the middleware.
And the one that we have in the services for software is services that add sluggard Jen.
We put in whether or not we either we if we were doing it manually, we would have to do this.
But because it was generated once again, we don't have that step.
So it will generate the Swiger document.
It supports versioning.
So if you have version one, version two, etc. off your API, you're able to keep track of the versions
or at least let whoever is reading the documentation or which version of the API they're looking at,
you can define certain open API information.
That is the title, the version.
If I click coming here, you'll see that you can add contact information, you can add a description,
license, all sorts of things to your documents or somebody's looking at your API documentation, knows
exactly who.
If you want to provide that level of detail and what this API is about later on or further down, rather,
in the configure section, we have the user swagga and app not use soggier UI.
So Swiger UI means you will create its own endpoint.
It will have its own kind of configuration file and it will call itself a listing if you want.
No.
Right.
No, this is under the end.
That is development.
So Env is just a variable that allows us to track which environment we're in.
Are we in development, are we in production right now?
Anything that goes in here is it's basically seeing we're in development.
So when we publish this to see as your I guess or, you know, to the Internet, whatever it is or wherever
it is we put it, don't do any of this stuff.
That's what this statement basically says.
No, I think software is useful.
So while they may have put it in the development parts, which I understand, I think that it's easier
to just include it in the API at all times so that when I published my API, I don't have to provide
as much technical support to somebody else to teach them how to use the API because that's what Soga
documentation is for.
So I'm going to just take these two lines out of that statement and place them in the general area where
everything else is going to get done regardless of the environment.
So that's my modification.
Once again, context is everything.
I can understand it for security reasons or just general lack of need for information exchange.
They probably said, well, you only look at it in a development setting because the developers may
be internal.
But and if it's for third party developers, then I'm going to make it external and publicly accessible.
So let's take a look at one of our controllers and the controller that we have.
And you see here, it gives us the weather forecast and the defense I get.
Method, all right.
No, if I run the application and the webpage comes up, we're seeing our Swiger documents.
All right.
So hotel listing version one, all of those were things defined in the startup.
So if you need to change the name or make it a bit more appealing, user friendly, human readable,
you can always change it inside of the configuration areas here and here.
Right there it is title.
So if you want to add a description of description, you will come up on the page.
Now, here it is showing us what is in the API and what's in the API would be our endpoint to get it
going back to the controller to get.
Weather forecast.
All right, so it's contextually generating this document based on what it sees in the project, only
that it will show you examples of what is going to come back when you try to retrieve anything, which
is exactly right, because this is returning at least off with a forecast and weather forecast series
is a class that has some data.
Feels defined on each one as a date data types, so date time, intent, intense string.
So you see if Swagga is actually taking all of them, see that it so you're going to get McAfee recorded
temperature C temperature if something is going to show you all of them.
And it is even giving you an idea of the data type.
This is a date time int industry.
So I'm just showing you how powerful Saugerties without any effort on our part to already have API documentation,
which once again is very important when you are going to be building a client application, consuming
an API, or if you are the one building the API, you make it easy for somebody who has to consume it.
So the same way you'd want to be treated as a consumer of somebodies API to have all the information
you need to know how to build around it.
You want to make sure you provide that information to persons interacting with yours.
So Swagga makes it out of the box very easy.
And just to push the envelope a bit, when we go to try it out, we can actually execute.
And Swagga allows us to actually test our API right here.
So these this data that's coming back with the statistical two hundred really gets into all of that
later on.
But you see the response, buddy, that's because it's actually executed the code that is here.
And just to prove that, if we click over in this page and we get this red dot, which is a break point,
so I'm just going to click execute again.
And then you see visual studio pauses and it hits this breakpoints is, you know, has this yellow in
it and that allows us to press every level and go line by line.
So I'm not trying to show you how to debug.
No, I'm just showing you that this is not fluff.
It actually will help us to test.
So now we have to test the utilities, Swiger and Posman.
All right.
So when I press five or I can continue up top here, whichever one, then it will just continue with
the execution and it will bring it back.
All right.
So that is how Swagga helps us in our quest for testing.
No, I'm just going to do two for one special.
And let's include over longer here.
So on top of already.
Well, by default it's injected.
So because we are using Cerillo as a default logger, when we do logging, using our object here, it
will use the silver logger.
So I'm just going to show you a little snippet of logging so I can see a logger dot and then I would
log information to see.
Accessed weather forecast.
All right, so this is just information to say access with the forecast and then I can see later on
with a forecast returned, something like that.
You know, it may not this this is elementary, but it's just once again, for example, seke.
So just see lugger.
Lowgar, oh, well, I'm sorry I put that too far down.
Here's a return statement, so.
Art, I'll just leave it has information for later on, we'll get to experiment more when we have our
own code to test it.
So I'm just going to run this application one sec and then I'm going to go ahead and try to click execute.
I can remove the breakpoint by just clicking.
So as long as that red dot is there, it's going to stop.
When it gets to that line, you just remove the red dot and F for it to continue.
All right.
So it's executed.
Let me see if my love is going to show me anything useful.
Let me try and find.
And there we go.
So this is not a love files all the times that we've actually opened it up and it did something you
see here, it's right in the log.
So here is our first log application is starting and the need log that this did that, that.
And here's the one that we just wrote, accessed weather forecasts.
Right.
And then it's telling you all of the details of what it's doing and getting on this and that.
So that's all logging works.
That's all soggier works.