Hey, guys, welcome back.
So in this lesson, we're going to be talking about global era handling, so I'm starting off in the
control of four countries.
And we had mentioned earlier that we would want to reduce the need to repeat this track, catch every
time we're able to do an operation.
While it is very essential, it becomes repetitive over time because we have four functions where we
keep on writing, try catch track, try to catch.
And for every other function, it would be important.
And so what we want to do is implement a global way to handle exceptions and reduce the need for the
repetitive track at statements.
So what we want to do is standardize what happens when we catch an error, because when we catch an
error, we actually do the same thing.
The only thing that's sort of dynamic would be the the part where we see the location, which to me
is actually kind of optional.
I probably don't necessarily have to do this part, but the point is that the message is relatively
the same and we always give that 500 response code.
So what we want to do is to have like a standard way to represent an area and.
I'm just going to create a new class and I'm going to call it error.
And then in Iraq, we're going to have three fields, so we're going to have.
Status quo.
We're going to have a message and then we're going to have a third one where we're providing the message
as serialized JSON object.
So for this one, we'll have Newton, Jason Newton, soft sorry, Jason.
So that is how our class will look after that.
What I want to do is extend our startup pipeline, but I'm going to use the service extensions like
what we've been doing for the past few times.
And I'm going to have a new form and we're calling this new function configure exception handler and
this time is getting the middleware pipeline.
So originally it would be getting the services that we're getting the application builder.
Right.
So in this, we go ahead and we set up don't use exception handler so that they don't make their application
in and of itself has its own exception.
Handler So we're just kind of doing like an override to see this is really how we want you to operate.
So use exception.
Handler And then we need our little token or lambda looking token.
And then in here we open and close to Brisas semicolon at the end.
So inside of this block I'm going to say error run.
So this is me adding the custom middleware code now and I'm going to see async and my token expression,
which I'm going to call context, and then my lambda arrow once again for another object.
Right.
So what I do is every time I am going to do one of these, I just make sure to put the semicolon on
the end of the on the Breece.
Are the parents user out there.
So I don't forget it later on it.
So then we're going to see some some some that I'm setting context dot response, that status quo to
be equal to status codes dot five hundred.
So the same five hundred that we return every time there's an error.
We're just setting that as a constant so we don't have to type it over and over it.
So where was I.
Sorry.
So status quo.
It's that status.
Five hundred internal server error and then I'm setting the content type to be application not JSON.
Then I'm going to see var context feature is equal to context, not features.
Get an exception handler feature.
You may need to import data missing data type for this one so you can go ahead and do that.
So what we're going to say now is if the context feature is not equal to null, then we want to see
log dots and then login error.
So remember that every time something fails, we actually do that.
We have our logger and then we login error or we pass in whatever is wrong.
Right.
So I'm going to see if something went wrong.
I just copy this basis over here.
Something went wrong, but instead of name often get countries.
This time I'm going to see context feature, not error.
So that will kind of give us an indication as to what went wrong.
Right.
So lugnut error, context, feature error.
And then we go on to see a wait context.
Is this just bring us back to asynchronous programming.
Notice that this little arrow here is green and seeing that we're seeing is seeing awaits, awaited
anything.
So when I say how it that error is not satisfied and it goes away or the async keyword is no satisfied,
the line goes away.
So I'm going to see a wait context, that response.
So we're going to see send back our response to the call in context of context here really represents
the controller that is passing the information.
All right.
We'll see how that works in a few.
So.
Right.
Async, right.
And then we want to say we want a new era.
So new era, I know, just go ahead and initialize this model.
There we go.
So want to new know where our status code is going to be equal to the status quo that we just set up
here?
So, I mean, we could have easily set that here.
It's fine, but we want that.
And we also want our message.
To be equal to something consistent, so I think here we just said internal server error.
Please try again.
I think that that's what we said every single time.
So just let the message be equal to that very consistent message.
And then all of this we want to convert to string.
Then we have a semicolon.
All right, so let's just review this a little bit so we're seeing that we want to override our default
exception handler and the way that we want the exception handling to occur is such that when one happens,
we write the log and then we generate an error model with the status code and the message.
All right.
So that would kind of eliminate our need to manually do that every single time.
Now, after writing that custom middleware code, what we need to do is go over to the Start-Up and
I'm going to put that one right underneath the swagga.
So we're going to set up not configure exception handler and that should be it.
So what I'm going to do as a proof of concept is remove the tray, because Char really means do this.
So with all the trades, I'm going to attempt to do it.
The real purpose are the game changing aspect of the try catch is that it will say try this operation
and handle the arrows that occur.
So if I have a global error handling, then I don't need to go ahead and put in anything to handle it
manually when something does occur.
So I'm going to try and well, I did that in the get ID or that's fine.
So we're going to run some tests with this as a proof of concept.
And what I will also do is, OK, we'll just we'll just look at how it works.
So I'm going to start and I'm going to run a request for API slash country, slash one.
And then we're getting country number one, which is Jamaica with the hotel.
So everything is working fine.
That's what we would expect.
All right.
I know it's hard for me to introduce an error otherwise.
So what I'll do is introduce it manually here in the code.
What I'll do is throw a new exception because the catch is there to catch an exception.
So if I throw an exception myself, then what would happen is that the code would actually stop executing.
At this point.
I never get down there now.
I want to see what response I would get when that exception is thrown.
So we're going to go ahead and run that same post request that was just successful.
No, we introduced this through exception.
And when we do that, we see that we're getting back started school and message.
And those two fields are the same two fields that we just defined in our error module.
All right.
So what is happening here is that the exception handler is actually globally watching for any time an
exception is caught.
Then it is doing what we asked it to do, which is to log the error and see if something went wrong
here.
So let's see what's in the log.
And when I check the log, I'm seeing my exception right here.
So system exception system that the exception was through.
And I could have made a more specific exception to this than that.
But then if you look down, you'll see the whole pipeline as to where it went.
So what happens is that it went to the controller, the controller through an exception and then the
exception handle the hand handler that we overrode our custom code.
And then it said, OK, what should I do?
Well, the status quo is five hundred.
The response type is, Jason, I'm going to log the error and then I'm going to write back in our response
that this has occurred so that we we can actually safely and confidently having done that, removal
of the other try catches from anywhere else in the code, because once again, those strike catches
were there to make sure that we're handling all the errors gracefully or as gracefully as possible so
that we've made it global.
You want you can do is just do as you see me doing and just go through and take out all the track catches
and whatever code it is that you expect to be executed, you just go ahead and execute that.
And what you realize is that because of that, the removal of that dependency on the tray catches everywhere
in every action.
When you are expanding on extending on your API is functionality, your code will look much cleaner
because then you and your team can just write the code, knowing full well that your exception handling
is happening at a global scale.
So I've done that with country.
You can go ahead and clean up the hotel controller as well as any other controller that you may have.