Hey, guys, in this video we're going to be installing Postman No Postman is an excellent tool for
collaboration and API testing and validation on all of those wonderful things.
So it's pretty easy to install really.
Just go to postman dot com postman, just like the guy who delivers your mail.
Postman dot com.
You download the app.
And of course, you choose your oil, so I have a 64 bit windows and then the oil starts.
All right, so once that download is finished, you can go ahead and open the installation file, run
the installer.
All right, so when it is finished, you will either see a screen prompting you to sign up or sign in
or you'll see the screen either way if you see something to sign in.
I would encourage you to do so.
I actually have it on my machine already.
So, you know, the floor may not be exactly like this, but if you do see this page come up, then
it's fine.
You can just click the X and you can take it off.
And I'm not signed in anyway.
So if you do see the R sign up screen looking something like this, then you can just go ahead and create
an account.
Sorry about that.
You can create an account quite easily.
Username, password, or you just signing with Google.
I like to just sign in with Google.
And the thing is that course I will keep a history of every test that you have done once you have enough
account.
All right.
So I'm just going to go ahead and sign in with Google and then once you're signed in, then, you know,
you can start working.
So I'm just going to show you guys a sample of what Posman is capable of.
Firstly, I'm going to suggest what's a dark moat because Darmody school and then I'm going to create
a new request window.
So using this plus sign, just like any browser with the plus signs at the top, you can just see a
plus sign and that gives you a new request.
No, I already went ahead and searched for some public APIs as we discussed APIs based on our gateway
into your database.
So people have APIs, various people have APIs and I found this website and Nidetch API dot com and
just try and go back to the very first page so you can see what they have to offer.
So from the, you know, the landing page, they show you a bunch of public facing API.
So you can just go ahead and click one and test it out.
So I went over to the Oxford Dictionary, one where I would get a list of languages.
So they show you all of the endpoints.
Right.
So in building all the API, they link to the data, be assured they have a common URL, but then they
have different endpoints that will give different bits of information.
Right.
And then they have different methods, get and post the potential of some other ones.
But the fact is that you have to know the request type.
You have to know the URL through which you can get that requests satisfied.
You have to know if you have to pass in headers.
So here I know I need the applications G and ID and then they show me the responses.
So two hundred means OK.
And then they show me an example in Jason what that response would be.
And then for four means not phoned.
Five hundred means that there is an internal error usually with the home server.
Not with you.
Right.
So four four means that you're probably searching for something that doesn't exist.
Five hundred means that the API provider has an error message from any API and want to free for free
forex API.
Sorry.
So I took a closer look at any API and I realized that all of those APIs require that you would have
had enough code to be a registered user, probably paying user off those platforms.
You can look through you see Instagram, you see YouTube, Google, most of those are protected API.
So they're using some moments of security around it.
And we're going to go through all of those techniques in this course.
But right now, I just want to talk with Quick-witted and satisfaction of seeing what Posman can do
and the relevance of it.
Right.
So I phoned the free for x API dot com.
You can just type that in free for API dot com and then we'll go over to documentation.
So that landing page is actually there, a demo of them consuming the data through the API that they're
exposing.
Right.
So they have a database that builds an API and then the they're making a series of API calls to show
the treating index between Yuren USD and GBP etc, etc..
So if I go to documentation, they will give me the terms of use, tell me how to use it.
So documentation is very, very important and vital when it comes to the API is that we'll be using
Swagga Swanger UI to our swashbucklers when we get there you'll see, but we'll be focusing on documenting
our APIs to a great extent also.
So from here they show you that you have the data that's the domain that the API is hosted on.
Right.
And then as you grow, don't you see the different types of functionality that they explicitly say get
great data?
Right.
And then they say to me, the request it is gets requests and then you have the the the endpoint sorry,
the Yooralla and the endpoint.
That's what it needs to look like.
And this is a.
Sample response.
All right, and if you look through, you see another one that you can get different, Piers, so right
here you're only looking at the euro, the one on the return that the results of that quarter for you.
And then in this one, you can get more than one if you want.
So you just put in both indexes that you're interested in as the parameter in that endpoint.
All right.
So that's a query string for the values the queries are on.
And then this is the response from the API.
Once that queries are on and the data is is phoned.
No, the error codes tell a good story because then you if you pass in two piers that don't exist in
their system, then they're telling you that it's if you don't pass in any setting, it's required.
And if you pass in something that's not there, then you'll see an error code one thousand and two.
So you have standard error codes and you have some areas that you yourself can meet.
So let's try this someplace.
I'm going to try the first one where I'm getting Euro and USD.
I'm just going to copy this link, which they said that's how you get to the data on this end point
that I'm going to open up postman and then what I'm going to do is paste it inside of this.
It says, enter request euro.
That's what we just copied.
Right.
Request on the euro.
So I paste the request, your URL and then the verb here immobilising you can get post, you have put
Potch deletes, you have a bunch of them.
So get is usually used when you're expecting to retrieve data.
Right.
So it gets and then free for its API, whatever that request was.
No one's committed to memory because it's there in the documentation and then I will click send.
What Postman does is make a call.
Well not really make it actually performs the call to that API endpoint and then retrieve the data in
the response.
So we see here it may not be as well formatted as how it is in the documentation.
Of course they're putting their best foot forward, but is the same bit of information we're getting.
Right.
And we're getting a timestamp and we're getting a code of two hundred.
If you look to the right, you'll see the status.
Two hundred or so.
Two hundred is the universal response for all.
T once you get to the 200 response, you know, everything is OK.
So the different numbers have different meanings, of course.
Right.
The time it took to make the call.
So this is a quick API.
It took only that's what, half a second and the size of the response.
Right.
You can always formatted so this you can click pretty or you can see raw or prevue.
Or visualize, I'm not sure why pretty.
Oh, that's right, I have to change the format.
So it's pretty HMO.
So this is all good looking HMO.
But if I take this, I can say something like SML what it sounds like some said HMO.
Let me click Jason, which it is.
And there we go.
So now it's pretty.
Geosung So now it looks a bit more like it is being previewed in their documentation.
So Posman is very handy when you just want to test what the response will look like.
Jason is the most widely used response type.
Well, I'm seeing that loosely.
I like to use JSON responses, but the process alternative to that would be XML and well, you know,
once the data is being returned, the user expects and you've documented what they can expect, then
you you can feel confident that anybody can use their API when needed.
So Posman is going to come in handy as we go about developing our API and just want to validate that
the response is, look, the way we expect them to.