Welcome back.
So nowhere on the point of creating our repositories and what we'll be implementing is a development
pattern, really.
So let me just give some background as to why we need to go through that when we're doing our work with
our API.
It's easy enough to just write the queries using entity, framework or and link, and we just write
it especially like balloon.
They have two tables contending with which our country and.
But what happens when we have eight, nine, 10, 20 tables?
It becomes kind of tedious to try and write queries every time we have a table.
And then that's going to lead to a repetition.
And then if we have the same query, multiple places, then that's a maintenance nightmare.
So that's why we're going to be implementing a pattern and we'll be using the generic repository pattern
alongside the units of work pattern to kind of create a container to define basic functionality that
will be shared across all our tables and all our database operations in our project.
So to get this started, I'm going to create two new folders.
One will be called I am a Repository, and the other one will be called the repository.
Right.
So we have a repository.
And that's going to be a capital I.
And then we're going to have another one that's I'm just going to call repository.
So there's a concept called separation of.
Concerns where you want to make sure that your every file knows that it is doing one thing.
So that's why we made sure to define two different files for this.
We want to define some amount of individual classes along the way, but they want to make sure that
certain things are generic and we're not repeating certain things right.
So in our eye repository, we're going to create an interface somewhat to create a class because that's
just quick.
But I'm going to call it a generic repository and go ahead and click on ADD and I'm just going to change
its interface.
If you choose interface, that will be fine doing the things that you have to remember to put on public.
Right.
So that's the only reason I really choose class because of the forgotten to put on public in the past.
And I couldn't understand why I was getting the air I was getting.
So that's my little failsafe based on my experience.
So what we're going to do is make this generic repository take a generic parameter in the form of T
where T is going to be class.
All right.
So I want to talk about generics.
This t just says, well, I'm prepared to take any type of class that you send my way, and that helps
us in creating those base operations for different situations with different class types.
So the first one that we're going to create is a function called get SA will get.
All right.
So I'm going to see.
Task, a list of type to get, all right, and then I'm going to be defining certain things, so let
me just explain exactly what is going on in this function Whitter task, what we're dealing with asynchronous
programming.
We have to use tasks.
If you're getting an arrow, it's because you don't have that library that I've highlighted there,
at which point, you know, you just do control DOT and go ahead and into the using statements.
So the task list of type T once again, generic and the function name is gets all so gets all has a
parameter which for which I'm going to include the missing reference which is of type, expression,
function and expression.
And we're making an optional parameter.
It's also going to take on a horrible.
I aquaria, all of that I ordered horrible.
So you can just rewrite that how I have it and order by that's also optional.
And then we have the ability to include if we need to.
All right.
Then I'm going to have a follow up function for git.
So task t get.
So this one is going to get at least this one is just getting one.
So that's why it's task T and this one is Toschi.
So this one is just going to get one record and is seeking the same expression parameter and it's going
to have the inputs on where fishing out the the actual function.
Then you'll understand what the parameters really stand for.
We're going to have similar functions for our current operations.
So I'm going to have to ask insert T entity.
So this is going to be the one to create.
We're going to have insert range.
So I like to keep this one nearby because sometimes they have both operations and instead of calling
this multiple times, you could just define one that takes that list and it just does the rest.
Anyway, we have delete and they also need to rearrange.
All right.
And update.
I don't like doing the etranger, but we have the update.
So notice that the task, the delete is task for all of these are task, but these two are void operations.
All right.
So that is it for our generic repository.
So once again, this is being defined as like a base, Getchell, no matter what the data type, if
we introduce five more tables and an accompanying domain classes, we don't really have to change much
here because these functions will be defined to handle any other table or domain class that gets through.
So now that we have the interface, I'm going to go ahead and create the concrete.
So I'm going to go with the repository and class.
And this time is an actual class and I'm calling it generic repositories of a generic repository.
And I have just generic repository and generic repository is going to take the same.
Generic T.
But it's also going to inherit from a generic repository where T is across.
I'm just going to go ahead and include the missing reference right there.
And then it's going to complain because once we're inheriting, we have to make sure we implement.
So I'm just going to go ahead and implement the interface and then it generates all of those MyFord
stubs for me.
Also kindly.
So let us flesh out exactly what we need here.
So we're going to have to do some modes of dependency injection.
So I've mentioned that if I have before, I haven't mentioned it much more dependency injection is basically
the concept by which whatever we load it up in the startup is no available application wide.
So we don't need to instantiate every time that we need it.
All we do is make reference to the already existing object because it was defined in our startup.
Right.
So more contextually or connection our bridge to the database, we can know.
Just get a copy of that to use in our file here.
Instead of trying to create a whole new bridge, our own instance of this bridge, we can just leverage
the one that exists as a result of it being included in the startup procedure.
All right.
That's that's in a nutshell what dependency injection really helps us to do.
So what we're going to do is define a private read only it's private.
It's read only because we don't need to make any modifications to it.
And it's going to be an instance of data base context.
All right, including the missing references.
There we go.
Private Read-Only.
And I'm just going to call it underscore context.
Right.
And then similarly, I'll just duplicate this line because I want the president to read only I want
DBI sit and remember, DBE said, coming over from the same database context and it's going to be defined
for a generic.
So I'll just go ahead and include the missing reference.
There are also the basics of typed and I'm going to call this one.
No, these are defined for this class.
However, dependency injection will require me to create a constructor and it's going to take a parameter
of type database context and I'm going to change the name.
So the private one has underscored this one does not.
And then having taken that parameter, it is no able it's not accessing the one or the copy from the
start of procedure.
So for my local use, I'm going to initialize my current context that I have as my private read, only
to be the same value as the one being injected in.
So that's pretty much dependency injection.
Yes, that was a mystery to your point.
You know, that is how it basically works.
There are other nuances to it, but for now, it doesn't need to get much more complicated than that.
So the next one is on the score.
DB is going to be equal to context.
Not at all.
Initialize plaintext.
I can see in context, give me a set of whatever it is.
And remember that at this point he needs to basically correspond with something that has been outlined
in our DB set in our database context.
All right.
So that is why I can confidently say go to the context file and give me a set of whatever this is,
because the context should know about it by the time we're building this repository.
So now that we have that part done, lets us go on to our implementation.
So let's do the delete, which is fairly easy.
All I want to say is var entity is equal to and then I'll wait.
So because you're doing asynchronous programming, you have to wait.
So I have to ask here.
But what I'm missing is the async keyword before it.
Right.
Anytime you have a task that you're going to be using it.
You have to have async notice.
When you click one, the other one gets highlighted.
They go hand in hand.
Right.
So we say I wait on the score DB dot find and I'm just going to find it.
Find async.
So Natcore sorry.
In entity framework or for almost every operation you have a corresponding async operation.
So at this point it's there, use it.
And if you're using async you have to precede it with it.
And by extension the method in which this awaits keyword is being used to have async on the method.
So it's not in the interface, it's not in the interface, but in the definition.
You have to have that as you write more and more, you'll get the hang of it.
So we'll find async and we'll pass in the idea for the report that you want to find.
And then we'll say DB dot remove.
And we're moving the entity that has been found with that, and that's it for delete now delete range
is pretty much one line.
It's just going to be DBI that remove range.
So we have a list of entities.
So I'm going to say DB dot, remove range and remove variances will give me the list of entities where
there is a list of entities.
Just remove them.
That's it for the remove range.
So I'm going to go ahead and kind of go through the easier ones.
So insert is easy, insert Reges easy and open, it is easy and then we'll go back to the get and get.
All those can get a bit more complicated.
So I'm just going to prepend each task in the method header with the keyword async.
That one is void.
So I don't need you there just to make sure that I don't run into any difficulties later on.
All right.
So far, insert that one is fairly simple.
All we're going to see is a wait db dot add async and we add the entity.
Whatever Kimura's data, add it.
That's all we need to do.
Right.
And then similarly for the insert range we're going to do is db dot outrange async.
So this one has an async notice or move range did not have an async.
Right.
So outrange async and the list of entities that you got to add.
And then for our update we have a two part operation.
One, I'm going to attach the entity to the DB.
So in other words, when the data comes over, it might not be attached or it might be an object that
exists in memory with no direct connection to the database at that point in time.
So attach means pay attention to this and check if you have it already.
Check if there's any difference between it and what you have in the database, because, I mean, we're
able to do an update, right?
So then it starts tracking to see that, OK, there are certain fields that are different.
So these are two different, let's say, records.
Right.
And then the next line would say context, that entry.
And then we reference entity.
That state is required to modify it.
So once we tell it that, OK, it has been modified, then it will know that, OK, I need to do an
update to it.
So let's go up to our get.
So get is actually easier to do then get to all.
But once you do get then get all will make a bit more sense.
So the first thing that I'm going to do is get an equitable.
I want to call it Quarrie of what's in the sermon ladyboys already defined to be whatever it is Datatel
that we're dealing with, right.
So just get all of the records basically that are in that table.
Pretty much that's what this is going to do.
And then I went to check to see if there was an includes.
Right, it was there and includes a requirement, meaning did the user did the calling code, whoever
called this method, would they like to include additional details?
I did say earlier that when it comes to the hotel on the country, instead of looking for the hotel
and then getting the contra idea and then calling the database again to get the country with that idea,
and then that's to database, because you could make one database call and we're getting the hotel and
including the country so that it will automatically fill this property with all the corresponding countries
details.
Right.
So that's what that includes is for.
So this code snippet basically says that if it includes is not equal to no.
So by default, it's not it's optional.
You don't have to put a value.
If, however, you choose to put a value, if it is not equal to null, then for each property in includes
I want to include to the query whatever property was asked for.
So this is the country then.
This group is going to run once.
If you have five foreign keys and you put all five of them in, that includes this, then this is going
to run five times, including each one.
Pretty much.
That's all I was going to do.
All right, so it's completely optional because there might be times when they need to include and there
are times when they don't need to for speed purposes, you don't want to intrude all the time for one
query, for one bit of information when you didn't have to.
So this helps us to keep the application kind of quicker than it would normally be if it included everything
all the time.
Then the next thing we want to do is return our wet query dot and then I'm going to say as no tracking.
So that's where that tracking thing comes in, because any record that is retrieved here is not being
tracked.
A copy is taken and it's sent into memory.
Syntel to the client, the database and into different words don't really care about it.
So that's why I don't hear.
We see I touch it.
So we get that record which wasn't being tracked or being looked at.
And then we say start looking at it and just note that it has been modified.
By the time it reaches here, it has been modified.
So we get Asmal tracking.
But then after that, what I really want to do is get the first our default record and there's a first
default async.
There we go.
And then I can see the expression.
So let me explain what the expression is, the expression is defined as expression, function t Boulin,
and that's the name of the parameter.
So this data that basically allows us to put in a lambda expression because then a lambda expression
would allow us to see something like Q and then the lambda arrow and then would say, query dot something
is equal to something else.
So that's why I said bool right.
Whatever condition.
So when we want to retrieve the one record, what is the condition that we want to use to retrieve the
one recorded by idea.
Is it by name.
So this allows it to be very generic and flexible because then we can write our different expressions
based on the context, but calling one method at any given time.
All right.
So that's it for the next four to get.
Sorry.
So the next one that we have to do is the get all right and get all is going to have all of that code
with some tweaks along the way.
So firstly, we're not going to be looking at any first our default.
So then we just modify this airline.
We get the query that as tracking and then I'm just going to make it go to the list is Sync.
All right, so that's why we have that.
Ones zero calling on asynchronous function.
You have to precede it with our.
All right.
So we're turning our list so we Biasutto list as opposed to this one where we just got the first our
default.
No, we have the same parameter for the includes, but we have another one for autobio.
So I'm going to put another little snippet right after.
Well, actually, I'm going to put two snippets in.
So firstly, we've got the query.
Then I'm going to check if there was an expression somewhere to filter the query first before I even
look at it includes someone to say if the expression is not equal to because we could be looking for
a list of records, but we want to see where the country is.
One on the sun.
Give me the list of hotels from Jamaica so we could put in the expression to see where whatever condition
is needed to specify from Jamaica.
And then if it is not, even if it is not equal to null meaning our condition is there, then filter
the query for me, please.
So query is equal to the initial query, which was all records dot where that expression is true.
Then after you've done that, because we could have had five hundred and know the filter, brought it
on to twenty, then you go ahead and put on the includes.
All right.
And then finally after you put on the interludes and everything, I would like you to order if necessary.
So if the person passed in that order by Oh I want it in descending, ascending or this or that, you
just see if it if the command came in, then queries equal to order by query.
All right.
So that's really all there is still to get and get all.
So we've gotten the majority of the work out of the way.
We have about two more steps to go and then we are done with this task.
So the next thing that we want to do is create that.
Well, I'm going to call it unit of work, right?
So we have the generic capacitor and we're going to give it the units of work framework on top.
So in iReports, etc..
I'm just going to go ahead and add what will be another interface.
So I'm just adding it and I'm quoting it all units of work, changing this to interface.
And this one is going to inherit from a disposable all right, and then what we're going to be defining
in our units of work would be it's going to act like our register for every variation of the generic
repository relative to the class T..
Right.
So right now, we only have two tables to cater for.
So I'm just going to see a generic repository for country.
Sorry for country.
And including the missing reference and I'm just going to call it countries, so different people have
different naming conventions here, I call it country.
Some people would say country repository or whatever.
I'm calling countries because when I call on needing to work, I can see this dot countries, dot whatever
operation I want to carry on.
Right.
So we're going to do that also for hotels or hotel.
And I'm calling the property hotels.
And then we're going to have one more operation, which is our task to save.
All right, so when we're carrying out all of these operations to add to the aid, we're making changes
to the context, but at this point, it's just staged, right?
So when we see save or save changes, then it will be affected.
So that is what this is for.
But this is outside of the repository, because if there are multiple changes to be made at that time,
then all of them can be caught in one operation as opposed to making multiple copies of the database.
So we have that unit of work.
The next thing would be to create the concrete glass so the repository will add class.
All units of work.
And then you and it's off work is going to inherit from units of work.
And once again, including missing references and then implement the interface.
All right, so then what this is really just going to do is say, all right, you normal countries,
what should I return when you call on countries from me?
What should I call on here?
What does disposals do?
What does Steve do?
Those are the things that we need to define.
So first, I'm going to include a reference to the database context.
Right.
Similar to what we had before, and then I'm going to define my constructor.
Or.
And try that again.
There we go, and I'm going to put in.
The context of the story to write it out again, so I'm just going to copy the relevant parts there
and paste.
There we go.
So I'm initializing the data context instead of the units of work here and the tool.
No, that's OK.
I have a copy of the data context also.
So then you're probably wondering, so why do I need the data context here?
And that is really because what we need to do is return an instance of the repository, but then we
have to backtrack a bit.
So I need to private the same way that we would have defined them over this side as private.
See if I can just do this quickly.
So I'm just going to take that and I'm going to define two private.
Properties of the respective hotel and and countries, but I'm going to rename them, I'm going to take
off the accessor, so this is going to be countries.
And this one is going to be hotels.
All right, so now that I have these private.
Properties, I'm going to say don't here that if the private property is empty, then return a new instance
of the generic repositories.
I'm not going to do that, Shata, because C Sharp nine is pretty cool.
So I can just say something like countries and then questionmark.
Questionmark equals.
So it's basically saying if this is null, then what should I do?
So instead of a whole if statement right now, just see if it is null, then return an object of the
generic repository of type country.
And of course, based on our definition of it, you need the database context, which is why we have
it injected here.
So we pass in the context.
Right.
And then I'm basically just going to do the same thing for Hota.
So this is like I register.
No, this is just like a roll dice to say that all of these are potential generic repositories.
Once you're in the network, I have access to the countries, the hotels and forever table that you
define.
You need to make sure that you put are you make representation for it in the eye unit of work as well
as the unit of work.
But all of what we just did with the generic repository in the itinerary repository, we don't have
to redo any of that with any other data table that we meet at in the future.
Right.
So it's just about maintaining this list and these functions to make sure that we have access to what
we need right here in our units of work register.
All right, so the next thing that we need to do or well, two more things, so I want to.
Define this pause and then we need to set up the scene and then we're done with this.
So this pause I'm going to kind of write this book was true.
So this is just the way I do it.
You may see variations of the units of work elsewhere, but this is the way that I have come to do it
for various reasons.
Once again, context is king.
So what I'm seeing here is I'm going to call another method.
So I'm going to define a method here.
Just that visual studio generates a method right underneath it for that purpose.
And then I'm just going to say, well, actually know that I'm doing it.
I'm just going to see right here on the score context.
So this pause is really like a garbage collector is just seeing when I'm done or when the operations
are done.
Please free up the memory.
That's that's the purpose here is actually short for garbage collector.
If you look at the description, garbage collector.
So this is seeing when this is called, then please dispose of the context, meaning kill any memory
that the connection to the database was using the connection, all the resources it was using, and
go ahead and do what it would do by default anyway.
So that is it for the disposal.
The next one would be our Sèvres changes.
And this one is actually pretty simple because it's really only one line, at least right now, where
we see await context, dot safe changes async.
Here's the arrow.
I'm seeing it.
But what don't I have?
I don't have the async.
Once I put that there, everything is fine in the world.
So let me just build to see if I have broken anything or if there's anything out of place and I have
a successful build.
So that means I've successfully put in the code for my units of work, at least code wise are syntactically
later on we'll find out if it works or not.
But right now, this is a good victory to have and this task is done.