Hey, guys, welcome back.
So we're going to continue our journey into setting up our authentication for our API and we'll be setting
up this endpoint for user WAN registration and to log in and by extension, authentication.
No, I've already kind of cheated and gone ahead and set up the new controller so you can pause and
go ahead and get up to speed controllers.
But it creates a brand new controller that's blank and call its account controller.
And I already went ahead and kind of started doing my injections.
So, too, you're familiar with to you would be seeing for the very first time.
So you already know the logger and the mopper.
So I don't need to explain those in any great detail.
However, you will be seeing user manager and sign in manager potentially for the first time.
These are two built in libraries courtesy of identity core.
So when you typed them, you may want to include the missing reference and you'll see those start to
appear on top.
No, notice the context for the user manager and for the signing manager is API user or whatever the
custom user class is that you would have used when you were setting up identity.
If you didn't use one, then you continue to use identity use.
So whatever class it is that you set as your context in your configuration and the configuration would
be here.
Whatever class you set there, you continue to use that throughout the application.
All right.
So.
User manager gives us access to a bunch our suite of functions that allow us to manage Cioni and retrieve
user information of users so we don't have to write any custom code to be adding or I don't have to
go and put in any unit of work functions for user user table interaction or rule table interaction.
All of those things come out of the box with the user manager sign in manager and you have another one
called the rules manager.
If we need to use it, then we will.
But I'm just letting you know that most of those things are encapsulated in these services, which can
easily be injected into our application.
So now that we have set up our controller and injected all of what we need, we need to start writing
our endpoint.
So our first endpoint is going to be for registration.
So it's going to look something like this public async task action result.
And the name is Register for Registration.
Since we'll be requiring potentially sensitive data.
Well, not potentially.
We'll be requiring username, password and so on.
I don't want to send that across the pipe in the parameter.
So we disclose that in the overview video where we're seeing that using the parameters quite fine when
it's something like this, just an ID, nothing to dummying.
Right.
But then when you get to asking, I use it to register and submit sensitive information.
You don't want to just start seeing stream emails, string password, etc, because then everything
will actually come across in plain text over to the to the endpoint.
So we want to do is make this one a post.
So we, we have done work with the get verb.
We haven't done much work or any work with the Post.
So a post is just like when you're submitting a form on the Internet, when you click submit to go to
let's say sign up for Facebook or sign up for something online.
If you look in the you are on top.
You don't see any of the information being listed or do you just know that your information left one
page and supposedly went somewhere and the other page could represent it?
That's what the post operation is, right.
So the message is encapsulated and kind of hidden from prying eyes.
When we do, I get it is sent across four in plain sight, just like what we saw here.
So there's no reason to it.
So of course, when you're dealing with sensitive information, you don't want to use a guitar or anything
that will not hide the information that's being sent across.
So with that considered, the parameter that we're going to use here is going to be a custom one.
So I'm going to put in an annotation to see get the information from body so the sender needs to send
it in the body as opposed to in the euro, in the body of the request.
And then we can specify data type that should take the information.
So I'm going to say user details.
I've created user D to yet, but I'm just going to say user DTL.
All right.
So let us go ahead and create this user, DTL, and then I'll explain why it can work that out.
So in models, we click on class, we're calling user DTL and then user to needs to have at minimum
the same feels that we one need to back to our API user and two, we need the user to provide.
So this is how I am designing my user details so you can pause replicated, but I'm going to walk you
through it anyway.
So first name, last name.
When registering you have the option to pass those two fields over notice.
I said the option because I'm sitting neither as required.
We have the phone number.
So if you want, you can send us your phone number and area to search for the API once again not required.
However, email is definitely required and password is definitely required.
And then for email will actually be using this as the user name also.
So if we have this DTL, as usual, we have to make sure that our mopper knows about the deal.
So mopper initialise or I'm just going to go ahead and see that API user and user DTL need to know about
each other and reverse map.
All right.
And so that is what we will do.
So the purpose of the from Buddy here is to see that when when a request hits this end point, you will
look in the body after request, don't look in the mirror.
So, one, I'm not requiring anything in the euro.
And two, if the user passes anything in the euro, I don't care.
I'm not looking for any information in the euro.
However, the body of the request should contain information with fields that match up to the user.
DTL So this and more information than I need it will be ignored.
But at minimum, they must send these to for me to process it so that so everything kind of ties in
when we talk about sanitising requests and making decisions based on what is coming across the pipe.
All right.
So let us go back to our current controller and then what we want to do at this point, and we can do
a number of things.
So I'm going to reverse the trend log and see registration attempt came in for and this I copied and
pasted.
That's kind of primitive myself.
But let's say a registration attempt for user DTL dot email.
Right, so whatever email came in over, to use a little, that's what I'm putting there.
So I'm going to also check if the valid state, if it is in a valid state so I can see if model state.
So this is over five farms, right, if you do if you have done NVC and this is your just learning EPA,
it's pretty much the same process.
We're going to see if modern state is valid.
Right.
So at this point, I would probably say if it is not valid, then I'm going to return a bud request.
So that means you sent over a request to register, but your validation failed.
So you didn't include the email.
It didn't include or you didn't meet whatever standards I would have laid out for you regarding the
data you should have sent.
Right.
And then I can return the model state so that it will kind of inform the senator what went wrong.
All right.
So if model state is not valid, then we do that.
Otherwise we can proceed to try.
So just try to keep tab.
And I'll catch that exception, so let me just deal with the exception part of it, where I'm going
to see.
Log arrow, something went wrong in that register section and then in previous times, what did we do?
We returned with a status code.
Five hundred.
So another type of return that you can do when there was a problem is literally a return problem.
And you would put in the same kind of message so I could put in something went wrong.
Right, and then tell it that it tells us that a squad of five on some of the shooting, that there
are different ways.
You know, if you are looking at other resources, you may see me do it this way and somebody else returning
our problem.
Somebody is returning the status code manually.
There are different ways to do this.
All right.
But then for the ones that are built in are to give you the methods, I generally encourage you to just
use those.
So we've taken care of the bad situations.
I'd like to just see if it is not right to do this now.
What do I do when it is right?
One, I can say if the user is equal to mopper dot mob into API user and then I am being user DTL.
So then it will say, OK, how much all the fields which we know already, we know how the map works
by now and then know that I have the user, I can see var results.
Is equal to and I went to await a call to my user manager, Dots, and then here's here's a bunch of
functions.
Like I said, we can do a number of things.
I can say create async.
So user manager, create a sink and then I'll just pass in the user objects.
All right, so go ahead and create that user, it will automatically take it to the password, hash
it, store it, do everything it needs to do.
We didn't have to write any complex logic to really facilitate that.
Right.
But then sometimes things fail.
So I'm going to say, if not result, not succeeded.
We'll tell you.
Did it succeed or not?
Then I'm going to also return a budget request.
So, you know, I'm going to say something went wrong this time.
It's not a model state thing.
It's probably just an arrow.
So the thing is that the results object actually gives you the arrows.
If you really need to list, the military can probably put them in a loop list, then put them in one
string and return them if you want if you want to give the user that much detail.
But sometimes those details can be too sensitive.
So you have to be careful what information you're sending back to the calling client.
Right.
So at this point, I'm just going to say.
But request it was a four hundred and it is because the user registration fee, that's all you need
to know.
So try again later because this could have been my fault.
Otherwise, if it was something serious, would have given them a 500 to know.
It is on our side that the problem is and if it is that you send incorrect data, then I'm telling you
what is incorrect, because the model states will list that out.
Right.
And that's pretty much it for the register.
Now, since we've done the register, I think we might as well just do the log in because I don't know
really to test our registers, to test the log in.
Right.
So I'm actually just going to copy and paste this code.
Right below, but what we need to do is change the action names, so this is a log in action.
We're using the same user detail we're taking from the same YORO from the same body, started ignoring
anything coming in the euro.
And then what we're going to do is see a login attempt for this user if it is invalid.
Once again, validation constraints, email, password, no.
One thing that we may want to consider is do we need the same data?
Should we use ACMD to you for a login that register same principle with the other details?
Right.
Because for a login, I don't need your first name, last name, phone number.
I only want your email and password.
So what I'll do here is quickly adjust to a class to see a log in Etel and I'm going to take these two
fields, put in just a login because it's absolutely necessary for login stuff.
But then I let this inherit from login so the fields are shared across the board regardless.
All right.
So I should log in.
User need to go.
Let my mopper know that it is.
Do I even need to map or.
No, I really don't need to let the mother know about this one because the operation is going to be
slightly different.
So I leave user detail in the upper, but I won't put this one and I'll explain why.
So logging user need to do so once again.
This is another part of security when we sanitize exactly what we want, because if the user may have
included malicious sorry, the client or the user sending the request, the client sending the request
could have included malicious information in the body of the request.
By doing this part here, I am saying that I am only looking for feels that match what I have outlined
in this all say this and more information that I need.
It's going to be ignored regardless.
So that's another part of the security considerations when creating APIs.
So we get the login user need to and then for the login.
OK, well we validate it.
OK, good.
So we checked the model state and then what I'm going to try.
So nothing much has to change here except maybe the log messages just to make sure that we are accurately
representing where what went wrong.
All right.
So under the tree, what we're going to do, I don't need to do any mapping.
So let me just remove what's in, try and start from scratch.
I am going to see if the result is equal to.
And then this is where we use the signing manager, not password signing is.
So you see that and he can even do a check, you can check to see if the password would be part of the
solution design.
And of course, that doesn't help the situation at this point because we want to actually sign it.
Right.
So signing async takes two overlord's.
We can parsing the whole user object.
I just took all the mapping and the password.
Or we can choose to just put in the user name and password, which is the one I'm going to use both
options.
So if we kept them up in passing the whole user object as well as the password in this case, I took
it also.
Just see a user, DTL Dot, and we're using the email address as a username and user your password and
then is persistent.
So let's read what is assistances.
It says Flug, indicating whether the signing cookie should persist after the browser is closed.
No, I this is an API.
I don't know what kind of application is calling the API.
Could be postman.
It could be the browser, it could be a mobile app.
I don't need to persist anything so to see falls.
Right.
And then the last one, Lochlyn feel.
I don't want to lock anybody when they fail to log in.
That would be too much of an administrative overhead.
Once again, context is everything, but this is what our signing code looks like.
No, the result is going to be a similar object to the register attempt.
So we can just say if results are sorry, if not result, not successful.
Oh, sorry, this is asynchronous.
So when we fail to put on the weight, then the result that we're going to get is off type Tosk, not
of the type that we are expecting.
So let me make sure I put on the weight.
And then when I do that you'll see that the Intellisense isn't giving me what I would expect.
So if it is not successful, let me just double check what we did when it wasn't successful here.
Then we will say we see a budget request up top.
But if it's an unsuccessful logging attempt, it's not necessarily a bad response.
But I would just say our budget requests are what I would say is unauthorized.
Right, which is a four or one, if I'm not mistaken or unauthorized, and I can probably just return
the user detail to see this is what they attempted to use.
It's unauthorized.
I'm sorry.
All right.
Otherwise, if it gets this far, that means everything is OK.
So we'll just return.
I could return, OK?
I've used accepted in the past.
Right.
So anything with that two hundred in the 200 range would be seen as an OK response.
So, OK, it's 200 you have created, which is I think a tool for you have accepted, which is still
two, etc. You don't have to worry about memorizing these codes necessarily.
Just know that in particular situations you want to use this one.
All right.
So then that is what our login function will look like.
And OK, I thought that made a change.
Just not.
All right.
So let us or the register is seeing that not all code path's return of value.
Oh, that is why I am so sorry I missed this one old.
So remember that you always have to have a financial return, so the same way that we said that your
statement does this, but we return, accept it afterwards, have to do that here so I could return
accepted.
Of top here also, right, I have accepted your registration attempt and then that is done.
No, before we move on to testing.
I want to bring something very important to your attention, and that is the routine considerations
for this endpoint where it established that the route would be controlled or in this case, EPP's account.
In previous times, let's say the hotel controller, we would have determined that we can't have two
identical get operations.
The name of the action is irrelevant, but I can't have two operations having identical verbs.
The verb can be the same, but then there must be some nuance to one implementation of the verb from
the other.
In this situation, I have both as forced.
Both of them are paused once again.
The name here doesn't matter, but they are both post, which means that if I attempt to do any post
operation, it's going to not know which one to use.
They're both kind of identical in terms of what they're expecting.
The only way I can really differentiate between these two is to give them their own roots.
Right.
So I can see the route for register is register.
And then the route for a log in.
Is log in so that we're at this point, the only way to hit register is to see a server slash API slash
O'Collins slash register as a post request.
The only way to log in is to see whatever slash API slash icon slash log in some specifying that the
route for this endpoint is log in and this one is register.
That way they can have identical verbs, but because there are different locations, they won't interfere
with each other.
All right.
So let's take this one, spin this, trying to register a user real quick.
So when we check out what Slogger has generated for us, you notice it doesn't append anything to call
for ID here and there they are no post not get right.
And then if I spun, they'll show me what the object needs to look like or can look like when it is
coming across the pipe.
All right.
Just for those the same for log in.
So you see the difference.
Remember that we have two different details.
This one has email password and the customer feels this one only takes email and password.
So that's what I was saying, that when in a situation when you don't need all the information you create,
I need you to limit exactly what you need in that situation.
All right.
So let us try with the registration attempt.
So I'm going to leave that that email.
I'm going to put in some password that has characters and a number.
And I want to leave everything else blank because all I really need are email and password.
However, by leaving these as they are, they're literally going to go over as string, string and phone
number.
So let's see what happens when we execute.
All right.
And this attempt is giving me a five hundred error.
So this would have been one of those exceptions caught on.
Itzin cannot resolve a particular service for the sign in manager.
All right.
So the assignment manager is giving a problem.
And I would like to sit down and troubleshoot it.
But when I'm thinking about it, I really don't need the signing manager for this API.
And I'm going to explain.
So when I put in sign in manager and injected it and all of these things, it was because that's like
a knee jerk reaction.
Whenever we have authentication to do, we want all the libraries that can help with authentication.
Right.
However, in the case of a Web application where somebody would submit a login attempts through a form
click submit and then be told they are logged in through some message or some indication, as is Hillal
username, that is really the signing manager creating something like a session or a cookie based on
the configuration setup for managing that user session in terms of an API.
We are not going to be maintaining a session for any user.
Yes, you were just there.
But we don't know when you're going to be calling the API how long.
And it's not like you're going to be lingering inside the API for one hour if you cause the API is going
to accept your request to give you a response and be finished.
That is why we're using tokens.
So I don't want to get too much ahead of myself and start discussing tokens.
But because of the tokens, we really don't need the signing manager in the traditional sense of what
the signing manager does.
So I'm going to remove all references to the sign in managerially and I'm going to comment on the login
endpoint for no.
So that's control.
Casey, just to comment.
I really don't need all of this just yet, so we'll get there.
But I just got ahead of myself and I apologize.
Sometimes these things happen, but hey, we're just going to come on the code and then we'll revisit
it later on.
Now, as it relates to some of the error messages that we want to send back, what I'm going to do here
is kind of add all the result arrows.
So I did see you could find a way to put the result arrows in a package and send someone to see for
each error in results, not errors.
I did say it could be sensitive information, so I'm accepting that risk.
But I want to see model state.
Not and I can see at Model Arrow, which is then going to ask me for a key, I don't have to put in
the key and then I'm going to see error.
Dotts, sorry, error being the error message coming back from the results attempt code.
So, all right, here's what I do.
I put the code as the key.
All right, so the key there really means what's the name of the arrow and then the core there, a description
would be right there.
Right.
And then we can see by request, user attempt failed or I just set the model state because it's already
obvious that it failed.
So that's how we'll proceed with the Arrow messages for our registration.
So let's just try this one more time.
All right.
So we're back in Swiger with the log and points, but we're going to just try to put in my complicated
password once again and then execute.
All right.
And this looks a bit better.
So first off, we're not getting any complaints about any user manager or any service not being registered.
That's one tool we're seeing here that we're getting back to four hundred and we're getting back some
details as to what is wrong.
So invalid user name, user name, blank blank is is invalid and can only contain letters or digits.
All right.
So that is because we did a mapping, but we're only asking for email.
The actual identity user has to have a user name value also.
So what I need to do here is to specify that user dot user name is equal to the email address.
So email address is required.
Field user name is a required field and password.
They're all required fields by the identity user.
So I was only providing email and password.
I'm just going to go ahead and provide the user name also, which is the same as the email address.
All right.
So let's just try that one more time.
And when I do that and I put in the same details, user after example and password one, look at what
we get.
We get our two hundred response.
Right.
And what is just telling us everything is good to go.
So it does not feel there is no validation, error or anything like that.
I notice that it is undocumented for the tool to.
That's because we didn't let the controller know or let Swiger know that Tool two is a potential return
type.
So remember that we did that with the other controllers where we listed the potential return types so
you can go ahead and replicate that in the account controller.
But for now, we set up our distribution process.
I know you might be disappointed that you're not getting to test the login one just yet, but it's really
not a login.
It's more it's going to be more like an affinity and authorization to see, OK, you have a token and
it's valid.
Yes, you can access the resource you want because once again, a login really is to create a session
and allow somebody to access the system for a period.
Whereas with that, with an API, we don't know what period you may need access for.
We don't need to facilitate you for a longer period than it takes to process your request and give you
your response.
So we just want to know that you are unacceptable accessor.
Validate that, give you what you want and then we're done with you.
So that is why we'll be doing the toolkits.
So when we get there, we will go ahead and have more how we restrict access.