Welcome back, guys, in this lesson, we're going to be configuring our course policy, of course,
is an acronym for Cross Origin Resource Sharing, and this is just a mechanism that allows you to allow
or restrict the sharing of resources across domains.
So let me say that in a bit more English.
When somebody who is not on your network tries to access your API by default, your API is going to
reject that access request.
All right.
So if I develop an internal API to be used in my company and somebody from outside my company with a
completely different IP address and everything tries to consume the API or talk to the API, then it's
going to automatically know that, hey, well, I can't send you any information because I don't know
you.
So we want to configure this policy to at least facilitate some conversation with sources are requesters
that are not necessarily in our network.
All right.
So I've actually run into this before.
I developed an API for my company for third party use, and I spent some time debugging why this company
couldn't access the API that was clearly working on my machine and every other machine around me.
And then after digging, I realized it was the course policy.
So sometimes you live on, you learn, you learn through experience.
Well, I'm here to just let you know what configurations you can put in place from the get go to kind
of avoid certain busywork.
So in order to add this policy, what we're going to do is in our startup case file and I'm just going
to add to your order does matter to some extent.
But right now we're not really focusing on the order.
We just want to get our configurations in someone to see services, not add.
Cause.
And then I'll just put the semicolon there.
So when we say, of course, we need to add the policy, like CRS needs to know how to behave.
Right.
So the same way that when we're setting up the other the Swiger, Jen Psaki would say, see?
And then they slam the arrow and then we can have multiple lines with multiple configurations.
You could see it within points and so on.
We're going to be doing that here.
So I'm going to see or you can use any tool can really doesn't it could be.
C could be or it could be the word options.
Like I said, do you see them using endpoints stone here.
So I just say or and then the lambda arrow and then what I'm going to do is open and close curly braces.
So that means I'm going to have a whole block of configuration.
So I'm just breaking the line so we can see clearly exactly what's what.
And then I'm going to say or not add policy.
All right, so I'm adding up policy, then I have to give it a name, so first Burm is the name, I'll
just call it cause policy, nothing too fancy or confusing.
So, of course, policy and then comma.
And then I have to define another lambdas.
I just call this one builder because now I'm going to be building the policy.
So Builder Lambda Arrow and I just break line.
So I going to say builder dot.
Allow any.
So here are all the options before I start setting them.
These are all the options you can allow any can disallow.
You can sit.
So if it is white listed or with certain headers, you can define whole your API will determine who
is allowed to access me or my resources and who is not for no for an occasional purposes, because later
on maybe we can look at the securing of it and how we mix and match.
But then once again, context is everything.
If you are developing an API for Internet and third party use, then you can't be too strict with the
API if ever anybody should be able to get on.
Otherwise, you're going to have an administrative overhead of trying to figure out who is who all the
time.
So I'm just going to say hello.
Any origin.
And I'm just going to chain along alone any method, meaning they can access every method that every
endpoint that is defined here, and then I'm going to say allow in the header, sorry I any header.
Right.
And then I'll close the briefs for the policy and then use semicolon.
So that's my course policy that's undefined.
So I'm just allowing every and anybody once you're coming to access my API, you can go ahead and use
the resources.
Once again, context is everything that will determine how strict you are with your your course policy.
No, after doing all of that, I'm No one to go down to configure and I'm going to let the app know
that it should use the course policy.
So right here I'm just going to set up not use cause.
There we go, and then he's going to say, OK, it does some overlord's, I'm going to tell it to the
Palestinians.
And so just by putting the quotation marks, it's an old saying, OK, what's a Palestinian sort of
Palestinian, as I just outlined on top is course policy.
So maybe you could make it a bit more informative.
You could see a loaf of bread because that's all it's really doing.
This policy is allowing someone to say use the policy that says, all right, so that's what the course
policy is really for.
So at this in this situation, we're not going to fully see the benefit of it.
But then if you've done any other project where you have the API and then you have an entirely different
project, which is the client project, which means it is being broadcast, it's a different IP address
than our port than the current API project.
Once they try to talk, that will not work until you have this policy in place.