Hey, guys, we'll come back and business and we'll be talking about versioning, our API now, the
reason you'd want to version our API is that over time, more functionality will evolve.
There are times when we may change the way our endpoints behave changed.
Some verbs are the way the payload is structured, all of those things.
But then you don't want to just do that.
And then all of your clients one day wake up and realize that they have to change the entire code base
because you implemented a change in your API.
So versioning, the API allows you to kind of run a parallel between the old way of doing things and
the new way of doing things.
And then eventually you can phase out the the one that all the clients have, of course, after adequate
warning and education, are the new de facto standard that you're introducing.
So right now, we want to talk about versioning and our journey is going to start right here in in you
get where we're going to get the Microsoft is spinet core MVC version in the library so it can go ahead,
search for that and install it.
And then after you've done that, we're going to go with the service extensions and we're going to add
a new function and we're calling this one configure version.
Of course, you know, you can call it whatever you're comfortable with, but right now we're calling
it configure versioning.
And then inside this function, we're going to have codes militarily.
So we're seeing services that are API versioning, and then we're going to include an option initialization
where we're seeing a report API versions.
True.
So report API versions means that there will be a header in our response is seeing this is the version
that you are using.
So when our clients talk to the API, we're going to see in their response.
Yes, you just hit this API version.
We're going to assume the default version when unspecified.
So if we have one, two, three API versions and the client failed to specify that they want to use
version one, three, etc, then we're just going to use a default one, which we have gone ahead and
specified below where we said the default API version is going to be API version one.
So you can go ahead and include any missing references as usual.
And then after you've done all of that, we can go over to the Start-Up and we can register our service.
So just put that one below here.
All right.
Now, what we're going to do is create a new controller.
So I'm just going to go to add controller will choose an API and I'll just leave it empty and then,
for example, say, OK, I'm going to call this one country V two.
All right.
So Country V two controller.
So we have a new controller.
And I'm just going to initialize it with some of the things from the original Cloninger controller.
So I'm just going to copy all of these things.
So I'm just I just want one endpoints just for testing purposes.
So the one endpoint that we're dealing with will be to get to go ahead and include any missing reference.
Well, actually, I'm going to change the way this one accesses data.
So instead of it using the unit of work, I'm going to let it implement the DB context directly.
So this is private data base context.
So, of course, remember that that is taboo.
You don't you don't really want to do that.
While it will work, it's not best practice to have the API looking directly at the data.
But for this example, I'll just do that so that we have a different return type between the two controllers.
So just go ahead and initialize this as quickly as possible, and then once that is done, once that
is injected and this is Contrave to controller.
All right.
So we can specify the Routier to be the same thing as the original contract because remember, they
all go to the controller.
Right.
So this will be API slash country.
However, this by default would be API slash Contrave tool.
But what if I said I don't want the controller name, I want to be the same endpoint?
Now, if it's the same endpoint by default, the API would not know where to go because it's going to
see this one with the route and see this one with the same route and it wouldn't know where to go.
Now what I can do is specify that this one is API version and then specify that this one is 2.0.
All right.
That should be a string.
So API version 2.0.
So what will happen, though, is that the client will need to specify which endpoint it is that they
hope to hit.
All right.
So I'm just going to hurry up and clean this up.
We don't have any request firearms in this situation.
And I just cleaned up the rest of it so I didn't want to bore you with my cleaning up.
But this is all that we're doing.
We're just seeing get countries and it's going to return context that countries, which is just going
to get the list of countries in the database and return to that side.
So the return type here will be different from the DTA return type of our original endpoint.
All right.
So let us take this for a test drive and see how this works.
Now, if you remember in our configuration, we had said that we should assume the default version when
unspecified.
So what we did here was just to repeat the same call that we always do to our endpoints.
You just said Ipswitch Country and we're getting back to our countries.
But then no, if you look in the header section, you'll see that the API supported versions, one point
or two, recall that our configuration would have set 1.0 as our default rate.
So that is working and realizes that there are versions and it's returning the results that from the
default one.
Now, how do we get our client to know how to specify which version they want?
There are a few ways to do this.
Number one, we can requested by a query string so we can see if you want the other one, you pass in
via course.
Our Param.
Let's just put it in the Palm API dush version and then we would say two point two and then they send
you would see that we get back two hundred.
Okay.
And the supportive version is two point or so.
Let me let me put this into a bit more context so we can visualize it.
So we know that we have two controllers, we have Controller Contrave two, which has the same route
as the original one, someone to put breakpoints at their respective functions.
And then we're going to see which one gets hit based on which request.
So I'm just going to repeat the request for version 2.0.
And then when Visual Studio lights up, you see it is hitting the new controller that we set up using
the same endpoint, except we're passing in the screen that we want version two.
All right.
So I can continue it.
It's the database and it returns the data accordingly.
And that's fine.
But then if I don't include the param and then do the same request notice it's hitting our original.
So that's it.
So we can have more than one controllers with the same route, except there are different versions.
So that is a quick way for the client to specify that they want version two.
If they don't specify, then we're going to send them to version one.
Know another way that we can do this.
And I'm just going to stop this right now, another way that we can specify which one is which version
or allow the client to specify which version they want is to modify the route.
So I can actually kind of superimpose right here in between the word API and the endpoint name and see
that I want you to pass in the colon and the API version.
All right.
So when we do that and I on, I'm going to kind of modify the original endpoint request.
So initially we had API slash country slash.
We put in the string to get version 2.0, but then I modify the route so I should be able to see two
point.
All right, here in the euro, so API slash 2.0 slash country and I still have the breakpoint.
Yes, I do.
So let's see if it gets hit.
And it does get to it, so you see, that's another way that the the client can specify which version
of the API they want and endpoint.
So version 2.0, the specified 2.0.
So it hits the appropriate endpoint.
No, there might be a situation where you don't necessarily want to augment the you are because right
now we have to augment or we are forcing the clients that they have to change their base URLs.
So they have to see the slash API slash 2.0 slash endpoint after postin as a query stream.
So another way that we can get the versioning to work, let me just stop the bug is to add a configuration
to our service extension for versioning where we see option dot API version the reader.
And if we just take a little look at what this is doing, it is seeing it's it's used to read the API
service when specified by a client.
All right.
So then we can see a new header API version reader.
So what is it about the incoming request that we want to read, write saucing, want the header API
version reader and we are looking for a header by the name of API version.
So this will allow us to one, not only keep our route the way we had it before, but enable the client
to just add a header instead of having to change their entire YORO.
So let us try that one.
So buckin postman, I'm just going to remove the 2.0 from our YORO and then what I will do is specify
in the header sections of headers selected API dash version.
So that's the new header that's I want to pass over 2.0 and then when I send that we hit our break point
in our version 2.0 controller.
All right.
So quite a few ways you have different functionalities or different methods of doing things instead
of introducing too many breaking changes all into the code base that everybody's already subscribed
to, you can phase in and you want to just call it version this version that and have them pass in the
header for the appropriate version when needed.
No.
One more thing that I'm going to show you on this topic is how you can specify that something is deprecated.
So in a situation and I'm just going to continue using this one because this is an experiment, let's
say that a version 3.0.
So Version 2.0 is deprecated or it's no longer the preferred version.
So you can actually add to the annotation here that the deprecated value of this API version is true.
So what would happen is that when it sends the header across for a response and we can test that here.
So this was this is a previous request.
So I'm going to run another request, hit the breakpoints, continue.
But then look at it.
And this is not an API deprecated version 2.0.
So, no, it's no longer just saying, oh, you're hitting the API version is letting you know that
this one is no longer the preferred one.
Right.
It's probably near the end of life, whatever it is.
So those are ways that you can actually implement versioning in your API to help control how you feel
seeing your changes as you go along.