Hey, guys, one quick addendum to what was done in the previous activity, setting up the registration
endpoints and everything, it worked.
However, when I checked the data, I realized that my user did not have a password, and that's because
I did not put this part on.
So if you look at the create user function.
It has to overtones, one where it just creates the user and another one where it asks you for the user
and the password to go with them.
So I'm not entirely sure why they feel the need to me to because for me, a user has to have a password.
But I guess for different situations, they may need to store something on the other.
So user karma and then from the user need to go to the password so that we can ensure that when the
user manager creates that user, that password is also going to get touched and stored on their record.