Hey, guys, welcome back.
So in this lesson, we're going to be setting up our data transfer objects and we'll be using Autumn
Upper to kind of automate the process of linking our detail to our domain objects.
So let me give a little background as to what a deal or data transfer object is.
No, it really is a part of a pattern where we try to decouple our domain object, meaning remember,
this is representing our database table.
We try to decouple this from the user interaction.
So we don't want users to be interacting directly with this class when they send and receive information
through our API.
So we have details as kind of like a middle layer, which will enforce certain validations at the front
in part, and we can do quite a few things that extends the flexibility so we can use that to kind of
sanitize the data before it actually gets over to our data class and by extension, our database.
No autum upper is a library that will actually facilitate us creating what we call mappings to say that
this detail matches this data class.
So let's firstly try to set up a data transfer object.
So in our project, I'm going to create a new folder and this folder I'm just going to call it models.
The details are like models.
So if you're used to using MVC or even Rezo pages or some other non, you're familiar with the word
model.
These two is just a fancy way of seeing a model, but it's usually use in terms of APIs.
So you can name that for the models if you want to name it details so that you know exactly what it
is.
That's fine, but I'll just stick with models now instead of our models folder.
We generally have a number of classes that represent each maybe variation of a request relative to each
domain object.
So let's start off with country.
So country has three fields.
All right.
So I'm going to create a detail that will allow us to interact with country or have another layer.
So I'm going to call it Country DTL, and that's my naming convention.
I put on the table to the end of the same name.
Right, because I don't want to country here and there.
And then I make a modification to one and then it turns out this was the wrong one.
So by name, in detail, you can clearly see which one is not the D2 on which one is right.
So go ahead, create country detail and really and truly the detail needs to look similar to.
The actual domain knowledge you're probably seeing, OK, so why the duplication, because you just
created another class in another folder just to give it about the same properties as well.
At this point, I did say we can add validation so I can see that the name is required.
Right.
So that means when a user is going to interact with the detail, this annotation is going to say you
cannot send me information for this deal without this value.
So if it's not their validation, we can also stipulate other things like the string length.
And then we can see maximum length is 150 or whether this is a country so let's say no country should
ever have a name longer than 50 characters.
I've done my research, but let's just work with 50, right.
And if I wanted to give a specific error message, if this was violated, I can send error messages
equal to country name is too long.
So if this validation for the string length for name is violated, then this is the error message.
So you can always annotate the DTL such that when the user is interacting with the DTL, where handling
certain things to make sure that we're not exceeding are going outside of the band of what we want our
data quality to be after they have successfully gone through this validation, then we will go ahead
and do the mapping between the Beatle and the country.
So the principle is that the user will never see country will never see the data class and the database
will never see the details.
So users interact here.
And then in the middle we transfer the data from here to here and then pass it onto the database.
So other validations that we can add and just add that to short name here.
I'll see a sharp name is also required and the maximum length for the short name would be to write an
error message.
Short name.
Our short Clinton, Mrs. Clinton, your name not, is too long.
We can always mix and match and jam these up and there are other annotations that we can add along the
way.
But these two are the ones that I'll use right now for the D to you know, there is also an extension
or extending this button a little bit more where we create details per operation.
So when we start developing our controller, our controllers will start looking at the different types
of operations and verbs.
And then what people do are doing some cases that they have a detail per operations.
They have a detail for reading, you have a detail for creating, you have a detail for updating, because
the reality is that there are some times when you don't need to provide certain information.
So somebody is creating a country.
I don't need them to have the field for ID.
Right.
So the detail that I would like them to interact with would be create.
Contrary to your and you won't get that opportunity to provide a value for the ID because we really
don't need the value for the ID, so generally speaking, you have to have the country or have the best
deal and then I have one for free because once again, creates doesn't need the ID.
All right.
So when we're doing our verbs, you'll actually see the difference between how we use either one.
I know what I'm putting it in the same file.
Single responsibility pattern can take precedence here.
And you do each one in its own file like we did for the domain classes.
Or since this is a small application, I just put all the details that are related to one domain inside
of the same file, just in separate classes with the appropriate names.
So I'm going to pause here and I'm going to challenge you to go ahead and do the same thing for hotel,
create the detail and go ahead and put on some validations for the field.
Right.
So I hope you took on that challenge.
And I am here to show you what I did know.
If you did it and you have no errors, that's really good.
I did it slightly differently.
So I'm just going to walk you through the thinking behind what I have done here for the hotel detail.
So I flipped the script instead of creating the hotel detail and then creating the create version.
What I did was I created the create version and then I let it inherit, let the detail, the biggest
one inherit from the create and I'll explain that decision.
Now, going back to what we just did with the country, do you notice that we repeated the fields?
Right.
I yds in one, but not in the other.
But then we repeated Neme and actually refactor this one.
Also we repeated name and chaat name.
Right.
So what I did was to see what are the common fields and what are the unique fields otherwise.
So I'd, I only really need idee when I am going to do an update or I'm going to look at the details
or something that's not a create operation.
Right.
So I have the create detail, which is going to have all the fields that are absolutely necessary for
the creation.
There are also absolutely necessary if you're looking for the details or if you're going to do it right.
And once again, you have variation.
So if it is that you wanted a detail that only allows you to update the name and that's what you want
to expose that user behavior to only the name of the country, but not the short name.
You know, just for example, seek, then you could create a detail that his update, country name,
detail and all it exposes is the name field.
So you have all of those options.
So I'm not going that granular into it.
So what I'm doing is defining one where the ID is not present and that's what will handle the create
operations are the non ID required operations.
And then I have the best one which is inheriting from the one that has all the other fields.
So the best one has ID and it's inheriting so it automatically has access to everything that was defined
that way.
I don't need to repeat my validations because initially I had the same validations twice in the file
and for as many other details as I may have defined, I would have had these validations again and again
and again.
So that was my thinking here.
So I extended that ideology to the hotel detail.
So I have the create totally two, which has its validation for the name.
Right.
I'm sorry, I copied and pasted.
I didn't even change this missive.
So that's hotel name is too long, address is too long and you have maximum length.
You can add minimum length.
You probably want to add many moments to short name because they need to provide at least one one character
or even name one character is is needed.
Right.
So going back to a hotel detail, we have that validation for the name of that validation for the address
for the rating.
And let me just put some space so we can see where everything starts and stops.
There we go.
So for the rating, it's required and I set our range of one to five because the rating needs to be
between a one star rating or a five star rating.
Of course, we're using double because you have four point five, four point one, one point five,
etc. So the range here just is whatever numeric value is, there needs to be between these numbers and
then the country ID is required.
No, no, it's have country ID, but unlike the domain class, I didn't define country.
And also missing from the create is the ID.
So these two are missing because of creation.
All I need is the ID.
All the database is going to see is the ID.
It's not going to.
To see the actual entity or anything coming from that field know that field does become necessary.
However, when I need to see the detail so like we describe, instead of going and running another query
to find out which country has the ID that was provided here, I can just one include and get the country
details included.
So that is why in the best detail and I don't like calling this one the base usually inherited from
the base.
So when I said base, I just mean the one that is not necessarily as specific for an operation.
So I'm using it loosely, but I'm just explain myself so I don't confuse you guys.
So hotel detail is inheriting all the fields that were outlined in the create version of it, but then
it includes the ID and it includes an object of type country deal.
So it would have been easy enough to just copy the fields over and you wouldn't be wrong.
You don't need to specify a foreign Florentin the detail once again, that's customer facing.
It's not database centric, so it doesn't really care if it's a foreign car and not to just says, OK,
I need an integer because I was defined as I didn't.
However, we're not using country because I, DTL should never reference a domain object directly.
So details of the details domain object stuff to domain objects.
Autum Upper is the only bridge in between the two.
So technically speaking, Ardito doesn't even know that it has a domain object.
So there should be no correlation with a domain object.
And to so the DTA is defined here and the property here is also a DTA.
So after all of this, I'm just going to do a builder and see if there's anything out of place and have
a successful build.
So everything seems to be no, it seems to know where it's supposed to be.
I'm going to just add two more things and then we can go ahead and install and configure Autumn Upir.
Now, when we look for a country, it is sometimes easy to look for the country or sometimes easier
to look for the country and just see the details of all the hotels that are part of this country.
So we kind of need that linking here where we're allowed to see the details of the country for any given
hotel.
But then when a country has multiple hotels, right.
We need to be able to say, look for the country with the eighty one and I want to see all the hotels
that's out there, which is not uncommon anywhere on the Internet.
If you look for, you know, on a booking website, you look at Jamaica, for example, and it's going
to show you the list of hotels.
So what will you need to do in our domain object?
And we'll be replicating that across also.
But we need to have a property that is public virtual list.
And I'll just use a list because that's an extension of the list type and it's a list of type hotel.
All right, and it is going to be called hotels and we get to that property.
So this property, we don't need to do our migration for this.
This is really not going to go to the beach.
This is just in the domain object that when you are getting data for all of these, if it is requested,
you can also include the list of hotels associated with the country.
So remember, indoor units of work we did see you can do includes.
So you could have included the details of our country with any given hotel, or we could look for our
country and include the list of hotels.
So that's what that property is there for now.
What I'm going to do is allow the DTA to actually have that behavior also in our country.
Need to you I'm going to place that one inside of the non-specific non operation specific detail and
once again, details speak to details.
So Hotel DTL, that's the data type we're dealing with and it maps back to hotel.
This doesn't need to be virtual.
All right.
So we have a public we have the potential to look at the country detail and get the list of hotels.
Also, the file names have to match between the DTA and our domain object if we want the mapping to
work seamlessly.
Otherwise, there are a lot of configurations that you have to go and see all this member or this property
such as this one.
That said, we don't want to go through all of that based on what we're doing here.
Everything should map to the other or to its counterpart quite well.
All right.
So I've been seeing my mom come up, so let's install Autom up here, because that's what we're going
to use to do this mapping.
Right?
So I click on the project, go to get packages, and then we're going to browse and we're searching
for auto mopper.
And what we really want to be autumn upward dog extensions that Microsoft up dependency injection,
because this one is specifically for core.
The other one, it's not optimized for Dommett Core.
So this is the one that we want.
We can just go ahead and install the autumn upir is not the standard.
There are other tools out there that do similar things to Autumn Upir, but this one is very popular.
I used a lot.
It does not field me, at least in very recent times.
It does not.
So we can get a lot of work done with Autumn Upper.
So now that we've installed it.
Oh, I thought the sun arrow.
No, we need to set up on initialization.
Right.
So what I want to do is just create a folder and you realize that I love to create folders, just kind
of segregate what is happening where some to call this folder configuration the configurations.
And in this folder I'm going to create a class that I'm going to call Mumper initialize or.
All right, so we have to create the configuration so that autumn up knows how it should behave and
what it should pay attention to.
So mopper or mopper, initialise.
And we're going to inherit from this class called profile.
And once I do that, I need to include the using statement for Autumn Upir.
And then this allows me to create what I need to create a constructor.
So on it's called it will do the initialization.
And then in this constructor, I need to define all of the mappings.
Right.
So in other words, I need to see that this domain is called country and then we go ahead and include
any missing library.
There we go.
Is going to map directly to country old.
All right, fine, go ahead and include this.
And then we open and close brace, and then I'm just going to follow that up with duct reverse mop,
which is also a function.
So this is seeing that the country ed class has a direct correlation or the feels, including your needs.
A class as a direct have a direct correlation to country deal fields and they go in either direction.
All right.
And then I'm going to want to do that for all of the details that I have.
So that's what I said.
You can get granular, but once you get granular, you have to make sure that you're covering the potential
mappings.
Right.
So country to create and country to country and then hotel to hotel DTL.
All right, and then the same behavior, same treatment for the hotel to the creator hotel deal.
All right, so now that we have the Mumper initial lizer setup, we need to know included in the startup
of our application, so we go to Starkel as usual, and then we're going to include a line that I just
included right here on the northeast corner where I went to see services that add auto mopper.
And then this is going to require me to include something, let me finish writing into it first.
All right, there we go.
So I need to include or have the using statement for autumn.
There we go.
So an autumn upir.
And I'm going to see type of and I'm going to pass in the data type associated with the map per initialise
or so mopper Inish.
Get the spelling right, Lizer.
And then once again include the missing reference to include using statements.
And then one side to that autumn upir is ready and raring to go.
So when we're actually developing our endpoints, we'll actually see the power of the awesome upper
and hold the details work and how everything relates to the data classes.
But it's good to get these configurations out of the way from early.
So once you set the standard for your application and to later on, there's not as much rework that
needs to be done because that standard has been set for maintaining that standard as your application
gets bigger and all of these things are already in place.