All right, guys, so I'm issuing a challenge to you, I want you to pause the video.
Yes, it just started, but go ahead and pause it.
And I want you to go ahead and create a controller for the hotels you can call a total controller and
the functionality that we have just gone through with our country controller.
I want you to replicate it in the context of the hotels.
So I already have it here.
But I want you to pause.
We're going to go through it together.
But I want you to pause activity to yourself and then we compare notes.
All right, so I'm back and I'm saying I'm back because I'm assuming that you pause the video, I know
you're resuming.
I know we can go through it together.
So here we have the hotel controller and I went through the same steps there.
I clicked, controllers clicked, add data controller, a blank API controller called the total controller.
I went ahead and injected basically the same services that were in the control controller and initialize
them in the constructor.
Know everything pretty much is identical.
The only things that really changed were my variable names, because obviously I'm not going to call
this one countries if we're getting hotel.
So get hotels instead of get countries, get hotels instead of get hotels and similarily, you'd want
to get to a hotel by IBE.
Another thing that I would want to point out would be the mapping where mapping to hotel detail.
And the final thing would be that I've kind of added more attributes.
So as you see the attributes kind of Eden, it indicates that at least swagga and I mean, it does dictate
the behavior, but sluggard does depend on it's also to know how to formulate that documentation.
So right here, I'm letting her know that this method produces 200.
It also produces five hundred, because if you recall, when we looked at Strugar and a return to five
hundred, you would have seen some things being undocumented underneath that 500 error.
And so we want to just make sure that Swiger contextually tells as much information to the developer
as possible at any given time.
So that I bring up swagga.
You're going to see the segregation country different from hotel.
All right.
I hope you're seeing this.
And if we look at hotel or any one of these that the attributes was both attributes were added to,
you could see that the five hundred wasn't there initially to see the two.
No, 500 wasn't there initially.
All right.
So that does work out for someone to use postmen to do some testing.
So I still have my test from the time.
And the thing is, with Postman, you can always just start a new type, right?
So instead of using one tub to continuously be changing, I went to have one for the get to know parameter
street over here.
So this is no parameter.
Let's see if that works.
All right, so I really didn't test Michael before.
No, I wrote it and I didn't test it, and I'm happy to see that it's working.
All right.
And then the one with the parameter.
That also works, and for now, that's all there is to setting up our controllers.
All right.
So as many controllers as you might have, of course, variations and based on context, certain things
may differ.
But we have a good template upon which we can build our get operations.
All right.
So you can go ahead and just start this off.
And then when we come back, we'll be pushing our changes to our repositories.