Hey, guys, welcome back.
So one very important parts of user authorization is knowing what role this users in appointing, though
we haven't done anything associated with roles who are more preoccupied with getting the user information,
validating it and whether we create the user or not.
Now, when it comes to rules, the rules that are allowed need to exist in the system prior to the system
being used.
So the same way that we would have set up these operations for hotels and countries of less importance
really than rules would be.
So we want to make sure that the rules are there from the get go so that when the users start registering,
the rules are already there.
So what we want to do is see them.
But instead of ceding them the way that we see the country and who, I'm going to show you the way that
we can obstruct that operation from our DB contacts and keep the BB context as light as possible, similar
to what I need to do that with our services that we are installing.
So what I'm going to do is set up a new folder.
I have configurations or that I'm just going to go ahead and add another folder inside that that I'm
going to call entities.
So configurations for anything that is entity related and then I'm going to add a class and then I want
to call this class roll configuration, go ahead and add it.
And then this rule configuration class is inheriting from entity.
Type configuration.
And it will be of the type identity role.
All right, go ahead and include any missing references.
So we're just listing rule configuration, all that.
It's going to be associated with that configuration type.
And of course, we have to go ahead and implement whatever this is seeing needs to be implemented,
which is our configure function or so it's automatically going to pass or the same builder that is in
use on model creating.
So then we can actually replicate the code that we have where we say builder DOT has data.
And then instead of building the test data, we can go ahead and create new rules, new rule objects.
So let me just sort of these quotation marks.
All right.
So a new identity rule.
And we're just going to initialize this object.
I'm not going to give it an idea, it was sort of an ad, but the name that's called this one user.
And we have to give it a normalized name, which is really just capitalized version of that.
The of the name, really, and then I'm also going to give it.
Administrator, hospital administrator.
And then the normalized is all caps version of the ministry or ministry.
So always make sure the spending is right.
I've spent these debugging but spilling, so don't be like me.
All right.
So now that we have this configured method and as many rules as you think you may need, you can go
ahead and configure them.
But the most important parts of all of that is when we're ready to put it into the system.
We need only say builder.
Not apply.
Sorry, Bill Der not apply configuration, and then I'm just going to see a new role.
Configuration.
And then include the missing reference store you created and there we go.
So you see, that looks much to me that looks much neater than having all of this in this file.
Remember that the reason we moved it from the top here above the list was that it was so huge a function
because of all these lines.
So if you want, you can pause right now and attempt to build other configuration files for country
and hotel.
All right, so I hope you actually attempted it because I did it right, so I'm not going to ask you
to do anything.
I'm not going to do so just in case you need some guidance.
We I went ahead and created configuration files per type.
All right.
So we have hotel and we have country and we have rules.
So we created a all together.
I did country.
Same name.
Basically, you could copy and paste according to the essential parts control configuration that I into
the type configuration relative to country as a contextless and then the same code that was there to
create the country's.
I just cut and paste.
All right.
The only thing is that in the previous one we had builder dot entity, something like that, and I removed
that DOT entity part.
So it's just builder that has data.
So you can go ahead and replicate that across both country and hotel.
And if you're doing your own thing across any other one, I know you're on model building looks much
cleaner.
Right.
And I think I just put this one.
I don't really think it matters where in terms of order, but I just put it on the bottom since that's
the order in which everything was being created anyway.
So country then hotel, then we have the rules once again.
These two are really optional in terms of what's really needed to get the application up and running.
Right.
So now that we have the rule configuration or seating, we can all just add migration and see added
default rules.
And that and the resulting migration file has two entries into our rules file.
So you see generated its own ID.
That's why I didn't bother to modify that.
But then we get user and we get administrator.
So when we do update database, it will go ahead and do the insert.
So once that is done, we have two other changes to make.
So one is in the user D to introduce this collection of type string and I'm calling its rolls.
Right.
So we're giving the user the opportunity to see which rule or rules should this person have.
And then in the account controller.
Right after we have vetted if the registration attempt was successful or not, are the user creation
operation was successful or not run, remember, if it gets beyond that is a statement, it means that
it was successful.
Then we take the extra step of seeing user manager that not add rules async and we're adding to the
user that was just created the role that came in our rules that came in.
So if you look at this, it has a few overrides, one over it allows it to or not over the overload.
Sorry.
So the one overload allows you to just passing in a list of rules that it will just go ahead and add
to this user.
So once the rule exists, then it will be associated with the user in the bucket once again, built
in function, not much code or if needed on our part.
So let us do this for a spin.
So in Swagga, you see that they are modifying the potential values, right, so that they are showing
that they can pass in an area called rules.
So the area is the square brackets, whereas an object is occurring.
So let's try it out.
And I'm going to leave this same user as the same user that we've got success with last time.
Right.
So that means I should get some validation message to see it shouldn't work, but I'm going to pass
in the role of user and when they execute and then here's what I'm getting.
So the result is that I have a 400 board request.
Duplicate email is the issue.
It's already taken.
So that validation is working.
So let's see, user at hotels, hotel listing, dot com does something different and that's the user.
So I'll go ahead and execute.
And what I'm getting is not a bad response.
All right.
That looks good.
So let's us see what happened in the database after those operations.
So I'm going to kill the execution, go over to the server manager and first, then want to look into
user status, I should have at least two users based on my tests so far, and they will go away.
I use a total listing and user at example.
All right.
So that's good.
The next one would be the rolls.
So I just scaffolded the rules myself.
I just see that the rules.
And so these other rules that we created.
However, the User Roll Association is stored here because it's a many to many.
So they're seeing that many users rights have many rules.
Right.
So that's why we allowed Honoria, because maybe one user might be administrator and user, maybe and
supervisor etc, etc. based on this system, it's all context.
Right.
However, in this table, when we view data, then we should see the user ID associated with the roll.
So if we were to just go back and double check, you see that this is the user ID.
There was no ending eight F seven.
So if I look at that same user ID and if seven and the rules seven, five, five.
So you have to go to this one to see which one is seven five five which is user.
So that is all.
We start integrating rules based authorization into our systems and all our users when they get registered,
will get registered with their appropriate rules.