All right, guys, so we're back in our project and our task today is simple, we're just sworn to take
in all our changes.
So anything with our Atik would have been modified along the way once again and anything with a green
plus sign was added.
So we can just go ahead and go to get changes.
And I'm just going to refresh what I don't need to refresh here all my changes listed.
So I'm going to put in my message.
And my message is just letting everybody know that I did the country and the hotel get my thoughts.
Also fix the units of work by short for dependency injection reference, because remember, we made
that modification in the start so I can go ahead and commit and sync.
And once that is done, we're ready to move on to our next module.