Hey, guys, welcome back.
In this lesson, we'll be exploring, implementing, caching on our API caching can significantly improve
the performance of the API.
Just think about when we have hundreds, maybe thousands of clients subscribing to the API.
They're all trying to find hotels and countries and probably even both at the same time.
And that can really take a toll on the performance of the API based on the whole infrastructure.
And if I have to hit the database with a request.
So caching will introduce kind of quick access layer on top of the real data store and it will significantly
reduce how often we have to pull the database.
So what we will be implementing is one caching.
We'll be looking at implementing an expert experience, a mechanism to reduce the whole.
Often we have to go to the database.
We'll be looking at implementing a validation mechanism to reduce the network bandwidth.
And at the end of this lesson, we just want an overall feel of caching why we have it and how it can
be implemented.
Now, there are three types of caching, and I just wanted to give you guys a little of here before
we get into the whole code matter.
So the client cash lives on the browser.
So it's a private cache because it's, you know, unique to a single or any particular client.
All right.
We have the gateway cache, which kind of leaves on the server and is assured cache.
So the gateway implements a cache and all the clients hitting the gateway at any point in time would
be hitting that cache.
And then we have a proxy cache, which is also a shared cache, but it doesn't live on the server.
It lives in the network.
No, to start cashing our source, it's pretty simple.
What we need to do is add the response cache attribute and set how long the cache should live for.
Right.
So over any control over an endpoint.
And I'll just start off with countries, you know, we just experiment between these two.
So I'm just going to add the attribute that's his response cache.
And then duration equals 60.
So 60 means 60 seconds.
All right.
So we're setting up cache control with a maximum age of 60 seconds.
If you look at duration, you see this sets max edge in the cache control header.
So when when a client queries for data from the endpoint, there will be a header included that says
this is the lifetime of the cache, that you are no getting our cached data that you are not getting.
So let's go to debug mode and conduct a quick test in post on.
What you want to do is just make sure that you're sending your cash header option is off so you can
just go to file settings and on the general, just look for that setting, make sure it's off, otherwise
you can proceed.
So we already know that we can look at all the headers coming back.
And I'm going to do send and when we get the response, we see that our cache control header is coming
back and it has the moth's age of 60.
All right.
Now, this is really just a header, so we are not actually catching anything just yet.
This is just letting the client know that, well, the data is cached, but of course, we actually
need to cache the data.
So we're going to have to modify some of our configurations in our Start-Up, which is where I started
off.
So in our startup that says we're going to add this new service registration in the configure services
function and that I'm just going to put it here.
So services that add response caching and then after that, we need to register our middleware, which
I will do right above the routine middleware that sets up that user response caching.
So you can just go ahead and add those two lines and then what we're going to do is do another.
And when I run this request, we are seeing a new header.
And this one is it indicates the number of seconds the object has been in a proxy cache.
All right.
So we just thought about the different kinds of caching.
So we're implementing a proxy and see the value here is nine.
So if I were on another one and it's No.
Thirty two seconds into the maximum age of 60.
So pretty much within the lifetime, if we continue to pull it, we would keep on getting a different
value for the aid.
So when I do that, you see the aid is gone because we exceeded the 60 second.
So I actually went to the database this time came back and there is no age.
But then if I pull it again, no, it's telling me that, OK, it's 10 seconds old, it's 14 seconds
old, etc..
It's no, I'm just going to go back over to my start of the real quickly and we're going to explore
how we can probably enter implements a more global value, because right now I would have to set this
manually over every action or every endpoint.
And then if we change it from 60 to 120, then I would have to go through each one.
So what we can do in the start, though, is add to the config for add controls are just put in my my
lambda expression when we have the token and we have the arrow another supporting the current abrasives,
because, you know, if we have more than one line to configure, that makes it easier.
But what I'm going to add is config to see cache profiles that add and we want to 120 seconds duration.
So here we can kind of define a cache profile, which then we can use and reuse throughout.
So I need let me see what I need here.
I need a semicolon at the end.
All right.
There we go.
So config cache profiles not add and we give it any name, I mean, within reason.
And then you cache profile duration and you can add other properties to the profile location, verb
by header.
Don't get too complicated.
But what we can do now is instead of specifying duration here in this header, I can see Cheche profile
cache profile name is equal to and then we put that name that we just specified in that slot.
So if you want, you can go ahead and test it.
I'm not going to test it again because we already get the gist of the headers coming back and the age.
So, no, we've increased it to one to ten over any endpoint that we wish to have that cash.
And more than likely, you'd want it over.
The ones that are reading the get profiles would be the ones to have that caching profile.
You wouldn't necessarily need that over to create and other operations.
All right, so let's talk about a situation where our data might get stale, so as I said, with the
cash, it takes like a quick copy of the data layer and it returns that data for as long as we told
it to.
So in this case, it's two minutes, but let's extend this to maybe 10 minutes.
And then the first time the client tries to get data, then it's going to hit and then get a test version
afterwards.
But then what if five minutes into this, 10 minutes or two minutes into this ten minute period and
update actually occurred, so a new country got added?
Right.
And then they're still getting stale data for as long as the cash is alive.
So we don't want that.
We don't want that.
When they when the data changes underneath, they're still getting old data.
So on to add to this is some validation.
All right.
So to do some validation or add headers for validation and expression checks, we're going to include
a new library and it's going to be this library called Marvin Cheche headers.
All right.
So it's be done at core where that adds cache hitters to responses and you see the different headers.
The cache control expires e-TAG and last modified.
All right.
So it implements cache expiration and validation.
So you can go ahead and get that.
And I'm going to refactor or code a bit.
So in the service extensions, I'm going to add a new function where we're seeing public static, void
configure cache headers and we know the drill would pass in the service collection.
And then I'm taking that first line that we added services that add response caching as well as services
that add a cache headers.
So we're taking those two.
And then what we're going to do is just add a reference to the start up.
So where I had the original one, I just add one reference to that function, which is going to initialize
these to service calls.
Right after that modification, we're going to add the middleware.
So after the user response caching, I'm going to add up not use if cache headers and before we do anything
for any more modifications, just to make sure everything is OK, we're just going to do a quick test
and we're going to send a brand new request.
And when we look at the list of headers coming back from that request, look at it.
We have expired last modified.
We have an item identifies a specific resource version.
So it's just like a little hash that says this is a version of the data.
You're getting very other things.
So we see that we're getting some new headers along the way.
Right.
You would also notice that the marks age is kind of gone back to 60.
So, yes, it was 120.
We set it to 120, but it's gone up to 60.
So we're going to just explore how we can customize that max age.
And the way we're going to do that is go back to our service extensions and add the following code on
the services that cache headers.
So we're going to define a token expiration option, Lambda Arrow, and we're going to see the expiration
option marks Eje.
Sixty five one twenty.
Whatever it is that we want, we can see the expiration option test location.
We want it to be private or we want it to be public sermon, whether it's all public or private.
So let's say we wanted it private and then the validation option you see most revalidate equals true
meaning.
Once the details change, we must go through that process again.
Now, after doing these modifications, we can actually remove the header from the resource.
All right.
So let's just do one more test and we'll see that the modification is actually global.
So even without putting the resource or the attribute right above the resource, we see that we're still
getting about the same headers.
And I'm just going on a live and out of the life of the one twenty.
All right.
So the next thing I want to show you are the or the next things I want to show you would be the custom
actually say you can actually add right above the potential endpoint that you want a different setting
for.
So, yes, we set the global setting in the start, starting the service configuration, but then over
the endpoint, you can actually override that.
So you can add those.
Missing references, so cash exploration and then you say you want a different location, you want it
to be public and this one should be 60, you can actually override the global settings right here.
And then you can tell this one that it doesn't need to revalidate.
So just bouncing back to the headers, coming back and all that, we've implemented caching just to
go through them.
Once again, this tag actually represents the unique, like a unique hash to say this is the version
of the data that you are seeing.
If if within the lifespan of the cache something changes, then this tag is actually going to change
and then you would get a new tag.
All right.
But then for as long as a data store does not change, what we're doing is just caching it so that we
don't have to hit the database to bring about the same data every time somebody wants it, at least
for two minutes, if we'll get one.
Those are requests we don't necessarily need to go to the database for the same old data.
So that is the advantage of adding caching to your API.
Of course, on a case by case basis, you may want to customize so particular endpoint, serve up the
data versus others.
You may also not even need caching based on the application, or it may not be suitable for the type
of operation that you are providing the API for.
So this is just another thing that I think it's good for you to know and you can use it, have it in
your arsenal for when needed.