Hey, guys, welcome back.
So we're at the second check in check point for our project.
So after each module, we'll just review what we've done and then go ahead and update our repository
accordingly.
So it's always good to keep the Collins off your, you know, small wins so that if your code gets corrected
later on, you can always revert to the most recent working version of your application.
So firstly, we can always know the changes that have been made by looking at the files already means
it was there.
And it is no different from the last thing that was checked in.
And the processing means that it has been added since the last chicken.
So it is always keeping track of what the file looked like and letting you know that it's no different
through old or ADIC or letting you know that this has been added since the last time.
If you want to see what has changed, you can actually right click go to it and you can see if history
or compare.
So when you do compare it to say, well, the last version I had is to the left, I'm just getting my
bearings right.
So the version I had is to the left and the new version is to the right.
So literally that this line was modified in that way.
And everywhere you see a green highlighted, it means that something happened.
So when working in a team setting, though, it's always recommended that you guys don't work on the
same files to check in, because then if you modify something on your side and modify that same file
on my side, then we end up with this clashing kind of like this crushing situation where we'll say,
well, the two lines are seeing two entirely different things.
Which one should I use at that point?
You have to manage what you call conflicts.
I'm coding by myself, so I can't really see any conflicts right now.
But hopefully you guys don't encounter that.
So what we're going to do is check in.
So to do that, I can right.
Click go to get.
No, that is incorrect to get changes.
There we go.
So new version of Visual Studio is a different level to just go with the get changes once again.
If you're not seeing that, you can always click view and you will be able to see that menu item accordingly.
So you always want to put in a message that depicts what was.
So my message is the mean telling whoever would see the second at a database of some upper unit for
I need you so you don't need to be you don't need to write an essay.
But at least let me have an idea or however have an idea of what you've done.
After that, we can click that.
Correct.
And then we see it all on the scene.
So it will commit the changes one and two to see if just wait and see if you will commit the changes
locally and then it will kind of synchronize with GitHub.
And at that point, if there are changes waiting on the other side, meaning your team member made some
changes and check them in before.
When you say come, it's all and think it will push up your changes, get the latest ones.
And once again, if you do modify the same file with different content, that's where that conflict
might come up.
So if you don't do that, then this is a really seamless process.
So here, we'll let you know that it was successfully synchronized and you can move along to the next
task.