You guys will come back, so Randall, we want to start discussing our Gece on the Web tokens, but
before we go ahead and implement them, unwrite mountains of beautiful code.
To do that, I want us to have a full understanding of the purpose that they serve in the whole workflow,
the API security and everything.
So there is a leading authority, at least in my view, there are leading authority in the form of zero,
if I'm not mistaken.
They're probably pioneers for this kind of protocol.
But you can go to JWT that aisle, and you land on the same page that I have here, where they display
to some token and kind of show you the breakdown.
So we're going to discuss exactly why tokens are necessary and what exactly they tell basically when
when they're being recorded.
So let's say, once again, the person attempts to log in to our API or they attempt to access our resource
from our API.
We have restricted access.
So we are telling them that we need to know who you are and what you are able to do.
But then I need to make sure that you are somebody who should be able to access my system to begin with.
Right.
So are talking here pretty much would be issued to them after a successful login attempts so they would
pass over their username and password that we already have stored in our system because they're registered.
Once we verify that they are who they say they are, we're going to give them a tool can with information
that we have on them so that when they are making subsequent requests, they can use this tool kit instead
of trying to log in every single time.
So this token would represent a hash or some encoded representation of all the information that we have
for them that would that could include their username, their password, not their password, back to
their username, their email address, if they're different, how long we're allowing them to use this
token to access the system, what role they have.
And this although one called claims, which means that you are able to do this, but not that sort of.
Right.
So those are the things that we encode in this huge string and send back to them after they have successfully
logged in.
Not the benefit of this is that on their side, they don't have to keep on calling the login because
remember that we're not keeping the session to know if they were logged in previously or not.
So instead of them having to try and log in every single time, they're going to make an API call,
they log in once, get this token and then make every other call with this token attached to the request
on our side, when we get the request and we see that there is a token, we decode it, validate that
it came from us, and then redirect them accordingly or provide the response accordingly.
So that is what JWT security is all about.
You'll see that this stream is actually color coded red.
I think that's I'm going to say lavender and blue.
Right.
And pretty much each section is explained over here.
So this is the heterosexual one which contains what harshing algorithm was used, as well as the type
of token which in this case is JWT.
The middle section has the payload or the data.
So the payload is really to see all of this information is what I know about this user.
So the more information we put into it is the bigger the section will get.
Right.
And over to the right, you see here they're showing you what exactly is included in this payload.
So the payload can have the expiration date of the token or date on time because usually you are talking
for a finite period of time.
So as long as this token is valid, then they don't have to log in again.
As soon as it's invalid, then they may want to log in and get their first token and then continue.
So that's what that that's the purpose that one serves.
And then the parts now with the signature piece of the server is the signature part to verify whether
the token contains a valid information or not.
So if we issued the token, then we would want to verify that it came from us because anybody can really
encode this kind of data, but they don't want to make sure that they have done here encoded relative
to our issuing key to make sure that it really came from us and it is valid in our system.
So I hope that cleared up some of the let's say the gray area is our own, what JWT is and why we're
using it.
When we come back, we will start changing up our configurations in our API to facilitate its use.