Hey, guys will come back in this business and we'll be talking about limiting rate, limiting or throttling,
as it is also called, is a technique by which we impose certain limits on how often somebody can hit
our endpoint and actually get better.
So, of course, if somebody comes and bombards the endpoint as much as we have caching on all of these
things, the fact is that the endpoint is actually prone to a denial of service or delice attack.
And what we want to do is kind of put a mechanism in that when we detect too many requests from one
source, we can kind of block them and say, hey, here, overdoing it outside of the potential DOS
attack.
It actually helps us to kind of meter how often any one client accesses data and many very popular APIs
or their Google.
And I'm just going to say Google.
But all of those big players with APIs and their SDK is they all have some form of throttling.
If you read the requirements and the terms of use of their APIs that all have something in there to
see, you can request maybe one hundred per minute or 100 per hour, stuff like that.
So today we're going to be sitting in our API just to get a feel of how it's done.
And we'll be using the library, SB Natcore it's limit so we can just go ahead and install that.
And once that is installed, the next thing that we want to do is go over to our startup and allow our
application to use memory cache because it's going to use memory cache to kind of store and keep track
of who requested what and how many times they've requested it in the Timir.
So we can say services that add memory cache right there in the configure services function and then
we have some modifications to make the service extension.
So I have the code here already.
And this method is called configurator limiting.
And we already know the drillable, the service collection.
And what we're doing here is setting up a set of rules so you can just go ahead and copy the code and
include any missing references as you go along.
So very limited rules equals new list, really limit the rules so you can have multiple rules.
So we have to initialize a new rule object which allows us to specify the particular endpoints.
In this case, I'm seeing star, meaning every single endpoint is going to adhere to this rule.
So based on this structure, I can actually have multiple rules that can see, say, comma and do a
new rule.
And let me just jump in, because I can do a new rule, specify a particular endpoint and then change
the limit.
So this one is limited to one call per second, right?
That's kind of short.
I mean, we can say 10 seconds, one call every 10 seconds.
I can see one call every 10 minutes, you know, or one hundred calls.
It's up to you.
We can configurator.
And once again, if you have different rules per endpoint, you can go ahead and add these rules and
specify the particular endpoints to which they're applicable.
Right now, I'm just going to set a global rule.
So I'm just going to say all endpoints and I'm going to set it to something that is very small so that
we can see it in text writes.
I want to see within five seconds you're only allowed one call on any endpoint.
Then we go ahead and we say services that configure how we put in the IP rate limit options and we just
say options, not general rules, equal the limited rules that we just defined.
Outside of that, we need to add these Singleton services in the form of a limit counter store, and
that is going to be associated with memory kashrut limit kolender store.
So all of these are just bits of code that are required to support the library that we import.
This different library might implement differently, but this is the code required for this particular
library.
So you can just hit pause, write them off.
At this point, Intellisense will be filling them in because you already have the package.
Now, after we're done in service extensions, we're just going to head back over to startup and we're
going to add these two lines, services that configure it, limiting, which is the method we just configured
and the services that add context accessor.
So this gives us access to the actual controller and it's InnerWorkings when needed.
And then finally, we're going to add the middleware where Antipov routine.
So I'm going to put it right underneath the caching we have about use IP rate limit and of course,
include any missing references.
Now, there have been different response codes used when they're, you know, responding to, say,
too many requests in more recent times for twenty nine has been used, which literally means too many
requests.
But in the past I've witnessed platforms using four twenty, which means and Honsinger.
Com and other ones.
So let's test this also for country.
I'm going to hit send and if we observe the headers, you'll see that we get about three new headers.
X-Rite Limit excretes Rhymin limiter meaning and limited reset.
Right.
So it's showing you that the limit is five seconds.
You have no more remaining four to five second window and that the reset is going to be at this timestamp.
So if I hit this multiple times or I'm going to use a different endpoint because I think this one is
protected by caching.
So it might not based on my caching configuration, it's not going to violate the throttle.
All right.
So I'm going to use the hotel because remember that we set up all of those things on the country endpoint.
So let me go to a hotel, which I didn't really modify as much.
So I already sent a request and it's showing me the same headers limit, etc., etc. If I send another
one, we're done five seconds later.
It's okay if I send another one.
Too many requests.
Right.
So it says right after as basically saying send another request after one second.
So nothing came back.
But the message API calls quote, exceeded maximum admitted one per five seconds.
Right.
So it's letting me know that I need to try Abuk in this amount of time.
And when I do, there we go.
If I try again, we try after four seconds, try again.
And if I keep on doing that, you see that that value keeps on changing relative to the number of seconds
that I have based on the last request.
So that is all we can add throttling and it automatically once again gives about that for twenty nine
to say too many requests.
All right.
And so the client knows that, hey, you're bombarding the API, enhance your comm.