All right, guys, so that's another milestone where we're just going to review the things that we implemented
in this section and then get to our changes to GitHub.
So going in order of what we did, the first one would be paging.
So we implemented paging where we post in some were request parameters into our get countries.
And we also went in and said some defaults to see if they don't provide any.
Then we're going to provide this much information upfront.
Otherwise we give the client the opportunity to say they want this many records.
Starting from this point on, they're represented by the number as well as the page.
Right.
So that's one thing that we implemented.
We also implemented global era handling, which allows us to create or write to our code without the
need for too many track catches.
And it comes a little bit neater than it was before, where every time we're seeing track catch track.
All right.
Another thing that we did was implement versioning on our API.
So we created this Contrave to controller just for experiment purposes where we specify the API version
and we explored how we can allow the client to specify which version of the API it is that they want.
And I think the last bit of configuration would have them positive as better.
All right.
So in our extend services we put in still for the exception, handling the global exception, handling
to see, you know, and there's an error log and return with that.
Five hundred for the versioning.
We did say that we want to implement versioning reading from the header being passed in with the request.
We specify the default API version to be one point or so.
If money is specified, then it's 1.0.
We also looked at implementing caching so we can actually just provide data for up to a certain amount
of time before we have to pull the database for the next request.
And we also put in validation to make sure that once the underlying data changes that need to kind of
refresh is on top in the cash layer.
And last, but by no means least, we put in throttling to kind of control how often a particular client
based on IP address, at least based on the way we've configured it, can hit a particular endpoint.
So right now the limit is very small, the period is small, but that's just for our experiment purpose.
In our real situation, probably you can look at other providers like Google and so on, and if your
infrastructure is robust enough, you can use their their values to inform you as to how you can put
in throttling what I leave those examples.
What is there for now and what we want to do is check in so we know that we just go over to get changes
and then we put in our message and that is my message.
So when I do this check in, I'll just go ahead and commit and sync.
So everything that I've done here and remember that in the examples of it, I've done it in one place.
I'd encourage you to try it in the other place.
But then you can always check the source code and double check and compare notes.
And once all of that is done, we're ready to move on to our next topic.