All right, guys, welcome back.
So coming off the heels of setting up our authentication manager to issue generates and issue the tokens,
what we want to do is actually finish up our login endpoints to the tune where we actually validate
the token and allow our deny access to anybody passing in this token.
Right.
So the first thing that we want to do is inject our newly created office manager service so we know
how to do the injection or if they can just go ahead and hit pause and go ahead and complete this injection
operation.
So once you've added the new three lines, one for the private property, one into the constructor and
initialization, then we can go about creating or a log endpoint.
So you would have already commented on the login endpoint.
You can uncommented and I already have the revised version of it on screen, so let's just go through
it together.
So what we want to do is log on to validate our requested or the data coming in the detail.
Then I'm going to see if the off manager validate user, if not so easy to read this as equals for us
in case you need to see sharp.
If not, you just put the exclamation side.
So this means if it is not a valid user, then return on authorized because.
Well, if you tried to log in and you're not a valid user, then you're not authorized to go any further.
Right.
Otherwise we're going to return accepted our OK, whatever it is I'm saying accepted, accepted new
and a new object with with an expression called token.
And it will take the value of the token that is created.
So we see it on the score off manager, not create a token.
So remember that that's what we would have set up in our office manager just null create token goes
through, generates all of these bits and pieces of data and then returns the tokens.
So that's what that payload will have.
So on to go ahead and test that functionality.
So let's revisit our login endpoint.
I'm just going to use Soggier for this part of it.
So just try it out and put in a user that I know I created and is already registered and then I'm going
to click execute.
Let's see what happens.
All right.
And we're getting a token response.
So you see this big string.
So token, that's by virtue of the expression we put in the custom object and the value being passed
is the token that is here.
So if I if I take this token and go to our website to look at what's in tokens.
Based it then we'll see here that we have the algorithm, we have Trevor, for example, DOT, that's
the claim for the user.
We have the role right.
And we have the expiration time.
And if you hover, it will show you exactly the time from when it's issued and the issuer.
All right.
And then if you wanted to go as far as verifying the signature, we could do that.
But we already have the mechanism to do that internally, so we don't need to do that here.
So now what I want to do is experiment with actually preventing somebody access to our endpoint, someone
to use our hotel hotel controller for that exercise.
So let's say that the ability to get the list of hotels, everybody should be able to do that.
We should be able to call it without authenticating, which is what we have been doing up until now.
However, we want to add an authorized flag or annotation to the call to get to one hotel's details.
So we just put on authorized and actually you could extend the the annotation here for the HTP get and
add authorized right there.
Right.
So you could do it either way.
So if you have this one, you don't need this one.
Personally, I like to separate them.
So I have the HTP yet authorize.
I'd actually like to or prefer to put it at the top.
So as I see it, I know it's an authorized endpoint.
Right.
So what we want to do is test our call so this and the point.
Unauthorized and authorized.
So let's go.
And for this activity, I'm going to use Postman someone to firstly test the one that we haven't authorized
just to make sure that it still works.
All right.
There's a list of photos of three hotels.
Good.
Now I'm going to test the one with the endpoint that requires an ID value.
Right.
So when I click send, it's going to say for one unauthorized it's not saying for one unauthorized because
I didn't login or whatever, because I mean, this is already authorized and we set up the default schema
to see I need to see a token in order to authorize are not Soloff.
That's just happening automatically.
If we have an old token in there, which I do, this is a token that was issued more than 50 minutes
ago, then it will automatically also deny access.
So in a token is issued and then it expires.
It is the onus of the client calling up.
Applications are to go and fetch a new token, meaning go through the login process again, get a new
token, and then come back and try and access this endpoint.
All right.
So in Postman, what we want to do is go with the authorization and choose barer token from this dropdown
list.
Then we provide the token that we have, which is the first token.
And then when we do that and I'm still getting a four or one on authorized.
So that means there's some configuration that is missing.
Let me go.
More than likely to be the start of that series.
And I think I left off one of the middleware.
So I need to add up, not use authentication right here.
All right.
So make sure you have this user authentication and order Mutter's in this situation.
So authentication, then authorization and all of that before this are up, not MVC.
The different core versions of different middleware is being included.
So as long as you get that general theme, you should be good.
So let's try that same request again.
And we're having much better success.
All right, so we're getting a status 200, OK, and we're seeing the one quarter that we requested.
So now you see that we just protected our endpoint, because if I remove this sense or off and insurance
and again, I get to for one unauthorized once I include the beer all token, I get the status 200.
If I modify this beer token, then it's unauthorized because the token could not be validated against
the information that was encoded and put in originally.
So that is how you can go ahead and harden your API.
And once again, this just this JWT method is very secure because this payload, yes, it can be decoded,
but it wanted shouldn't contain any information that is too sensitive and information that it contains
should be information that if you see it, it's of no major consequence to the API and the underlying
infrastructure.
However, it is enough for me to verify who you are and that I am the one who gave you access to the
system.